<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

<channel>
	<title>Mozilla Reps Planet</title>
	<link>http://planet.mozillareps.org</link>
	<language>en</language>
	<description>Mozilla Reps Planet - http://planet.mozillareps.org</description>
	<atom:link rel="self" href="http://planet.mozillareps.org/rss20.xml" type="application/rss+xml"/>


<item>
	<title>Mehul Patel - Maker Fest 2018</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.rowdymehul.com/?p=1502</guid>
	<link>http://www.rowdymehul.com/mozilla/maker-fest-2018/</link>
	<description>MakerFest has always been very closed to my heart because from here what my journey as a #Mozillian started and as result, this is my 2nd consecutive year as a Lead organizer and 3rd year as a volunteer from Mozilla ...</description>
	<pubDate>Sun, 25 Feb 2018 19:04:19 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

<item>
	<title>Mehul Patel - GSIndia Summit 2017</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.rowdymehul.com/?p=1488</guid>
	<link>http://www.rowdymehul.com/mozilla/gsindia-summit-2017/</link>
	<description>GirlScript India Summit – It is the first ever women oriented technical festival of India hosted by GirlScript Foundation. It is a platform where students get a chance to polish their skills and explore their potential. The Technical fest will ...</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 23 Feb 2018 18:34:23 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

<item>
	<title>Viswaprasath KS - GNUnify 2018</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">https://iamvp7.github.io//GNUNify_18/</guid>
	<link>https://iamvp7.github.io//GNUNify_18/</link>
	<description>GNUnify is one of the amazing event where each and every year Mozilla India community make sure to participate. GNUnify is an annual gathering consisting of Free and Open Source software workshops, talks, seminars and BOFs (Birds of a feather), ...</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2018 07:39:00 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

<item>
	<title>Official Reps Blog - Reps On-boarding Team</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.mozilla.org/mozillareps/?p=531</guid>
	<link>https://blog.mozilla.org/mozillareps/2018/02/15/reps-on-boarding-team/</link>
	<description>As you already know from our discourse topic, we have created an Onboarding Screening Team. The scope of this team is to help on evaluating the new applications to the Reps program by helping the Reps Council on this process. ...</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 15 Feb 2018 16:57:59 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

<item>
	<title>Mehul Patel - Google DevFest Ahmedabad 2017</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.rowdymehul.com/?p=1476</guid>
	<link>http://www.rowdymehul.com/rust/google-devfest-ahmedabad-2017/</link>
	<description>Google Developers Group (GDG) – is open and volunteer geek community who create exciting projects and share experience about Google technologies with a passion and GDG Ahmedabad is one of the most active &amp;amp; passionate community. The aim of GDG ...</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2018 08:29:48 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

<item>
	<title>Nino Vranesic - Embracing the improvement psychology</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.elnino.si/post/170845327967</guid>
	<link>http://blog.elnino.si/post/170845327967</link>
	<description>What would you do if you could do it all the time? Everybody is the happiest when they are doing...</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 13 Feb 2018 21:04:20 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

<item>
	<title>Official Reps Blog - Rep of the Month – January 2018</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.mozilla.org/mozillareps/?p=529</guid>
	<link>https://blog.mozilla.org/mozillareps/2018/01/31/rep-of-the-month-january-2018/</link>
	<description>Please join us in congratulating Cynthia Pereira, our Reps of the Month for January 2018! Cynthia is digital communications strategist and front-end developer with expertise on technical consulting, user and staff training and customer service in IT and Telecom segments. ...</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2018 17:47:24 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

<item>
	<title>Official Reps Blog - Rep of the Month – December 2017</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.mozilla.org/mozillareps/?p=527</guid>
	<link>https://blog.mozilla.org/mozillareps/2018/01/30/rep-of-the-month-december-2017/</link>
	<description>Please join us in congratulating Bala Subramaniyan and Jayesh Katta Ramalingaiah, our Reps of the Month for December 2017! Bala Bala, a Rep in Warangal, India, has been contributing to Mozilla for more than 5 years. (Bala with Jeff at ...</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2018 16:26:34 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

<item>
	<title>Sanyam Khurana - Web Extensions, Womoz &amp; Privacy</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">tag:SanyamKhurana.com,2018-01-23:blog/web-extensions-womoz-privacy.html</guid>
	<link>http://SanyamKhurana.com/blog/web-extensions-womoz-privacy.html</link>
	<description>A Saturday well spent teaching students about Open Source, Add-ons and Privacy. We had an activity at Indira Gandhi Delhi Technical University for Women (IGDTUW) for Addons, WoMoz and Privacy. The session started with Trishul giving a talk on getting ...</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 23 Jan 2018 14:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

<item>
	<title>Sanyam Khurana - Web Extensions, Womoz &amp; Privacy</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">tag:SanyamKhurana.com,2018-01-23:blog/mozcoffe-2017-end.html</guid>
	<link>http://SanyamKhurana.com/blog/mozcoffe-2017-end.html</link>
	<description>A Saturday well spent teaching students about Open Source, Add-ons and Privacy. We had an activity at Indira Gandhi Delhi Technical University for Women (IGDTUW) for Addons, WoMoz and Privacy. The session started with Trishul giving a talk on getting ...</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 23 Jan 2018 14:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

<item>
	<title>Sanyam Khurana - Moz-Fedora Day</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">tag:SanyamKhurana.com,2018-01-14:blog/moz-fedora-day.html</guid>
	<link>http://SanyamKhurana.com/blog/moz-fedora-day.html</link>
	<description>We recently organized Moz-Fedora Day, a one day event on promoting FOSS through Mozilla &amp;amp; Fedora at Investopad, Hauz Khas, Delhi on Jan 13, 2018. The aim was to depict the usage of packaging &amp;amp; building one of the Mozilla&#39;s ...</description>
	<pubDate>Sun, 14 Jan 2018 14:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

<item>
	<title>Michal Stanke - Mozilla.cz 2017 recap</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">https://michal.stanke.cz/2018/01/14/mozilla-cz-2017-recap</guid>
	<link>https://michal.stanke.cz/2018/01/14/mozilla-cz-2017-recap.html</link>
	<description>This week I have published a recapitulation of the last year, how we did in 2017 and how we would like to continue in 2018. It was rather a short article in Czech and I would like to elaborate more ...</description>
	<pubDate>Sun, 14 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

<item>
	<title>Official Reps Blog - Reps Council at Austin</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.mozilla.org/mozillareps/?p=522</guid>
	<link>https://blog.mozilla.org/mozillareps/2018/01/11/reps-council-at-austin/</link>
	<description>TL;DR The All Hands is a special time of the year where Mozilla employees along with core volunteers gather for a week of many meetings and brainstorming. The All Hands Wiki page has more information about the general setting. During ...</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 11 Jan 2018 13:41:51 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

<item>
	<title>Sanyam Khurana - Ending the year with MozCoffee</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">tag:SanyamKhurana.com,2017-12-24:blog/mozcoffee-2017-end.html</guid>
	<link>http://SanyamKhurana.com/blog/mozcoffee-2017-end.html</link>
	<description>We had MozCoffee Delhi on last Saturday, Dec 23, 2017. We had a lot of Rep Attendees this time with other Mozillians. What would have been a better way to end an year than the MozCoffee. From past various months, ...</description>
	<pubDate>Sun, 24 Dec 2017 15:04:00 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

<item>
	<title>Official Reps Blog - New Council Members – Autumn 2017</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.mozilla.org/mozillareps/?p=519</guid>
	<link>https://blog.mozilla.org/mozillareps/2017/12/13/new-council-members-autumn-2017/</link>
	<description>We are very happy to announce our 2 new council members Prathamesh Chavan and Mayur Patil are fully onboarded and already working moving the Mozilla Reps program forward. Of course we would like to thank a lot the 2 outcoming ...</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2017 22:34:12 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

<item>
	<title>Viswaprasath KS - Year in review 2017</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">https://iamvp7.github.io//Year-in-review-2017/</guid>
	<link>https://iamvp7.github.io//Year-in-review-2017/</link>
	<description>2017 is one of the amazing year I had. I have dedicated it fully to learn and share my knowledge about WebExtension and develop some WebExtension during my free time.</description>
	<pubDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2017 01:34:00 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

<item>
	<title>Mehul Patel - Maker Fest 2018, Ahmedabad – Call for Participation</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.rowdymehul.com/?p=1458</guid>
	<link>http://www.rowdymehul.com/mozilla/maker-fest-2018-ahmedabad-call-for-participation/</link>
	<description>Hey Mozillians! We are so thrilled to announce that Mozilla India is partnering with the India’s largest Maker Festival, Maker Fest 2018 for the 5th consecutive year. The call for participation is open for all Mozillians. Mozilla India has partnered ...</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2017 18:59:10 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

<item>
	<title>Christophe Villeneuve - Retour sur le meetup-hackathon WebExtensions</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">urn:md5:1e47a3027ffc329dd34f5915c1b93018</guid>
	<link>https://blog.mozfr.org/post/2017/12/retour-meetup-hackathon-WebExtensions</link>
	<description>Les 17 et 18 novembre dernier, Mozilla Paris accueillait un hackathon dédié aux WebExtensions. Ce nouveau modèle d’extensions multinavigateur était devenu exclusif dans Firefox quelques jours plus tôt. Une soirée de présentation a précédé la journée de programmation de ces ...</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 13:47:08 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

<item>
	<title>Md Shahbaz Alam - WebVR Camp @ JRU, Ranchi</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://alamshahbaz.wordpress.com/?p=929</guid>
	<link>https://alamshahbaz.wordpress.com/2017/11/30/webvr-camp-jru-ranchi/</link>
	<description>Event was the follow-up of MozAarambh . Students were very much excited to know about the Virtual reality in our previous event. So we went again with A-frame and WebVR through WebVR Camp. Event started with a warm welcome and ...</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 30 Nov 2017 14:12:29 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

<item>
	<title>Christophe Villeneuve - Mozilla au Paris Open Source Summit les 6 et 7 décembre</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">urn:md5:80e63071046691abe5b71ebfb2e1f1f4</guid>
	<link>https://blog.mozfr.org/post/2017/11/Mozilla-Paris-Open-Source-Summit-6-7-decembre</link>
	<description>Le Paris Open Source Summit, premier événement européen du Libre et de l’open source, se déroulera les 6 et 7 décembre prochains à l’Eurosites Les Docks. Vous y trouverez un salon, des conférences, des tables rondes et un village associatif ...</description>
	<pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2017 16:43:14 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

<item>
	<title>Michal Stanke - Pontoon Tools 3.0</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">https://michal.stanke.cz/2017/11/12/pontoon-tools-3-0</guid>
	<link>https://michal.stanke.cz/2017/11/12/pontoon-tools-3-0.html</link>
	<description>After 150 commits in total, Pontoon Tools got a third major release 3.0! From now on, post-installation/update tour will show you the most important features in Pontoon Tools. So this time for the last time probably (and shortly) what’s new ...</description>
	<pubDate>Sun, 12 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

<item>
	<title>Xavier Martorell - My Experience - Mozfest17</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">https://yunit0.tumblr.com/post/167299502492</guid>
	<link>https://yunit0.tumblr.com/post/167299502492</link>
	<description>Right now, I’m on my flight back from London where I had the pleasure to assist to the Mozilla Festival 2017. I’ll try to use this 2 hours of my flight time to relate to you how my experience was ...</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 09 Nov 2017 09:52:28 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

<item>
	<title>Official Reps Blog - Resources Reps, what’s next?</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.mozilla.org/mozillareps/?p=515</guid>
	<link>https://blog.mozilla.org/mozillareps/2017/11/01/resources-reps-whats-next/</link>
	<description>In the previous blog post, I wrote about the learnings that we got from the initial training session. And last Friday, we just announced the new graduates from the final phase of Resources Rep training. The assessment was made during ...</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2017 16:52:15 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

<item>
	<title>Michal Stanke - The story of me@mozilla</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">https://michal.stanke.cz/2017/10/20/the-story-of-me-at-mozilla</guid>
	<link>https://michal.stanke.cz/2017/10/20/the-story-of-me-at-mozilla.html</link>
	<description>After our successful presence on the LinuxDays conference in Prague, I have been asked by a Linux Expres for an interview, how I get to the Mozilla community, what I do there, etc. The article is not public yet The ...</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 20 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

<item>
	<title>Xavier Martorell - My Story with Mozilla</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">https://yunit0.tumblr.com/post/166545352987</guid>
	<link>https://yunit0.tumblr.com/post/166545352987</link>
	<description>I was in high school, sitting in the Computers room, taking part of a boring and monotonous class about Office IT. Because of that, I decided to open Firefox and start surfing the web for some entertainment to make the ...</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2017 20:11:36 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

<item>
	<title>Md Shahbaz Alam - MozAarambh Jharkhand RAI University</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://alamshahbaz.wordpress.com/?p=861</guid>
	<link>https://alamshahbaz.wordpress.com/2017/10/17/mozaarambh-jharkhand-rai-university/</link>
	<description>I started my journey in Mozilla as a contributor to Mozilla Community Rajasthan and met many enthusiasts who inspired me to do every possible contributions i could do to Mozilla and Open source in general. I am from Jharkhand , ...</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 17 Oct 2017 15:52:05 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

<item>
	<title>Official Reps Blog - Rep of the Month – September 2017</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.mozilla.org/mozillareps/?p=512</guid>
	<link>https://blog.mozilla.org/mozillareps/2017/10/03/rep-of-the-month-september-2017/</link>
	<description>Please join us in congratulating Kushagra Varade, our Rep of the Month for September 2017! Kushagra is a web developer from Bhopal, India and has joined the Reps program in the first Webinar we ever organized back in April. Since ...</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 03 Oct 2017 09:14:11 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

<item>
	<title>Viswaprasath KS - Weeks of Contribution- WebExtension Session7</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">https://iamvp7.github.io//MozWOC-Session7/</guid>
	<link>https://iamvp7.github.io//MozWOC-Session7/</link>
	<description>Date : 29th August 2017</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 02 Oct 2017 00:54:00 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

<item>
	<title>Viswaprasath KS - Weeks of Contribution- WebExtension Session6</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">https://iamvp7.github.io//MozWOC-Session6/</guid>
	<link>https://iamvp7.github.io//MozWOC-Session6/</link>
	<description>Date : 22nd August 2017</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 02 Oct 2017 00:34:00 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

<item>
	<title>Viswaprasath KS - Weeks of Contribution- WebExtension Session5</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">https://iamvp7.github.io//MozWOC-Session5/</guid>
	<link>https://iamvp7.github.io//MozWOC-Session5/</link>
	<description>Date : 4th August 2017</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 02 Oct 2017 00:04:00 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

<item>
	<title>Viswaprasath KS - Weeks of Contribution- WebExtension Session4</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">https://iamvp7.github.io//MozWOC-Session4/</guid>
	<link>https://iamvp7.github.io//MozWOC-Session4/</link>
	<description>Date : 2nd August 2017</description>
	<pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2017 23:34:00 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

<item>
	<title>Viswaprasath KS - MozillaTN SFDHack WebExtension Workshop</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">https://iamvp7.github.io//SFDHack-MozActivate-WebExt-workshop/</guid>
	<link>https://iamvp7.github.io//SFDHack-MozActivate-WebExt-workshop/</link>
	<description>We wanted to make a strong community in Chennai. We got this wonderful place KCG E-cell. Lot of planning went around this event, and we planned event month before.</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 29 Sep 2017 01:34:00 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

<item>
	<title>Mehul Patel - Dive Into Rust at ORDINATEUR’17</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.rowdymehul.com/?p=1416</guid>
	<link>http://www.rowdymehul.com/mozilla/dive-into-rust-at-ordinateur17/</link>
	<description>The event is focused on introducing and teaching the state of art system programming language Rust to local programmers and Mozillians in Gujarat. This is the first time Mozilla will participate at ORDINATEUR’17! The summit will involve students and tech ...</description>
	<pubDate>Sat, 23 Sep 2017 23:37:52 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

<item>
	<title>Mehul Patel - Why Open Source ?</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.rowdymehul.com/?p=1406</guid>
	<link>http://www.rowdymehul.com/mozilla/why-open-source/</link>
	<description>Firstly, let me extend the thanks to Yuvalay Electronics Lab for inviting me as Speaker to give a talk on Open Source. Moreover, kudos to you to arrange a talk on Open source first time ever in Vadodara city. About ...</description>
	<pubDate>Sat, 23 Sep 2017 22:25:32 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

<item>
	<title>Viswaprasath KS - MozillaTN SNSCT WebExtension Workshop</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">https://iamvp7.github.io//SNSCT-MozActivate-WebExt-workshop/</guid>
	<link>https://iamvp7.github.io//SNSCT-MozActivate-WebExt-workshop/</link>
	<description>Coimbatore is one of the amazing city in Tamilnadu, and its so special for MozillaTN community as we have more amazing student contributors. SNSCT college at Coimbatore is so special and is best known for QA activities.</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 19 Sep 2017 01:34:00 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

<item>
	<title>Ajay Kumar Jogawath - Mozilla Campus Club Inauguration @ BITS,Warangal</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://ajaykumarjogawath.wordpress.com/?p=499</guid>
	<link>https://ajaykumarjogawath.wordpress.com/2017/09/11/mozilla-campus-club-inauguration-bitswarangal/</link>
	<description>Hello everyone, It has been a long time, I have been writing here. This blog post will be about sharing my personal experience during the Mozilla Campus Club Inauguration at Balaji Institute of Technology and Science, Warangal, Telangana, India. I ...</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2017 06:07:02 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

<item>
	<title>Michal Stanke - Mozilla Latest Version - my first project dedicated to Mozilla</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">https://michal.stanke.cz/2017/09/07/mozilla-latest-version-my-first-project-dedicated-to-mozilla</guid>
	<link>https://michal.stanke.cz/2017/09/07/mozilla-latest-version-my-first-project-dedicated-to-mozilla.html</link>
	<description>Mozilla Latest Version (shortly Mozlv) was my first project I have written entirely because of Mozilla. It’s a WordPress plugin to get the latest version number of Firefox/Thunderbird/SeaMonkey and the corresponding links for download or release notes. Currently it loads ...</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 07 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

<item>
	<title>Ram Dayal Vaishnav - Highlights from Netherlands HackerCamp – SHA2017!</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://gurumukhi.wordpress.com/?p=882</guid>
	<link>https://gurumukhi.wordpress.com/2017/09/05/highlights-from-netherlands-hackercamp-sha/</link>
	<description>SHA, aka Still Hacking Anyways, is part of international non profit outdoor hacker camp series organized once in 4 years in The Netherlands. This year it was organized in Zeewolde on August 4th to 8th and I was honored to ...</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 04 Sep 2017 20:32:51 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

<item>
	<title>Mehul Patel - MozConnect with IEEE R10 Sectional Leadership Summit</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.rowdymehul.com/?p=1374</guid>
	<link>http://www.rowdymehul.com/mozilla/mozconnect-with-ieee-r10-sectional-leadership-summit/</link>
	<description>While wrapping up with RainOfRust campaigns I was working on reports and gathering feedbacks from the community about our recent initiative and we got an overwhelmed responses from the all around. The participation with IEEE R10 Sectional Leadership Summit was ...</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 22 Aug 2017 17:18:40 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

<item>
	<title>Abhiram Ravikumar - It’s raining Rust at Red Hat</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://abhiramrk.com/?p=322</guid>
	<link>http://abhiramrk.com/its-raining-rust-at-red-hat/</link>
	<description>I know it’s been a while since I’ve put out a post and mostly because I’m trying to learn amazing things and get my hands dirty, trying to build solutions that actually make sense. One such pet-project has been Rust, ...</description>
	<pubDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2017 14:21:43 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

<item>
	<title>Official Reps Blog - Reps Program Objectives – Q3 2017</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.mozilla.org/mozillareps/?p=510</guid>
	<link>https://blog.mozilla.org/mozillareps/2017/08/15/reps-program-objectives-q3-2017/</link>
	<description>As with every quarter, we define Objectives and Key Results for the Reps Program. We are happy to announce the Objectives for the current quarter. Objective 1: The Reps program continues to grow its process maturity KR1: 20 Reps have ...</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 15 Aug 2017 08:16:02 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

<item>
	<title>Robert Reyes - First Time at COSCUP Taiwan</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.bobreyes.com/myblog/?p=5421</guid>
	<link>http://www.bobreyes.com/myblog/first-time-coscup-taiwan/</link>
	<description>I had the opportunity to represent Mozilla (and my country) in COSCUP 2017 over the weekend. COSCUP is an annual conference held by Taiwanese Open source community participants since 2006. It’s a major force of Free software movement advocacy in ...</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 07 Aug 2017 02:35:27 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

<item>
	<title>Viswaprasath KS - Weeks of Contribution- WebExtension Session3</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">https://iamvp7.github.io//MozWOC-Session3/</guid>
	<link>https://iamvp7.github.io//MozWOC-Session3/</link>
	<description>Date : 28th July 2017</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 28 Jul 2017 23:34:00 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

<item>
	<title>Viswaprasath KS - Weeks of Contribution- WebExtension Session1</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">https://iamvp7.github.io//MozWOC-Session1/</guid>
	<link>https://iamvp7.github.io//MozWOC-Session1/</link>
	<description>Date : 24th July 2017</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 28 Jul 2017 23:34:00 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

<item>
	<title>Official Reps Blog - Rep of the Month – July 2017</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.mozilla.org/mozillareps/?p=508</guid>
	<link>https://blog.mozilla.org/mozillareps/2017/07/28/rep-of-the-month-july-2017/</link>
	<description>Please join us in congratulating Vigneshwer Dhinakaran, our Rep of the Month for July 2017! Vigneshwer is a data scientist working on realtime data and a tech enthusiast coming from India. During the last months, Vigneshwer (or Viki as most ...</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 28 Jul 2017 11:12:34 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

<item>
	<title>Official Reps Blog - Council at the All Hands in San Francisco</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.mozilla.org/mozillareps/?p=506</guid>
	<link>https://blog.mozilla.org/mozillareps/2017/07/25/council-at-the-all-hands-in-san-francisco/</link>
	<description>The All Hands is a special time of the year where Mozilla employees along with core volunteers gather for a week of many meetings and brainstorming. The All Hands Wiki page has more information about the general setting. During the ...</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 25 Jul 2017 11:05:52 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

<item>
	<title>Michael Kohler - WebVR/A-Frame Hackathon in Lausanne</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">https://michaelkohler.info/2017/07/24/webvr-aframe-hackathon-in-lausanne/</guid>
	<link>https://michaelkohler.info/2017/07/24/webvr-aframe-hackathon-in-lausanne/</link>
	<description>Last Saturday the Mozilla Switzerland community, together with</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 24 Jul 2017 20:49:55 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

<item>
	<title>Mehul Patel - Rain Of Rust – How we did it?</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.rowdymehul.com/?p=1343</guid>
	<link>http://www.rowdymehul.com/mozilla/rain-of-rust-how-we-did-it/</link>
	<description>Growing up I was a tech geek, always kept myself updated with the latest ongoing in the language world. It always excited me to explore the tiny bits of these platforms and constantly kept myself updated with brushing my knowledge. ...</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 18 Jul 2017 10:35:00 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

<item>
	<title>Official Reps Blog - Reps Mobilizer Experiment</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.mozilla.org/mozillareps/?p=503</guid>
	<link>https://blog.mozilla.org/mozillareps/2017/07/10/reps-mobilizer-experiment/</link>
	<description>During the second quarter of 2017, and in order to understand how to better identify, recruit and support mobilizers, we decided to run a small experiment with a reduced set of existing “best in class” mobilizers and walk with them ...</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2017 13:25:18 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

<item>
	<title>Md Shahbaz Alam - Let’s increase Firefox Market share</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://alamshahbaz.wordpress.com/?p=852</guid>
	<link>https://alamshahbaz.wordpress.com/2017/07/02/lets-increase-firefox-market-share/</link>
	<description>With the Andreas Gal’s latest post it is quite clear that we are losing our market share and same can be seen on Wikipedia’s Usage Share Page. I am a Mozilla Rep. When I joined Mozilla 4 years back, I ...</description>
	<pubDate>Sun, 02 Jul 2017 06:40:47 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

<item>
	<title>Official Reps Blog - Rep of the Month – June 2017</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.mozilla.org/mozillareps/?p=501</guid>
	<link>https://blog.mozilla.org/mozillareps/2017/06/30/rep-of-the-month-june-2017/</link>
	<description>Please join us in congratulating Mehul Patel, our Rep of the Month for June 2017! Mehul is an highly motivated Rep from India supporting and enabling many Mozillians in the region of Pune, Nashik and Gujrat. He is also a ...</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 30 Jun 2017 21:45:12 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

<item>
	<title>Sanyam Khurana - Why you should contribute to Open Source</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">tag:SanyamKhurana.com,2017-06-26:blog/why-contribute-to-foss.html</guid>
	<link>http://SanyamKhurana.com/blog/why-contribute-to-foss.html</link>
	<description>My first step with FOSS was during the summer of 2014, where I got introduced to DGPLUG (Durgapur Linux Users Group). Every year, they conduct a training over IRC covering a wide range of topics. Since then, I&#39;ve been contributing ...</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 26 Jun 2017 11:41:00 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

<item>
	<title>Official Reps Blog - New Council Members – Spring 2017</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.mozilla.org/mozillareps/?p=497</guid>
	<link>https://blog.mozilla.org/mozillareps/2017/06/23/new-council-members-spring-2017/</link>
	<description>We are very happy to announce that our new council members are already onboarded and working on their focus areas. We are also extremely happy with the participation we had for these elections as for the first time we had ...</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 23 Jun 2017 09:39:39 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

<item>
	<title>Md Shahbaz Alam - A-frame Bug Fixing Contest</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://alamshahbaz.wordpress.com/?p=848</guid>
	<link>https://alamshahbaz.wordpress.com/2017/06/10/a-frame-bug-fixing-contest/</link>
	<description>Hello Mozilla India! We are inviting all the new developers as well as everyone else interested in contributing, to take part in the A-Frame bug fixing contest. A quick description for those who don’t know, A-Frame is an open-source web ...</description>
	<pubDate>Sat, 10 Jun 2017 06:43:29 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

<item>
	<title>Tanzeel Khan - Kashmir Uses Firefox Nightly</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://khantanzeel.wordpress.com/?p=350</guid>
	<link>https://khantanzeel.wordpress.com/2017/05/25/kashmir-uses-firefox-nightly/</link>
	<description>The event was a part of PAN India pilot campaign for Firefox Nightly aimed to create a strong technical community who will be using and testing Nightly on a regular basis. Besides, it was a meetup for community members in ...</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 25 May 2017 15:55:59 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

<item>
	<title>Md Shahbaz Alam - Jaipur Uses Firefox Nightly</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://alamshahbaz.wordpress.com/?p=779</guid>
	<link>https://alamshahbaz.wordpress.com/2017/05/16/jaipur-uses-firefox-nightly/</link>
	<description>It was an initiative to run a pilot campaign for Firefox Nightly in Jaipur as it is happening throughout India. Through this event we wanted be building strong technical community in Jaipur which will be using and testing Nightly on ...</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 16 May 2017 04:31:14 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

<item>
	<title>Nino Vranesic - Let’s focus on privacy and get rid of the clutter</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.elnino.si/post/160523882052</guid>
	<link>http://blog.elnino.si/post/160523882052</link>
	<description>We live in Information Society in which the creation and distribution of information has become the...</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 10 May 2017 19:49:39 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

<item>
	<title>Biraj Karmakar - India uses Firefox Nightly: Kick off on May 1, 2017</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://birajkarmakar.wordpress.com/?p=1367</guid>
	<link>https://birajkarmakar.wordpress.com/2017/04/25/india-uses-firefox-nightly-kick-off-on-may-1-2017/</link>
	<description>In my last blog, I have announced that Mozilla India is going to organize a special campaign on Firefox Nightly Usage in India. RSVP here. Everything is set. Gearing up for the campaign. BTW Recently we have organized one community ...</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 25 Apr 2017 13:02:38 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

<item>
	<title>Robert Reyes - Pinoy Mozillians at the 2017 Asian L10n Workshop in Taipei</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.bobreyes.com/myblog/?p=5149</guid>
	<link>http://www.bobreyes.com/myblog/pinoy-mozillians-2017-asian-l10n-workshop-taipei/</link>
	<description>A delegation of four (04) Pinoy Mozillians participated in the weekend-long workshop for Mozilla Localization (L10n) at Mozilla Taiwan office. Heading the delegation was your’s truly, with fellow Mozilla Rep Frederick Villaluna, and Localizers Richmond Lacanlalay and Michelle Manlogon. Bye, ...</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 24 Apr 2017 14:55:59 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

<item>
	<title>Nino Vranesic - We need diversity and polymorphism to secure future of the Web</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.elnino.si/post/159804822072</guid>
	<link>http://blog.elnino.si/post/159804822072</link>
	<description>The digital revolution is now part of our everyday life. Much of the digital change has happened at...</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2017 22:41:46 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

</channel>
</rss>
