<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

<channel>
  <title>Mozilla Reps Planet</title>
  <link>http://planet.mozillareps.org</link>
  <language>en</language>
  <description>Mozilla Reps Planet - http://planet.mozillareps.org</description>
  <atom:link rel="self" href="http://planet.mozillareps.org/rss20full.xml" type="application/rss+xml"/>


<item>
  <title>Official Reps Blog - New Council members – 2019 Spring elections</title>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.mozilla.org/mozillareps/?p=590</guid>
  <link>https://blog.mozilla.org/mozillareps/2019/06/04/new-council-members-2019-spring-elections/</link>
  <description>
    <![CDATA[<p>We are very happy to announce that our 5 new Council members are are fully on-boarded and already working moving the Mozilla Reps program forward.</p>
<p><a href="http://blog.mozilla.org/mozillareps/files/2019/06/collage-council.png"><img alt="" class="aligncenter  wp-image-591" height="339" src="http://blog.mozilla.org/mozillareps/files/2019/06/collage-council-300x225.png" width="452" /></a></p>
<p>In more detail here are the subjects that they will work on:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://reps.mozilla.org/u/yomanpatil/">Mayur Patil</a>: Campaigns engagement and Newsletter work</li>
<li><a href="https://reps.mozilla.org/u/Tuxxy/">Yuliana Jimenez</a>: improving the onboarding experience</li>
<li><a href="https://reps.mozilla.org/u/prathamesh/">Prathamesh Chavan</a>: Reaching out to external entities</li>
<li><a href="https://reps.mozilla.org/u/shahidfarooqui/">Shahid Farooqui</a>: Reps value proposition</li>
<li><a href="https://reps.mozilla.org/u/Irvin/">Irvin Chen:</a> will continue his work on bridging the local communities with the program</li>
</ul>
<p>Of course we would like to thank our outgoing Reps council members <a href="https://reps.mozilla.org/u/Mte90/">Daniele</a>, <a href="https://reps.mozilla.org/u/manel_rhaiem92/">Manel</a> and <a href="https://reps.mozilla.org/u/omudongo/">Oarabile</a> for all their contributions during their last year in the program.</p>
<p>The Mozilla Reps Council is the governing body of the Mozilla Reps Program. It provides the general vision of the program and oversees day-to-day operations globally. Currently, 7 volunteers and 2 paid staff sit on the council.<a href="https://wiki.mozilla.org/ReMo/Council"> Find out more on the Reps wiki</a>.</p>
<p> </p>]]>
  </description>
  <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2019 16:02:00 +0000</pubDate>
  
</item>

<item>
  <title>Official Reps Blog - Rep of the Month – April 2019</title>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.mozilla.org/mozillareps/?p=587</guid>
  <link>https://blog.mozilla.org/mozillareps/2019/05/13/rep-of-the-month-april-2019/</link>
  <description>
    <![CDATA[<div class="cooked">
<p>Please join us in congratulating <a href="https://reps.mozilla.org/u/21lidyaa/">Lidya Christina</a>, Rep of the Month for April 2019!</p>
<p>Lidya Christina is from Jakarta, Indonesia. Her contribution in SUMO event in 2016 lead her into a proud Mozillian, an active contributor of Mozilla Indonesia and last March 2019 she joined the Reps program.</p>
<p><img alt="1957cca0ed448d8ba2e9a2c586a4b46c" class="d-lazyload" height="400" src="https://discourse-paas-production-content.s3.dualstack.us-east-1.amazonaws.com/original/3X/a/8/a88cacd520a5476f3929b53f4df37a1af5caa21f.jpeg" width="400" /></p>
<p>In addition to that, she’s also a key member that oversees the day to day operational work in Mozilla Community space Jakarta, while at the same time regularly organizing localization event and actively participating in campaigns like Firefox 66 Support Mozilla Sprint, Firefox Fights for you, Become a dark funnel detective and Common Voice sprints.</p>
<p>Congratulations and keep rocking the open web! <img alt=":tada:" class="emoji" height="20" src="https://discourse.mozilla.org/images/emoji/twitter/tada.png?v=9" title=":tada:" width="20" /> <img alt=":tada:" class="emoji" height="20" src="https://discourse.mozilla.org/images/emoji/twitter/tada.png?v=9" title=":tada:" width="20" /></p>
<p><a href="https://discourse.mozilla.org/t/rep-of-the-month-april-2019/40229">To congratulate Lidya, please head over to Discourse!</a></p>
</div>]]>
  </description>
  <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2019 17:07:21 +0000</pubDate>
  
</item>

<item>
  <title>Viswaprasath KS - WebXR talk at VIT DevSpace</title>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://vp7techie.wordpress.com/?p=901</guid>
  <link>https://vp7techie.wordpress.com/2019/05/12/webxr-talk-at-vit-devspace/</link>
  <description>
    <![CDATA[<p>VIT, Vellore is one of the most reputed college in Tamilnadu. At the end of this March they organized <a href="https://devspace.csivit.com/">DevSpace</a>, Computer science department and Computer Society Students branch of college teamed up and organized this event. It is one of the amazing event and the students were very enthusiastic to learn more. </p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img alt="" class="wp-image-902" src="https://vp7techie.files.wordpress.com/2019/05/img_20190512_231707.jpg?w=1140" />DevSpace 2019 Speaker Tag</figure>



<p>I got opportunity to share about WebXR (focusing WebAR mostly using Aframe and AR.js) for this event.  I was very excited to talk about WebAR for this event mainly because this is the first time I am going to give the talk  on this topic and as usual my Mozilla Techspeaker friends and MozillaReps helped me a lot to prepare this topic. To name few friends Fabien, Karthikeyan and Bhuvana.</p>



<p><strong>My Agenda of the Talk</strong></p>



<ul><li>To discuss Why WebAR instead of Native</li><li>Different Technologies / libraries</li><li>Different types of AR apps</li><li>What is Aframe<ul><li>Showing Demos of Aframe</li><li>EC System in Aframe</li></ul></li><li>What is Marker Based AR<ul><li>Building Custom Markers</li></ul></li><li>Limitations of Various Libraries</li></ul>



<p><strong>Why this is amazing event</strong></p>



<p>Devspace has attracted more number of students and student startup. Around 150 students had attended my session.  There were some more session a day before and after my session. Session from Amazon, IBM Watson,  branch.io and so on were there.  Then in the afternoon the hackathon was there.  It will be great if more and more session like this happen at this college. After the event was having the discussion with the  organizers  about improving the event. There was a plan from the team to make the FOSS Specific conference to bring in more students across Tamilnadu. Two teams who were doing projects at the hackathon had been doing projects related to Augmented Reality. They were thinking to use Aframe and AR.js.  Still most of the students / professional are thinking more projects around Marker based AR or when they go for Markerless AR then its very huge for implementing. More proper library support should come so developers can hack and build some amazing things.</p>



<p>I am very happy and should thank organizers team for the effort they made. They helped right from booking the tickets, late night check-in to the room for my stay, dropping me again at the railway, the ID card they designed, fetching the details about the speakers instead of asking us.</p>
		<div class="wpcnt">
			<div class="wpa wpmrec">
				<span class="wpa-about">Advertisements</span>
				<div class="u">		<div style="padding-bottom: 15px; width: 300px; height: 250px; float: left; margin-right: 5px; margin-top: 0px;">
			<div id="atatags-26942-5cfd59b5703e7">
				
			</div>
		</div></div>
				
			</div>
		</div>]]>
  </description>
  <pubDate>Sun, 12 May 2019 17:52:40 +0000</pubDate>
  
</item>

<item>
  <title>Bhuvana Meenakshi Koteeswaran - Discovery of another passion!</title>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://kbmtechie.wordpress.com/?p=331</guid>
  <link>https://kbmtechie.wordpress.com/2019/04/07/discovery-of-another-passion/</link>
  <description>
    <![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;">During this year’s traditional festival of Tamil Nadu, I not only celebrated it in a holy way but also I <em><strong>learnt</strong></em>, <em><strong>shared</strong></em> and <em><strong>discovered</strong></em>. Yes, this was the exact time that the<a href="https://events.mozilla.org/firefoxfightsforyoucampaign" rel="noopener" target="_blank"> </a><strong><a href="https://events.mozilla.org/firefoxfightsforyoucampaign" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Firefox Fights For You</a> </strong>video challenge was open and I was always eager to put my creative skills into this.</p>
<p><img alt="photo_2019-04-08_00-02-53" class="  wp-image-337 aligncenter" height="346" src="https://kbmtechie.files.wordpress.com/2019/04/photo_2019-04-08_00-02-53.jpg?w=461&amp;h=346" width="461" /></p>
<p><strong>Learnt:</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Once the challenged was announced I questioned myself how to do this in a unique way because I was sure that everyone willl literally localise the content and edit the videos accordingly. But to stand out of the crowd there must be a wow-factor that not only impress the judges but also attract a lot in YouTube and other social media platforms as there were two types of awards. So, I thought since the harvest festival of my state was also fast approaching I gathered my friends and other Mozillians in my town as they had a lot of festive holidays. The next day, we planned to go to the country side nearby and do the video shoot. The plan was to do the video not only with localised content (the <strong>Mozilla TN L10n </strong>played a vital role in the precised translation), but also to show the culture of our region.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">After we stepped into the fields the villagers looked at us in surprise and mistook us as the movie actors/ directors. I spoke with them all and made them feel comfortable and asked them to participate in the video too. Although many of them were shy, I managed to convince a few girls and boys to do a little stuff.</p>
<p><img alt="photo_2019-04-08_00-00-41" class="  wp-image-336 aligncenter" height="257" src="https://kbmtechie.files.wordpress.com/2019/04/photo_2019-04-08_00-00-41.jpg?w=456&amp;h=257" width="456" /></p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Shared:</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">We took a few breaks in between the shoot and I observed these young crowd from the country side alone happened to use smart phones. I was happy that they were digitally connected, so I just tested their literarcy on web as they had some 2G speed internet connected to their phones and also they have laptops at home which they get from the government for free of cost. I asked them the frequent browser they use and the default answer was Google and I asked them why not <strong>Firefox </strong>and their response was that they did not know much about it because they are hardly even taught to handle the gadgets but just they see Google everywhere they even thought its the only existing browser.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">I took this opportunity to share them what latest <strong><a href="https://www.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/new/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Firefox browser</a> and <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=org.mozilla.rocket&amp;hl=en_IN" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Firefox Lite</a> </strong> has for them and how they must be very aware of the “privacy and security”. It was very new to them and I also showed them <a href="https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">MDN</a>, which willl be helpful for them start with. They apparantely did not know they can develop things themselves and even make their own user. Moreover, I also encouraged all the people of different ages to use internet in a healthy way because the community consisted of farmers and owners of very small-scale industries. They were awe-struck to know the benefits and opportunites.</p>
<p> </p>

<a href="https://kbmtechie.wordpress.com/2019/04/07/discovery-of-another-passion/photo_2019-04-08_00-00-35/#main"><img alt="" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail" height="150" src="https://kbmtechie.files.wordpress.com/2019/04/photo_2019-04-08_00-00-35.jpg?w=100&amp;h=150" width="100" /></a>
<a href="https://kbmtechie.wordpress.com/2019/04/07/discovery-of-another-passion/photo_2019-04-08_00-00-31/#main"><img alt="" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail" height="84" src="https://kbmtechie.files.wordpress.com/2019/04/photo_2019-04-08_00-00-31.jpg?w=150&amp;h=84" width="150" /></a>
<a href="https://kbmtechie.wordpress.com/2019/04/07/discovery-of-another-passion/photo_2019-04-08_00-00-29/#main"><img alt="" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail" height="84" src="https://kbmtechie.files.wordpress.com/2019/04/photo_2019-04-08_00-00-29.jpg?w=150&amp;h=84" width="150" /></a>

<p><strong>Discovered:</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">The place where we went to take a video shoot at last became a campaign mission. Anyway I loved the way things went. I am so happy that I educated many and also I provided certain directions on how the video has to be composed and asked everyone to tell out the dialogues assigned to them.</p>
<p>The main things that highlight our video:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Localised precisely</strong></li>
<li><strong>Diversity and inclusion</strong></li>
<li><strong>Clarity on the content</strong></li>
<li><strong>Most of the participants were <a href="https://mozillians.org/en-US/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Mozillians</a></strong></li>
<li><strong>Spread it widely</strong></li>
</ul>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Finally, the videos were uploaded on <a href="https://youtu.be/pze7UZoA5KA" rel="noopener" target="_blank">YouTube</a> and the words were spread on many platform (the Mozilla TN Social Media team did a great job!). Also I was inspired with the other <a href="https://youtu.be/XlDKT5rPW_E?list=PLwdR-058nLX6ow0JNTs5vzsnU3DAxRdvn" rel="noopener" target="_blank">videos</a> too and I appreciate everyone who took efforts to do this.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">After few days, the winners were announced and was really astonished to see that “we” won the “<strong>The most Popularity Award</strong>“. Yes, it was a great team to work with and I thank every <a href="https://mozillatn.github.io/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">MozillaTN </a> contributor who worked on bringing out things very perfectly as I tried to visualize.</p>
<div class="embed-twitter">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">As promised, here are the winners of the <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/FFFY?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#FFFY</a> video challenge. Thank you everyone for participating and congrats for those who win <img alt="👏" class="wp-smiley" src="https://s0.wp.com/wp-content/mu-plugins/wpcom-smileys/twemoji/2/72x72/1f44f.png" style="height: 1em;" /><img alt="👏" class="wp-smiley" src="https://s0.wp.com/wp-content/mu-plugins/wpcom-smileys/twemoji/2/72x72/1f44f.png" style="height: 1em;" /> <a href="https://t.co/NNtCOX1yz1">https://t.co/NNtCOX1yz1</a></p>
<p>— Mozilla Reps (@mozillareps) <a href="https://twitter.com/mozillareps/status/1096329046542114816?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">February 15, 2019</a></p></blockquote>
<p></p></div>
<p> </p>
<p>As a reward all the participants received a cool special edition T-shirt. Thanks Mozilla and Mozilla Reps for the same <img alt="🙂" class="wp-smiley" src="https://s0.wp.com/wp-content/mu-plugins/wpcom-smileys/twemoji/2/72x72/1f642.png" style="height: 1em;" /></p>
<div class="embed-twitter">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Thanks a lot <a href="https://twitter.com/firefox?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@firefox</a> and <a href="https://twitter.com/mozilla?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@mozilla</a> for recognising our video as the best one under "Popularity category" <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/FFFY?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#FFFY</a> video challenge and rewarding all of us with cool limited edition tees<img alt="😎" class="wp-smiley" src="https://s0.wp.com/wp-content/mu-plugins/wpcom-smileys/twemoji/2/72x72/1f60e.png" style="height: 1em;" /></p>
<p>And yes we've got a fox in this fight!!!<img alt="✊" class="wp-smiley" src="https://s0.wp.com/wp-content/mu-plugins/wpcom-smileys/twemoji/2/72x72/270a.png" style="height: 1em;" /><img alt="✌" class="wp-smiley" src="https://s0.wp.com/wp-content/mu-plugins/wpcom-smileys/twemoji/2/72x72/270c.png" style="height: 1em;" /><a href="https://twitter.com/mozillaTN?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@mozillaTN</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/MozillaIN?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@MozillaIN</a>  <a href="https://twitter.com/mozillareps?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@mozillareps</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/mozlove?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#mozlove</a> <a href="https://t.co/sXXvQGFJHB">pic.twitter.com/sXXvQGFJHB</a></p>
<p>— Bhuvana Meenakshi (@bhuvanakotees1) <a href="https://twitter.com/bhuvanakotees1/status/1110124027161382912?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">March 25, 2019</a></p></blockquote>
<p></p></div>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Above all celebrations and suprises, the most important lesson in my life is that I found the hidden talent in me as “<strong>director</strong>“. I never imagined myself in this context before but I just loved doing this. Thanks <a href="https://reps.mozilla.org/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Mozilla Reps</a> and Firefox for this opportunity!</p>
<p><img alt="photo_2019-04-01_22-42-00" class="  wp-image-332 aligncenter" height="278" src="https://kbmtechie.files.wordpress.com/2019/04/photo_2019-04-01_22-42-00.jpg?w=371&amp;h=278" width="371" /></p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>]]>
  </description>
  <pubDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2019 18:37:47 +0000</pubDate>
  
</item>

<item>
  <title>Viswaprasath KS - Add-ons session at LPU</title>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://vp7techie.wordpress.com/?p=889</guid>
  <link>https://vp7techie.wordpress.com/2019/03/31/lpu2019/</link>
  <description>
    <![CDATA[<p>LPU generally called as Lovely Professional University is well known university in India. Recently the students club organized one of the amazing event  <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/DiveIntoOpenSource?src=hashtag_click">#DiveIntoOpenSource</a>  </p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img alt="" class="wp-image-890" src="https://vp7techie.files.wordpress.com/2019/03/d2sfhbkwwaoixiq.jpeg?w=1140" /></figure>



<p>It was not a very easy travel to LPU. I to some extent I love travel but too much of travel is very difficult. The schedule of travel was very difficult around 7:30 PM i started from office, my flight was around 10:30 reached Delhi around 2:00 and was there for more than 3 hours and then from 5:30 started from there and reached AMRITSAR around 6:45. From there Amritsar started in the bus and travelled to Punjab and reached around 10:00.  It was very difficult travel which was first time inside India. I had the keynote session “Getting Started with Open source” where I was about to share my journey in Open source. Since I reached late the students were waiting that time was caught by  Vishal, this is the really  good attitude which I liked.  I always say to my mentee we should always make sure no one waits for us. In India, still we are new to FOSS technologies, students / professionals still go behind Brand names even when they know / use the alternatives.</p>



<p></p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed-twitter wp-block-embed is-type-rich"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<div class="embed-twitter"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p dir="ltr" lang="en">Super privileged to have <a href="https://twitter.com/iamVP7?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@iamVP7</a> as our keynote speaker! <img alt="💖" class="wp-smiley" src="https://s0.wp.com/wp-content/mu-plugins/wpcom-smileys/twemoji/2/72x72/1f496.png" style="height: 1em;" /> <a href="https://t.co/oQGfhx2yCl">pic.twitter.com/oQGfhx2yCl</a></p>— Mozilla Punjab (@MozPunjab) <a href="https://twitter.com/MozPunjab/status/1107230001655676928?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">March 17, 2019</a></blockquote></div>
</div></figure>



<p>So I got up freshen-up  and reached the Workshop room around 10:40. There myself and Shivam started our session on WebExtension. This topic is always close to my heart. WebExtension is one the way we can interact with Browser Features and make them work for us. Browser is always meant for users to work, it will obey for us and this is the way its designed for. Browser are designed for people. Myself and Shivam divided the Session as below.</p>



<ul><li>Introduction of WebExtension by Viswaprasath<ol><li>What is WebExtension</li><li>Types of UI and Scripts</li><li>How to configure developer settings in Browser</li></ol></li><li>Live coding and Demo by Shivam</li><li>Code explanation by Viswa</li></ul>



<figure class="wp-block-embed-twitter wp-block-embed is-type-rich"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<div class="embed-twitter"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p dir="ltr" lang="en"><a href="https://twitter.com/iamVP7?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@iamVP7</a> and Shivam started the day with <a href="https://twitter.com/mozamo?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@mozamo</a> <a href="https://t.co/eLVwflIB0s">pic.twitter.com/eLVwflIB0s</a></p>— Mozilla Punjab (@MozPunjab) <a href="https://twitter.com/MozPunjab/status/1109434765780774914?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">March 23, 2019</a></blockquote></div>
</div></figure>



<p>Each and every session is unique, we get to meet large number of audience and learn something new from them. One of the feedback I got which was “They got to learn how the<strong> Keep by Google </strong>Add-on on Chrome sends selected data to keep.google.com” ( an example using Context menu)  Around 2 PM we finished our session and started for lunch.</p>



<p>In the afternoon session We had other session in the afternoon.</p>



<ul><li>Plasma Mobile </li><li>Kotlin</li><li>Git and Github</li></ul>



<p>At the end of the day we had some of the group pics and ice breaking sessions like Quiz.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed-twitter wp-block-embed is-type-rich"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<div class="embed-twitter"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p dir="ltr" lang="en">Well, look at them, the best part of today was them, and even the better part was the amount of female participants <img alt="💖" class="wp-smiley" src="https://s0.wp.com/wp-content/mu-plugins/wpcom-smileys/twemoji/2/72x72/1f496.png" style="height: 1em;" /><a href="https://twitter.com/mozilla?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@mozilla</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/github?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@github</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/flutterio?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@flutterio</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/kotlin?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@kotlin</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/mozilla_l10n?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@mozilla_l10n</a> we had them all, and more is coming tomorrow <img alt="😍" class="wp-smiley" src="https://s0.wp.com/wp-content/mu-plugins/wpcom-smileys/twemoji/2/72x72/1f60d.png" style="height: 1em;" /> <a href="https://t.co/ULRjxUe4uV">pic.twitter.com/ULRjxUe4uV</a></p>— Mozilla Punjab (@MozPunjab) <a href="https://twitter.com/MozPunjab/status/1109446382291582978?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">March 23, 2019</a></blockquote></div>
</div></figure>



<figure class="wp-block-embed-twitter wp-block-embed is-type-rich"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<div class="embed-twitter"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p dir="ltr" lang="en">And them, well we truly love them, who made it possible, and can't wait for more, tomorrow <img alt="😍" class="wp-smiley" src="https://s0.wp.com/wp-content/mu-plugins/wpcom-smileys/twemoji/2/72x72/1f60d.png" style="height: 1em;" /><img alt="💖" class="wp-smiley" src="https://s0.wp.com/wp-content/mu-plugins/wpcom-smileys/twemoji/2/72x72/1f496.png" style="height: 1em;" /> <a href="https://t.co/MnBiliiL17">pic.twitter.com/MnBiliiL17</a></p>— Mozilla Punjab (@MozPunjab) <a href="https://twitter.com/MozPunjab/status/1109446732029415424?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">March 23, 2019</a></blockquote></div>
</div></figure>



<p>As a speaker I personally vouch other Evangelist should come to this college and share their technical knowledge. I can say the students who attended the event had enough knowledge to under Javascript / Kotlin / Other topic. I even saw some of them were easily using Amazon AWS.</p>



<p>I was Unfortunate was not there for the second day, heard we had session on pontoon L10N tool, Aframe and many more. </p>



<p><strong>Some of the Resources shared at the event to learn MozWebExt</strong></p>



<ul><li>Documentation : <a href="https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Mozilla/Add-ons/WebExtensions">Link</a></li><li>Video tutorials   :  <ul><li>Viswaprasath : <a href="https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLdIyyZgtQZ7CJR5XFB5xvZH0oaBIT_gTD">Link</a></li><li>Trishul : <a href="https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLI08QU9qtPEJiBs7rVOT4FvXJlisDgTlS">Link</a> </li></ul></li><li>Code Samples : <a href="https://github.com/iamVP7/mozwebext_book_src">Link</a></li><li>Free E-Book : <a href="http://leanpub.com/mozwebext/">Link</a></li></ul>]]>
  </description>
  <pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2019 15:50:07 +0000</pubDate>
  
</item>

<item>
  <title>Official Reps Blog - Rep of the Month – February 2019</title>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.mozilla.org/mozillareps/?p=581</guid>
  <link>https://blog.mozilla.org/mozillareps/2019/03/14/rep-of-the-month-february-2019/</link>
  <description>
    <![CDATA[<p>Please join us in congratulating <a href="https://reps.mozilla.org/u/edovio/" rel="nofollow noopener">Edoardo Viola</a>, our Rep of the Month for February 2019!</p>
<p>Edoardo is a long-time Mozillian from Italy and has been a Rep for almost two years. He’s a Resource Rep and has been on the Reps Council until January. When he’s not busy with Reps work, Edoardo is a Mentor in the <a href="https://foundation.mozilla.org/en/opportunity/mozilla-open-leaders/" rel="nofollow noopener">Open Leadership Training Program</a>. In the past he has contributed to Campus Clubs as well as MozFest, where he was a Space Wrangler for the Web Literacy Track.</p>
<div class="lightbox-wrapper">
<p><a class="lightbox" href="https://discourse-paas-production-content.s3.dualstack.us-east-1.amazonaws.com/original/3X/1/8/18f04ead2ebad735329e8f3ac4847c6b17a0c405.jpeg" rel="nofollow noopener" title="edoardo.jpg"><img alt="edoardo" class="d-lazyload" height="460" src="https://discourse-paas-production-content.s3.dualstack.us-east-1.amazonaws.com/optimized/3X/1/8/18f04ead2ebad735329e8f3ac4847c6b17a0c405_2_690x460.jpeg" width="690" /></a></p>
<div class="meta"><span class="informations"> </span></div>
</div>
<p>Recently Edoardo helped out at FOSDEM in Brussels as part of the Mozilla volunteers organizing our presence. He helped out at the booth, as well as helping to moderate the Mozilla Dev Room. He also contributes to the Internet Health Report as part of the volunteer team to give input for the next edition of the report.</p>
<p><a href="https://discourse.mozilla.org/t/rep-of-the-month-february-2019/36947">To congratulate him, please head over to Discourse!</a></p>]]>
  </description>
  <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2019 12:32:46 +0000</pubDate>
  
</item>

<item>
  <title>Official Reps Blog - Rep of the Month – November 2018</title>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.mozilla.org/mozillareps/?p=578</guid>
  <link>https://blog.mozilla.org/mozillareps/2019/03/06/rep-of-the-month-november-2018/</link>
  <description>
    <![CDATA[<p>Please join us in congratulating <a href="https://reps.mozilla.org/u/iamvp7/" rel="nofollow noopener">Viswaprasath KS</a>, our Rep of the Month for November 2018!</p>
<p>Viswaprasath KS, also know as iamvp7, is a long time Mozillian from India who joined the Mozilla Rep program in June 2013. By profession he works as a software developer. He initially started contributing with designs and SUMO (Army of Awesome). He was also part of Firefox Student Ambassador E-Board and helped students to build exciting Firefox OS apps. In May 2014 he became one of the Firefox OS app reviewers.</p>
<div class="lightbox-wrapper">
<p><a class="lightbox" href="https://discourse-paas-production-content.s3.dualstack.us-east-1.amazonaws.com/original/3X/f/c/fc0033d28d79034e668f4594d772fc955064804f.jpeg" rel="nofollow noopener" title="vs.jpg"><img alt="vs" class="d-lazyload" height="500" src="https://discourse-paas-production-content.s3.dualstack.us-east-1.amazonaws.com/original/3X/f/c/fc0033d28d79034e668f4594d772fc955064804f.jpeg" width="500" /></a></p>
<div class="meta"><span class="informations"> </span></div>
</div>
<p>Currently he is an active Mozilla TechSpeaker and loves to evangelise about WebExtensions and Progressive Web Apps. He has been an inspiration to many and loves to keep working towards a better web. He has worked extensively on Rust and WebExtensions, conducting many informative sessions on these topics recently. Together with other Mozillians he also wrote <a href="https://leanpub.com/mozwebext" rel="nofollow noopener">“Building Browser Extension”</a>.</p>
<p>Thanks Viswaprasath, keep rocking the Open Web! <img alt=":tada:" class="emoji" src="https://cdn-production.discourse.mozilla-community.org/images/emoji/twitter/tada.png?v=6" title=":tada:" /> <img alt=":tada:" class="emoji" src="https://cdn-production.discourse.mozilla-community.org/images/emoji/twitter/tada.png?v=6" title=":tada:" /></p>
<p><a href="https://discourse.mozilla.org/t/rep-of-the-month-november-2018/36599">To congratulate him, please head over to Discourse!</a></p>]]>
  </description>
  <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2019 11:06:34 +0000</pubDate>
  
</item>

<item>
  <title>Shivam Singhal - 2018 Year in Review with AMO</title>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://championshuttler.wordpress.com/?p=417</guid>
  <link>https://championshuttler.wordpress.com/2019/02/14/2018-year-in-review-with-amo/</link>
  <description>
    <![CDATA[<figure class="graf graf--figure"><img class="graf-image" src="https://championshuttler.files.wordpress.com/2019/02/ed177-0zfi71olxub0lt9bj.jpg?w=1000&amp;h=745" />Sibelius Monument, Finland</figure>
<p class="graf graf--p">Each one of us have some goals to complete, things to learn, and places to visit. With the year getting ended, it is time to lock back and see what all did we do for the last 365 days.</p>
<p class="graf graf--p">Well, 2018 have been a phenomenal year for me. Working with Addons aka AMO Team is where the major part of 2018 was spent. I have learned how to work remotely with a cross-cultural team. I have met some super awesome people like <a class="markup--anchor markup--p-anchor" href="https://twitter.com/caitmuenster" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Caitlin</a> , <a class="markup--anchor markup--p-anchor" href="https://github.com/rebmullin" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Rebecca</a> and many more. I fixed ~50 Bugs in <a class="markup--anchor markup--p-anchor" href="http://addons.mozilla.org" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"><em class="markup--em markup--p-em">AMO</em></a>. I got to meet a lot of great people, built connections and learned things. I am really happy to see few of my goals getting completed. I failed of the things miserably too.</p>
<h3 class="graf graf--h3">Here is everything I did in the last year.</h3>
<h3 class="graf graf--h3">January</h3>
<ul class="postList">
<li class="graf graf--li">Got the idea for <a class="markup--anchor markup--li-anchor" href="https://www.npmjs.com/package/create-web-ext/" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">create-web-ext</a> — a scaffolding tool for browser extensions.</li>
<li class="graf graf--li">Talked to my mentor <a class="markup--anchor markup--li-anchor" href="https://championshuttler.com/blog/2018-year-in-review-with-AMO/trishulgoel.com" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Trishul</a> about it.</li>
</ul>
<h3 class="graf graf--h3">February</h3>
<ul class="postList">
<li class="graf graf--li">Pitched the idea of <a class="markup--anchor markup--li-anchor" href="https://championshuttler.wordpress.com/feed/invalid#zSoyz" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">create-web-ext</a> to Mozilla Addons team and asked to submit it as GSoC Project.</li>
<li class="graf graf--li">Declined as GSoC Project. Decided to go ahead to develop it.</li>
<li class="graf graf--li">Made team with my Mentor <a class="markup--anchor markup--li-anchor" href="https://championshuttler.com/blog/2018-year-in-review-with-AMO/trishulgoel.com" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Trishul</a> and <a class="markup--anchor markup--li-anchor" href="https://tushararora.github.io/" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Tushar</a> to start working on the project.</li>
<li class="graf graf--li">First International Flight to Finland for Methane Hack. Won 1500 Euros.</li>
</ul>
<h3 class="graf graf--h3">March</h3>
<ul class="postList">
<li class="graf graf--li">Spent many sleepless nights with Trishul, Tushar to work on create-web-ext.</li>
<li class="graf graf--li">Made the prototype of create-web-ext. Trishul pitched it in Addons Show &amp; Tell Meeting. Got good feedback about it <img alt="🌟" class="wp-smiley" src="https://s0.wp.com/wp-content/mu-plugins/wpcom-smileys/twemoji/2/72x72/1f31f.png" style="height: 1em;" />.</li>
</ul>
<h3 class="graf graf--h3">April</h3>
<ul class="postList">
<li class="graf graf--li">My first code contribution to AMO, a small <a class="markup--anchor markup--li-anchor" href="https://github.com/mozilla/addons-frontend/pull/4773" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">patch</a> for <a class="markup--anchor markup--li-anchor" href="https://championshuttler.com/blog/2018-year-in-review-with-AMO/addons.mozilla.org" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">amo-frontend</a>.</li>
<li class="graf graf--li">Was working on another patch, sadly never completed it, huh.</li>
<li class="graf graf--li">Applied for the Featured Addons Advisory Board. <code class="markup--code markup--li-code">REJECTED</code> <img alt="😎" class="wp-smiley" src="https://s0.wp.com/wp-content/mu-plugins/wpcom-smileys/twemoji/2/72x72/1f60e.png" style="height: 1em;" /></li>
</ul>
<h3 class="graf graf--h3">May</h3>
<ul class="postList">
<li class="graf graf--li">Fixed 8 bugs in <a class="markup--anchor markup--li-anchor" href="https://championshuttler.com/blog/2018-year-in-review-with-AMO/github.com/mozilla/addons-server" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">addons-server</a> and <a class="markup--anchor markup--li-anchor" href="https://championshuttler.com/blog/2018-year-in-review-with-AMO/github.com/addons-frontend" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">amo-frontend</a></li>
<li class="graf graf--li">Was working on twitter card implementation for addons, sadly never completed it. Felt demotivated so many times due to this bug.</li>
</ul>
<h3 class="graf graf--h3">June</h3>
<ul class="postList">
<li class="graf graf--li">Send 9 patches to <a class="markup--anchor markup--li-anchor" href="https://championshuttler.com/blog/2018-year-in-review-with-AMO/github.com/mozilla/addons-server" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">addons-server</a> and <a class="markup--anchor markup--li-anchor" href="https://championshuttler.com/blog/2018-year-in-review-with-AMO/github.com/addons-frontend" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">amo-frontend</a>. Learned about the css property: <code class="markup--code markup--li-code">word-wrap: break-word;</code></li>
<li class="graf graf--li">Went to Finland again to OuluHack Hackathon. Won 1000 Euros <img alt="💵" class="wp-smiley" src="https://s0.wp.com/wp-content/mu-plugins/wpcom-smileys/twemoji/2/72x72/1f4b5.png" style="height: 1em;" /></li>
</ul>
<h3 class="graf graf--h3">July</h3>
<ul class="postList">
<li class="graf graf--li">Sent 3 patches in <a class="markup--anchor markup--li-anchor" href="https://championshuttler.com/blog/2018-year-in-review-with-AMO/github.com/addons-frontend" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">amo-frontend</a>.</li>
<li class="graf graf--li">Made the dropdown on AMO better. Learned about test assertions.</li>
</ul>
<h3 class="graf graf--h3">August</h3>
<ul class="postList">
<li class="graf graf--li">Fixed 6 bugs in <a class="markup--anchor markup--li-anchor" href="https://championshuttler.com/blog/2018-year-in-review-with-AMO/github.com/mozilla/addons-server" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">addons-server</a> and <a class="markup--anchor markup--li-anchor" href="https://championshuttler.com/blog/2018-year-in-review-with-AMO/github.com/addons-frontend" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">amo-frontend</a>.</li>
<li class="graf graf--li">Deployed Static themes on production on AMO Frontend.</li>
<li class="graf graf--li">Learned that <code class="markup--code markup--li-code">RTL</code> means Right to Left and <code class="markup--code markup--li-code">LTR</code> Left to Right.</li>
<li class="graf graf--li">Wrote code in SQL for the first time ever for AMO Server.</li>
<li class="graf graf--li">Gave talk about browser extensions in <a class="markup--anchor markup--li-anchor" href="https://devconf.info/in" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">DevConf</a></li>
<li class="graf graf--li">Met <a class="markup--anchor markup--li-anchor" href="https://championshuttler.com/blog/2018-year-in-review-with-AMO/dgplug.org" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">dgplug</a> members Farhaan, Sayan and many others in DevConf’18.</li>
</ul>
<h3 class="graf graf--h3">September</h3>
<ul class="postList">
<li class="graf graf--li">Fixed 10 bugs in <a class="markup--anchor markup--li-anchor" href="https://championshuttler.com/blog/2018-year-in-review-with-AMO/github.com/mozilla/addons-server" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">addons-server</a> and <a class="markup--anchor markup--li-anchor" href="https://championshuttler.com/blog/2018-year-in-review-with-AMO/github.com/addons-frontend" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">amo-frontend</a>.</li>
<li class="graf graf--li">First <a class="markup--anchor markup--li-anchor" href="https://bugzilla.mozilla.org/show_bug.cgi?id=1471305" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">patch</a> to Webextensions API.</li>
<li class="graf graf--li">Went through many sleepless night to setup Gecko on my laptop for the patch. Took more than 15 days. <img alt="🤓" class="wp-smiley" src="https://s0.wp.com/wp-content/mu-plugins/wpcom-smileys/twemoji/2/72x72/1f913.png" style="height: 1em;" /></li>
<li class="graf graf--li">Decided to dual boot with Fedora OS for Gecko.</li>
<li class="graf graf--li">Sat next through to Wifi router for ~8 Hours to setup Gecko.</li>
</ul>
<h3 class="graf graf--h3">October</h3>
<ul class="postList">
<li class="graf graf--li">Sent 5 patches to <a class="markup--anchor markup--li-anchor" href="https://championshuttler.com/blog/2018-year-in-review-with-AMO/github.com/mozilla/addons-server" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">addons-server</a> and <a class="markup--anchor markup--li-anchor" href="https://championshuttler.com/blog/2018-year-in-review-with-AMO/github.com/addons-frontend" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">amo-frontend</a>.</li>
<li class="graf graf--li">Added developer policies in footer of <a class="markup--anchor markup--li-anchor" href="https://championshuttler.com/blog/2018-year-in-review-with-AMO/addons.mozilla.org" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">AMO</a>.</li>
<li class="graf graf--li">PyCon India, my 2nd time , which I attended as a volunteer.</li>
<li class="graf graf--li">Met dgplug members again in PyCon.</li>
<li class="graf graf--li">Applied for Mozilla Addons Reviewer. <strong class="markup--strong markup--li-strong">Rejected</strong>. Lesson learned — need to work on my JS Skills.</li>
</ul>
<h3 class="graf graf--h3">November &amp; December</h3>
<ul class="postList">
<li class="graf graf--li">College Exams, practical and lot of college useless stuff.</li>
<li class="graf graf--li">Managed to solve 5 bugs in the mean time only.</li>
<li class="graf graf--li">Joined Featured Addons Advisory Board for next 6 months.</li>
</ul>
<h3 class="graf graf--h3">My plans for 2019</h3>
<ul class="postList">
<li class="graf graf--li"><strong class="markup--strong markup--li-strong">Helping beginners</strong> For 2019, I am looking to help few handful new <strong class="markup--strong markup--li-strong">code</strong> contributor to AMO Project because I feel while contributing in code you get to learn a lot of things like how to communicate, code is just one part of it .</li>
<li class="graf graf--li"><strong class="markup--strong markup--li-strong">More patches</strong>. I am looking to submit patches to Addon Manager and Webextensions API in Firefox.</li>
<li class="graf graf--li"><strong class="markup--strong markup--li-strong">Eat, sleep, code, gym, repeat</strong>. Being a software developer you are most likely to keep sitting on your chair for the major part of your day. This year I want to take out more time for physical activities.</li>
</ul>]]>
  </description>
  <pubDate>Wed, 13 Feb 2019 17:27:14 +0000</pubDate>
  
</item>

<item>
  <title>Official Reps Blog - Reps OKRs – First half of the year 2019</title>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.mozilla.org/mozillareps/?p=576</guid>
  <link>https://blog.mozilla.org/mozillareps/2019/01/29/reps-okrs-first-half-of-the-year-2019/</link>
  <description>
    <![CDATA[<p>Here are the OKRs for the first half of the year:</p>
<p><b>Objective 1: Reps are the bridge between their local communities (Mozilla or other local open source communities) and the Mozilla contribution opportunities<br />
</b></p>
<ul>
<li><b>Key Result 1.1:</b> 60% of Reps have a connection with another open source community (as a result of our community connection training)</li>
<li><b>Key Result 1.2:</b> 70% of Reps have gathered data about the interests of their community</li>
</ul>
<p><b>Objective 2: Mozilla projects reach out to Reps as gateway to community engagement<br />
</b></p>
<ul>
<li><b>Key Result 2.1:</b> 200 employees say they know about the Reps program’s purpose (Implementation hint: We aim for an All Hands Lightning Talk and being featured in the tl:dr newsletter with an update about the program)</li>
<li><b>Key Result 2.2:</b> Reps collaborate with two new functional teams</li>
</ul>
<p><b>Objective 3: Reps feel more involved in the program<br />
</b></p>
<ul>
<li><b>Key Result 3.1:</b> As a result of the mobilizing activities of the Reps we are able to connect 50% of campaign outcomes to their mobilizing efforts</li>
</ul>
<p><b>Objective 4: External, non-Mozilla entities identify the Reps program as a connector to the broader Mozilla community<br />
</b></p>
<ul>
<li><b>Key Result 4.1:</b> External open source communities are informed about 2019 Reps plans with two publications</li>
<li><b>Key Result 4.2:</b> By updating the Reps description in all resources to reflect the current purpose of the program more people could explain the purpose of the Reps program</li>
</ul>
<p><b>Objective 5: Existing Reps and new applicants understand the resources we provide —<br />
</b></p>
<ul>
<li><b>Key Result 5.1:</b> we have less questions by new Reps on understanding the community coordinator role (Implementation hint: Document resources on what we provide)</li>
</ul>
<p><b>Objective 6: We understand what is missing for the Reps Program to enable personal growth<br />
</b></p>
<ul>
<li><b>Key Result 6.1:</b> 50% of Reps have reported what the Reps program helped them to do in terms of community building and personal growth</li>
<li><b>Key Result 6.2:</b> We identified 3 new personal growth area opportunities we want to provide</li>
</ul>]]>
  </description>
  <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2019 18:24:44 +0000</pubDate>
  
</item>

<item>
  <title>Bhuvana Meenakshi Koteeswaran - 2018 – Red letter days, Mozilla and Me :)</title>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://kbmtechie.wordpress.com/?p=327</guid>
  <link>https://kbmtechie.wordpress.com/2018/12/31/2018-red-letter-days-mozilla-and-me/</link>
  <description>
    <![CDATA[<p><strong>Date: 31.12.2018</strong></p>
<p> </p>
<p>With the New Year fast approaching I just recollected the sweet memories that the past year 2018 has given me. Of course a lot of ups and downs, without which life can’t be interesting.</p>
<p>Firstly I express my gratitude to all the situations, people and Mozilla for giving me more than what I expected in my life. I would like to share significant events that happened as the 2018 is going to fade out in a few hours.</p>
<p><em>January</em> – Started my internship at the D<strong>efence Research and Development Organisation, Bangalore.</strong></p>
<p><em>February- </em>Was officially selected as “<strong>Mozilla Reps</strong>“.</p>
<p><em>March</em> – 1) Invited as a speaker at <strong>PES University,</strong> Bangalore and addressed about WebVR with a mini-hackathon.</p>
<p>2) Invited as a speaker at <strong>SRM University, Chennai for Mozofest 2018</strong>.</p>
<p><em>April</em> – Completed my internship at DRDO</p>
<p><em>May</em> – Successfully graduated from college with B.E. degree</p>
<p><em>June</em> – Inaugurated a campus club , <strong>Tezilla at Narasus Sarathy Institute of Technology, Salem.</strong></p>
<p><em>August</em> – 1) Selected as a speaker at <strong>Devconf 2018, Christ University, Bangalore</strong> and spoke about Aframe and its applications where my audience were mostly developers and industrialists.</p>
<p>2) Mentored students of <strong>KGiSL college, Coimbatore</strong> for “HackyGenius” hackathon on AR/VR.</p>
<p>3) Started my internship as a Research Intern at <strong>Indian Institute of Science, Bangalore.</strong></p>
<p><em>September –</em> Organised Dark Funnel campaign at Salem.</p>
<p><em>October – </em>1) Hosted a WebVR workshop at <strong>Vidyavardaka College of Engineering, Mysore.</strong></p>
<p>2) Was selected as a facilitator at <strong>Mozfest 2018, Ravensbourne University, London. </strong>(very first time in my life I flew overseas)</p>
<p><em>November – </em>Hosted a workshop at the <strong>National Institute of Technology, Karnataka.</strong></p>
<p><em>December – </em>1) Mentored students of <strong>Ramaiah Institue of Technology, Bangalore</strong> at the <strong>Local Hack day 2018, </strong>a hackathon hosted by Github.</p>
<p>2) Hosted the first ever MozillaTN e-meetup on <strong><a href="https://hubs.mozilla.com/">Mozilla Hubs</a>.</strong></p>
<p>3) Successfully completed intership at IISc, Bangalore.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>Thanks a lot 2018 for all these joys. Hoping 2019 gives me more happiness and opportunities <img alt="🙂" class="wp-smiley" src="https://s0.wp.com/wp-content/mu-plugins/wpcom-smileys/twemoji/2/72x72/1f642.png" style="height: 1em;" /></p>
<p> </p>
<p>Happy New Year all!!!</p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>]]>
  </description>
  <pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2018 18:30:12 +0000</pubDate>
  
</item>

<item>
  <title>Robert Reyes - ASEAN Mozillian Localizers Meet at Hanoi, Vietnam</title>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.bobreyes.com/myblog/?p=5591</guid>
  <link>https://www.bobreyes.com/myblog/asean-mozillian-localizers-meet-at-hanoi-vietnam/</link>
  <description>
    <![CDATA[<p>All roads (flights, actually) lead to Hanoi, Vietnam as the Mozilla Localization Team hosted a Meetup/Workshop for Mozillian Localizers from Southeast Asia on the weekend of 17 to 18 November. The delegation from Mozilla Philippines (MozillaPH) is composed of Kemuel Domanog (from the province of Laguna), Amiel Pastor (based in Bacolod City), and myself. Our […]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.bobreyes.com/myblog/asean-mozillian-localizers-meet-at-hanoi-vietnam/" rel="nofollow">ASEAN Mozillian Localizers Meet at Hanoi, Vietnam</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.bobreyes.com/myblog" rel="nofollow">Bob Reyes Dot Com</a>.</p>]]>
  </description>
  <pubDate>Mon, 19 Nov 2018 15:21:49 +0000</pubDate>
  
</item>

<item>
  <title>Official Reps Blog - New Council Members – Fall 2018 Elections</title>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.mozilla.org/mozillareps/?p=574</guid>
  <link>https://blog.mozilla.org/mozillareps/2018/11/12/new-council-members-fall-2018-elections/</link>
  <description>
    <![CDATA[<p>We are very happy to announce that our 2 new Council members <a href="https://reps.mozilla.org/u/MonicaBonilla/">Monica Bonilla</a> and <a href="https://reps.mozilla.org/u/yofiesetiawan/">Yofie Setiawan</a> are fully on-boarded and already working moving the Mozilla Reps program forward. A warm welcome from all of us. We we are very excited to have you and can’t wait to build the program together.</p>
<p><img alt="https://www.mozilla.org/media/img/mozorg/about/leadership/monica-bonilla.2fc7c83eec6a.jpg" src="https://www.mozilla.org/media/img/mozorg/about/leadership/monica-bonilla.2fc7c83eec6a.jpg" /> <img alt="https://www.mozilla.org/media/img/mozorg/about/leadership/yofie-setiawan.2b2fde73bb65.jpg" src="https://www.mozilla.org/media/img/mozorg/about/leadership/yofie-setiawan.2b2fde73bb65.jpg" /></p>
<p>Of course we would like to thank a lot the 2 outgoing members: <a href="https://reps.mozilla.org/u/yomanpatil/">Mayur Patil</a> and <a href="https://reps.mozilla.org/u/prathamesh/">Prathamesh Chavan</a>. You have worked extremely hard to move the program forward and your input and strategic thinking have inspired the rest of the Reps.</p>
<p>The Mozilla Reps Council is the governing body of the Mozilla Reps Program. It provides the general vision of the program and oversees day-to-day operations globally. Currently, 7 volunteers and 2 paid staff sit on the council.<a href="https://wiki.mozilla.org/ReMo/Council"> Find out more on the Reps wiki</a>.</p>]]>
  </description>
  <pubDate>Mon, 12 Nov 2018 18:31:09 +0000</pubDate>
  
</item>

<item>
  <title>Official Reps Blog - Rep of the Month – October 2018</title>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.mozilla.org/mozillareps/?p=572</guid>
  <link>https://blog.mozilla.org/mozillareps/2018/11/12/rep-of-the-month-october-2018/</link>
  <description>
    <![CDATA[<p>Please join us in congratulating <a href="https://reps.mozilla.org/u/Mad_Maks/" rel="nofollow noopener">Tim Maks van den Broek</a>, our Rep of the Month for October 2018!</p>
<p>Tim is one of our most active members in the Dutch community. During his 15+ years as a Mozilla Volunteer he has touched many parts of the Project. More recently his focus is on user support and he is active in our Reps Onboarding team.</p>
<div class="lightbox-wrapper"><a class="lightbox" href="https://discourse-paas-production-content.s3.dualstack.us-east-1.amazonaws.com/original/3X/2/9/294ce992b9168007f3ab0f47cb76b15ebf06f05b.jpeg" rel="nofollow noopener" title="www.libravatar.org.jpg"><img alt="org" height="500" src="https://discourse-paas-production-content.s3.dualstack.us-east-1.amazonaws.com/original/3X/2/9/294ce992b9168007f3ab0f47cb76b15ebf06f05b.jpeg" width="500" /></a></div>
<p>On the Onboarding Team he dedicates time for new Reps joining the project to ensure a smooth process in getting to know our processes and work… He is also helping the Participation Systems team in operationalizing (i.e. bug fixing) identity and access management at Mozilla (shortly known as IAM login system).</p>
<p><a href="https://discourse.mozilla.org/t/rep-of-the-month-october-2018/33256">To congratulate him, please head over to the Discourse topic!</a></p>]]>
  </description>
  <pubDate>Mon, 12 Nov 2018 12:59:59 +0000</pubDate>
  
</item>

<item>
  <title>Bhuvana Meenakshi Koteeswaran - An escape to The Square Mile #Mozfest2018</title>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://kbmtechie.wordpress.com/?p=297</guid>
  <link>https://kbmtechie.wordpress.com/2018/11/03/an-escape-to-the-square-mile-mozfest2018/</link>
  <description>
    <![CDATA[<p><strong>Dates of the event: 26,27 and 28, Oct 2018.</strong></p>
<p><strong>Venue: Ravensbourne University, London</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">My first trip overseas came true  just because of Mozilla and Mozfest2018. In first place my sincere thanks to Mozilla Foundations and Sarah Allen for helping me to make myself all way to London and for Mozfest.</p>
<p><img alt="Image from iOS(1).jpg" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-298" height="294" src="https://kbmtechie.files.wordpress.com/2018/11/image-from-ios1.jpg?w=784" width="392" /></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">I arrived at the Heathrow airport on 25th morning with my crew of Indians and we started to explore the city with our journey in the tubes. An ecstatic view of old and new buildings and with the 6 degree celsius made me remember Ooty and Kodaikanal in India. It was like me entering into a country whose replica remain similar under the name of India. So it was like a home away from home. When I was initially confused with things happening around it was so good to see the British people helping me and easing me out despite me being a stranger.</p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>

<a href="https://kbmtechie.wordpress.com/2018/11/03/an-escape-to-the-square-mile-mozfest2018/img_3238/#main"><img alt="" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail" height="113" src="https://kbmtechie.files.wordpress.com/2018/11/img_3238.jpg?w=150&amp;h=113" width="150" /></a>
<a href="https://kbmtechie.wordpress.com/2018/11/03/an-escape-to-the-square-mile-mozfest2018/img_3245/#main"><img alt="" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail" height="113" src="https://kbmtechie.files.wordpress.com/2018/11/img_3245.jpg?w=150&amp;h=113" width="150" /></a>

<p style="text-align: justify;">I stayed at Modrian London- The sea containers hotel, which was located at the banks of Thames river and the location was very busy with tourists, office workers and Mozillians. A walk along the bank of Thames was very serene and relaxing. Every morning I loved the breakfast at the hotel and the British style of starters satisfied my appetite.</p>
<p><img alt="IMG_3330" class="  wp-image-310 aligncenter" height="263" src="https://kbmtechie.files.wordpress.com/2018/11/img_3330.jpg?w=350&amp;h=263" width="350" /></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">On 26th morning I was very eager to meet all the virtual people in their physical forms. Had a few minutes of training session and met other facilitators who had come for the same purpose as me. I was thrilled to see people who were attending Mozfest for  the 3rd or 4th time consecutively and learnt a lot from their experience as a veteran. Then we moved to our spaces and I introduced myself to the team. There I saw my family, yes they are none other than the wranglers of my space, and my face beamed with excitement when I met them in person. David Bild, Mariaon, Stephanie, Yo Yehudi and Marcos were all helpful to me throughout the days of the event, they guided and appreciated me for all the efforts I paid for.<img alt="😊" class="wp-smiley" src="https://s0.wp.com/wp-content/mu-plugins/wpcom-smileys/twemoji/2/72x72/1f60a.png" style="height: 1em;" /></p>
<p><img alt="Dqmjqg6WkAAFfrl" class="  wp-image-303 aligncenter" height="236" src="https://kbmtechie.files.wordpress.com/2018/11/dqmjqg6wkaaffrl.jpg?w=315&amp;h=236" width="315" /></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">I also made a poster which was appreciated by many and I stuck it on the elevator in order to promote my session. But what I did was very minimal when compared to the posters of other sessions which were all around from washrooms to trash cans, where ever there was little space left.</p>
<p><img alt="photo_2018-11-03_13-23-21.jpg" class="  wp-image-306 aligncenter" height="241" src="https://kbmtechie.files.wordpress.com/2018/11/photo_2018-11-03_13-23-21.jpg?w=321&amp;h=241" width="321" /></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Then the big day came, it was 27th and I had to present my session on “Farmer’s Gear” under the Openness space and I was a bit tensed because my presentation was the first session of the day. Initially I did not see much participants but later I went around to call people for my session. Atlast some 7 interested folks joined me and a few left before the conclusion. Not sure if they had to rush for their own sessions or something more interesting than mine<img alt="🙈" class="wp-smiley" src="https://s0.wp.com/wp-content/mu-plugins/wpcom-smileys/twemoji/2/72x72/1f648.png" style="height: 1em;" /> . But my purpose was solved, I wanted some inputs in a diverse context and I did manage to get it. Thanks to Dirk and Zannah for helping me to organise my session plan. Although my audience were 7 in number after my session I went all over the space to know what was happening. In this way, when I met people and they asked me what session I had been doing for the weekend I got to spread a word about my project to more 20 people and they also gave me valuable feedback, so my number of participants is actually 27 . But it is not just for the number I was happy to get some volunteers who were eager enough to contribute for my project.</p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>

<a href="https://kbmtechie.wordpress.com/2018/11/03/an-escape-to-the-square-mile-mozfest2018/img_3327/#main"><img alt="" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail" height="113" src="https://kbmtechie.files.wordpress.com/2018/11/img_3327.jpg?w=150&amp;h=113" width="150" /></a>
<a href="https://kbmtechie.wordpress.com/2018/11/03/an-escape-to-the-square-mile-mozfest2018/img_3332/#main"><img alt="" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail" height="113" src="https://kbmtechie.files.wordpress.com/2018/11/img_3332.jpg?w=150&amp;h=113" width="150" /></a>

<p style="text-align: justify;">Moreover, there was another session which impressed me a lot. It was called “VR colored girls musuem” <img alt="😍" class="wp-smiley" src="https://s0.wp.com/wp-content/mu-plugins/wpcom-smileys/twemoji/2/72x72/1f60d.png" style="height: 1em;" /> and my passion towards VR and AR drove my interest to know more about it. I attended the session and was also ready to contribute for the same. It was astonishing to know that LaBrina Loving, Community Manager from Microsoft was also part of the project.</p>
<p><img alt="photo_2018-11-01_01-16-41" class="  wp-image-307 aligncenter" height="314" src="https://kbmtechie.files.wordpress.com/2018/11/photo_2018-11-01_01-16-41.jpg?w=419&amp;h=314" width="419" /></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">On 28th, I explored other spaces and was inquistive in solving the puzzles in the 7th floor.</p>
<p><img alt="Image from iOS" class="  wp-image-318 aligncenter" height="474" src="https://kbmtechie.files.wordpress.com/2018/11/image-from-ios.jpg?w=355&amp;h=474" width="355" /></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Mozfest is the right place to meet the people from Mozilla and Mozilla Reps program <img alt="❤" class="wp-smiley" src="https://s0.wp.com/wp-content/mu-plugins/wpcom-smileys/twemoji/2/72x72/2764.png" style="height: 1em;" />, which is my favorite part not just because I am a Rep but because of the sole responsibilities and other stuff I do as a part of the Mozilla Community of my region. Happy to meet Konstatina and Michael Kohler, I did clarify all my doubts and also shared my experience as a Rep with them. Also, it was great to meet Caitlin and discussed my ideas I had for Mozilla Addons and how eager I was to develop one. David Ross helped me to take a tour through the Science Fair and helped me to connect with more people. I was all about awaiting for the openings of Tech Speakers and got the right chance to meet Flaki and expressed him my crave to join the program.</p>
<p><img alt="Dqndr2VWsAULH3T" class="  wp-image-319 aligncenter" height="177" src="https://kbmtechie.files.wordpress.com/2018/11/dqndr2vwsaulh3t.jpg?w=266&amp;h=177" width="266" /></p>
<p>Also got the right chance to visit the Mozilla UK office and it was super awesome. Loved it!!! Discussed about Mozilla IoT and Firefox Mixed Reality and other trending projects.</p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>

<a href="https://kbmtechie.wordpress.com/2018/11/03/an-escape-to-the-square-mile-mozfest2018/img_3396/#main"><img alt="" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail" height="113" src="https://kbmtechie.files.wordpress.com/2018/11/img_3396.jpg?w=150&amp;h=113" width="150" /></a>
<a href="https://kbmtechie.wordpress.com/2018/11/03/an-escape-to-the-square-mile-mozfest2018/img_3394/#main"><img alt="" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail" height="113" src="https://kbmtechie.files.wordpress.com/2018/11/img_3394.jpg?w=150&amp;h=113" width="150" /></a>
<a href="https://kbmtechie.wordpress.com/2018/11/03/an-escape-to-the-square-mile-mozfest2018/photo_2018-11-01_00-35-10/#main"><img alt="" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail" height="75" src="https://kbmtechie.files.wordpress.com/2018/11/photo_2018-11-01_00-35-10.jpg?w=150&amp;h=75" width="150" /></a>

<p> </p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">The final day came, the last day of the trip and I wanted to cover some popular attractions around and my fellow Indian Mozillians accompanied me.</p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>

<a href="https://kbmtechie.wordpress.com/2018/11/03/an-escape-to-the-square-mile-mozfest2018/photo_2018-11-01_00-35-07/#main"><img alt="" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail" height="150" src="https://kbmtechie.files.wordpress.com/2018/11/photo_2018-11-01_00-35-07.jpg?w=112&amp;h=150" width="112" /></a>
<a href="https://kbmtechie.wordpress.com/2018/11/03/an-escape-to-the-square-mile-mozfest2018/img_3381/#main"><img alt="" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail" height="113" src="https://kbmtechie.files.wordpress.com/2018/11/img_3381.jpg?w=150&amp;h=113" width="150" /></a>
<a href="https://kbmtechie.wordpress.com/2018/11/03/an-escape-to-the-square-mile-mozfest2018/photo_2018-11-01_00-35-01/#main"><img alt="" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail" height="150" src="https://kbmtechie.files.wordpress.com/2018/11/photo_2018-11-01_00-35-01.jpg?w=84&amp;h=150" width="84" /></a>
<a href="https://kbmtechie.wordpress.com/2018/11/03/an-escape-to-the-square-mile-mozfest2018/photo_2018-10-31_23-13-03/#main"><img alt="" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail" height="150" src="https://kbmtechie.files.wordpress.com/2018/11/photo_2018-10-31_23-13-03.jpg?w=112&amp;h=150" width="112" /></a>

<p style="text-align: justify;">I just could not await for the next Mozfest. Truly I had so much attachment towards the place and people that I left London with drops of tears running down my eyes.</p>
<p>Mixture of emotions, thrill, connections, family, bonding and me made Mozfest2018 complete <img alt="😍" class="wp-smiley" src="https://s0.wp.com/wp-content/mu-plugins/wpcom-smileys/twemoji/2/72x72/1f60d.png" style="height: 1em;" /></p>
<div class="embed-twitter">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Completed my session successfully with great inputs from the attendees <a href="https://twitter.com/mozillareps?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@mozillareps</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/mozillaTN?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@mozillaTN</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/mozillareps?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@mozillareps</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/MozfestOpenness?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@MozfestOpenness</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/MozFest2018?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#MozFest2018</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/mozfest?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#mozfest</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Mozfest18?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#Mozfest18</a></p>
<p>— Bhuvana Meenakshi (@bhuvanakotees1) <a href="https://twitter.com/bhuvanakotees1/status/1056179869682487298?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 27, 2018</a></p></blockquote>
<p></p></div>
<div class="embed-twitter">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Along with the lady without whose help I would not have made to <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/MozFest2018?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#MozFest2018</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/sarahtallen?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@sarahtallen</a> thanks a ton <img alt="🙂" class="wp-smiley" src="https://s0.wp.com/wp-content/mu-plugins/wpcom-smileys/twemoji/2/72x72/1f642.png" style="height: 1em;" />  <a href="https://twitter.com/mozilla?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@mozilla</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/shefw?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@shefw</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/mozillareps?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@mozillareps</a> <a href="https://t.co/MRJYtqpcgN">pic.twitter.com/MRJYtqpcgN</a></p>
<p>— Bhuvana Meenakshi (@bhuvanakotees1) <a href="https://twitter.com/bhuvanakotees1/status/1058077530849079296?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 1, 2018</a></p></blockquote>
<p></p></div>]]>
  </description>
  <pubDate>Sat, 03 Nov 2018 08:31:45 +0000</pubDate>
  
</item>

<item>
  <title>Official Reps Blog - Community Coordinator role</title>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.mozilla.org/mozillareps/?p=569</guid>
  <link>https://blog.mozilla.org/mozillareps/2018/10/10/community-coordinator-role/</link>
  <description>
    <![CDATA[<p>The Reps program is evolving in order to be aligned with Mozilla’s changes on how we perceive communities. Part of those changes is the Mission Driven Mozillians project, where the Reps are involved.</p>
<p>We (the Reps Council) believe that the Reps program has a natural place inside this project because of the experience, skills and knowledge on leading, growing and helping communities on their daily life.</p>
<p>Based on  the <a href="https://discourse.mozilla.org/t/what-s-next-for-volunteer-leadership-in-2018-shared-agreements/25091">work that has been done in the Mission Driven Mozillians project</a> (video: <a href="https://discourse.mozilla.org/t/a-quick-video-intro-to-mission-driven-mozillians/25912">https://discourse.mozilla.org/t/a-quick-video-intro-to-mission-driven-mozillians/25912</a>), two types of volunteer leadership have been identified:</p>
<ol>
<li>Volunteers who have been identified inside the community as experts based on their knowledge and skills on a specific functional area – <b><i>functional area experts</i></b></li>
<li>Volunteers who have been identified as experts based on their ability to coordinate, support and expand communities  – <b><i>community coordinators.</i></b></li>
</ol>
<p>For the first category, functional areas are able to easily identify the right fit for the position based on different knowledge criterias and years of experience in the project. However, for the second category there is not a well defined role nor a set of guidelines for volunteers that were interested in community building. As a result, historically, people from the first category took over the community coordinator roles without necessarily being properly trained for it.</p>
<p>For that reason, the Reps Council has worked on a definition of the community coordinator role, since we believe that the Reps are a natural fit for this role.</p>
<p><b>Suggested definition of community coordinator role:</b></p>
<p>Community coordinator volunteers are a<i>ligned and committed Mozillians who are interested in:</i></p>
<ol>
<li><i>finding and connecting new talent with Mozilla projects they are contributing to</i></li>
<li><i>developing communities on a functional and/or local level</i></li>
<li><i>supporting local communities and Mozilla to </i>have an effective and decentralized environment for contribution</li>
<li><i>creating collaborations with other local communities in an effort to spread Mozilla’s mission and expand Mozilla’s outreach in the open source ecosystem</i></li>
</ol>
<p> </p>
<p>In order to be able to describe the responsibilities of the role more, we have specified how the role is going to look like based on <a href="https://discourse.mozilla.org/t/what-s-next-for-volunteer-leadership-in-2018-shared-agreements/25091">the agreements the Mission Driven Mozillians group has crafted</a>.</p>
<h2></h2>
<h2>Where people hold coordinating roles, they should be reviewed regularly</h2>
<ul>
<li>This creates opportunities for new, diverse leaders to emerge.</li>
<li>Ensures continuous support from the communities they serve.</li>
<li>Prevents toxic individuals from maintaining power indefinitely.</li>
<li>Allows space for individuals to receive feedback and support to better thrive in their role.</li>
</ul>
<p><b><i>What does that mean for Community Experts?</i></b></p>
<ul>
<li>All Community experts and any volunteers that hold roles within this group have fixed terms and are reviewed regularly. Established processes will help contributors give feedback and review these roles.</li>
</ul>
<h2></h2>
<h2>Responsibilities should be clearly communicated and distributed</h2>
<ul>
<li>Creates more opportunities for more people.</li>
<li>Avoids gatekeeping and power accumulation.</li>
<li>Reduces burnout and over reliance on an individual by sharing accountability.</li>
<li>Creates leadership pathways for new people.</li>
<li>Potentially increases diversity.</li>
<li>An emphasis on responsibility over title avoids unnecessary “authority labels”.</li>
</ul>
<p><b><i>What does that mean for the Community Experts?</i></b></p>
<ul>
<li>All Community experts have public role descriptions that articulate clearly their responsibilities and have a culture of delegating them when needed across their co-volunteers.</li>
</ul>
<h2></h2>
<h2>When people are in a coordinating role, they should abide by standards, and be accountable for fulfilling their responsibilities</h2>
<ul>
<li>This builds confidence and support for individuals and these roles from community members and staff.</li>
<li>Ensures that everyone has shared clarity on expectations and success.</li>
<li>Creates an environment where the CPG is applied consistently.</li>
<li>Increases the consistency in roles across the organization .</li>
</ul>
<p><b><i>What does that mean for the Community Experts?</i></b></p>
<ul>
<li>All Community experts should keep their activities public and visible to everyone and they are accountable to fulfill their responsibilities</li>
</ul>
<h2></h2>
<h2>People in coordinating roles should follow and model Mozilla’s diversity &amp; inclusion values</h2>
<p> </p>
<ul>
<li>Creates a culture of inclusion that invites participation from new voices.</li>
<li>Encourages the inclusion of diverse voices and groups.</li>
<li>Creates an environment where the CPG is applied consistently.</li>
<li>Enables leadership pathways that explicitly consider inclusion dimensions.</li>
</ul>
<p><b><i>What does that mean for the Community Experts?</i></b></p>
<ul>
<li>The Community experts group has processes that are optimized to be welcoming to diverse audiences, ensures that all community building activities across the organization roles are available for everyone, and has communication channels that are properly used and are accessible for everyone. All Community experts are trained on the  CPG before joining and are confident to flag any lack of accountability and/or violations of the CPG.</li>
</ul>
<h2></h2>
<h2>People with coordinating roles should be supported and recognized in a set of standard ways across Mozilla</h2>
<p> </p>
<ul>
<li>Enables people to have equal access to training and growth opportunities regardless of what part of the organisation they contribute to.</li>
<li>Allows people to follow their passions/skills instead of just contribute for rewards.</li>
<li>Roles have clear definitions and avoid labels that create authority feeling</li>
<li>We get shared understandings of the kind of responsibilities that exist</li>
</ul>
<p><b><i>What does that mean for the Community Experts?</i></b></p>
<ul>
<li>This means that we recognize all community building activities across the organization equally, support and also provide training for skills improvement on community building and self development.</li>
</ul>
<p> </p>
<p>These are the agreements that the Reps Council is suggesting and we need your feedback!</p>
<p>All Reps should agree because of their role as a community coordinators in their communities, let us know what you think on <a href="https://discourse.mozilla.org/t/community-coordinator-role-is-here/32485">Discourse</a>!</p>
<p><em>This blogpost is part of the work that the <a href="https://reps.mozilla.org/people/#/view/grid/group/council/">Reps Council</a> and <a href="https://reps.mozilla.org/people/#/view/grid/group/peers/">Reps Peers</a> has been doing for the last quarter. The blogpost as been authored by <a href="https://reps.mozilla.org/u/Mte90/">Daniele Scasciafratte</a></em></p>]]>
  </description>
  <pubDate>Wed, 10 Oct 2018 12:56:48 +0000</pubDate>
  
</item>

<item>
  <title>Md Shahbaz Alam - VR and AR on the Web @ Cognizance 2018</title>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alamshahbaz.wordpress.com/?p=1102</guid>
  <link>https://alamshahbaz.wordpress.com/2018/10/04/vr-and-ar-on-the-web-cognizance-2018/</link>
  <description>
    <![CDATA[<p>Mozilla India’s first collaboration with Cognizance 2k18. Spreading the Mozilla mission in Changa. Also spreading awareness for online privacy, MozActivate campaign. Amongst students from all over Gujarat, in the technical fest hosted by CHARUSAT, Changa. This will be the 1st year when Mozilla India will be present at Cognizance or Changa.</p>
<p>Reps Event Page: <a href="https://reps.mozilla.org/e/cognizance-2018/" rel="nofollow">https://reps.mozilla.org/e/cognizance-2018/</a></p>
<p>The event started with the formal introduction of the speakers, <a href="https://mozillians.org/en-US/u/pransh15/" rel="noopener">Pranshu Khanna</a> and<a href="https://reps.mozilla.org/u/shahbaz/" rel="noopener"> Md. Shahbaz Alam</a></p>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en"><a href="https://twitter.com/mdsbzalam?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@mdsbzalam</a> started VR/AR workshop at CHARUSAT , Changa<a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/MozVR?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#MozVR</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/MozActivate?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#MozActivate</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/aframevr?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@aframevr</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/mozillavr?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@mozillavr</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/andgokevin?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@andgokevin</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/MozillaIN?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@mozillaIN</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/mozillareps?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@mozillareps</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Cognizance18?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#Cognizance18</a> <a href="https://t.co/0mP4m67oLq">pic.twitter.com/0mP4m67oLq</a></p>
<p>— Sahilbatham26 (@sahilbatham26) <a href="https://twitter.com/sahilbatham26/status/1042667808604053505?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 20, 2018</a></p></blockquote>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Introduction to AR/VR by <a href="https://twitter.com/mdsbzalam?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@mdsbzalam</a> at CHARUSAT, Changa<a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/MozVR?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#MozVR</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/MozActivate?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#MozActivate</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/aframevr?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@aframevr</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/andgokevin?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@andgokevin</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/MozillaIN?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@mozillaIN</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/mozillareps?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@mozillareps</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Cognizance18?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#Cognizance18</a> <a href="https://t.co/0mP4m67oLq">pic.twitter.com/0mP4m67oLq</a> <a href="https://t.co/e59ZX2Je8R">pic.twitter.com/e59ZX2Je8R</a></p>
<p>— Sahilbatham26 (@sahilbatham26) <a href="https://twitter.com/sahilbatham26/status/1042672894948466689?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 20, 2018</a></p></blockquote>
<p>Event pics: <a href="https://photos.app.goo.gl/g68YGybpsALyJyCH9" rel="nofollow">https://photos.app.goo.gl/g68YGybpsALyJyCH9</a></p>

<a href="https://alamshahbaz.wordpress.com/2018/10/04/vr-and-ar-on-the-web-cognizance-2018/img_20180627_101301-2/"><img alt="" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail" height="113" src="https://alamshahbaz.files.wordpress.com/2018/10/img_20180627_101301.jpg?w=150&amp;h=113" width="150" /></a>
<a href="https://alamshahbaz.wordpress.com/2018/10/04/vr-and-ar-on-the-web-cognizance-2018/20180920_121647/"><img alt="" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail" height="150" src="https://alamshahbaz.files.wordpress.com/2018/10/20180920_121647.jpg?w=113&amp;h=150" width="113" /></a>
<a href="https://alamshahbaz.wordpress.com/2018/10/04/vr-and-ar-on-the-web-cognizance-2018/20180920_121144_capture/"><img alt="" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail" height="150" src="https://alamshahbaz.files.wordpress.com/2018/10/20180920_121144_capture.jpg?w=113&amp;h=150" width="113" /></a>
<a href="https://alamshahbaz.wordpress.com/2018/10/04/vr-and-ar-on-the-web-cognizance-2018/20180921_111739/"><img alt="" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail" height="150" src="https://alamshahbaz.files.wordpress.com/2018/10/20180921_111739.jpg?w=113&amp;h=150" width="113" /></a>
<a href="https://alamshahbaz.wordpress.com/2018/10/04/vr-and-ar-on-the-web-cognizance-2018/20180921_122751/"><img alt="" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail" height="113" src="https://alamshahbaz.files.wordpress.com/2018/10/20180921_122751.jpg?w=150&amp;h=113" width="150" /></a>

<p>We were fortunate to have good volunteers with us, who helped as managing this event Pratik, Sumed and Shivam.</p>

<a href="https://alamshahbaz.wordpress.com/2018/10/04/vr-and-ar-on-the-web-cognizance-2018/20180920_150727/"><img alt="" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail" height="113" src="https://alamshahbaz.files.wordpress.com/2018/10/20180920_150727.jpg?w=150&amp;h=113" width="150" /></a>
<a href="https://alamshahbaz.wordpress.com/2018/10/04/vr-and-ar-on-the-web-cognizance-2018/20180920_150746/"><img alt="" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail" height="150" src="https://alamshahbaz.files.wordpress.com/2018/10/20180920_150746.jpg?w=113&amp;h=150" width="113" /></a>
<a href="https://alamshahbaz.wordpress.com/2018/10/04/vr-and-ar-on-the-web-cognizance-2018/20180920_150752/"><img alt="" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail" height="113" src="https://alamshahbaz.files.wordpress.com/2018/10/20180920_150752.jpg?w=150&amp;h=113" width="150" /></a>
<a href="https://alamshahbaz.wordpress.com/2018/10/04/vr-and-ar-on-the-web-cognizance-2018/20180920_153756/"><img alt="" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail" height="113" src="https://alamshahbaz.files.wordpress.com/2018/10/20180920_153756.jpg?w=150&amp;h=113" width="150" /></a>
<a href="https://alamshahbaz.wordpress.com/2018/10/04/vr-and-ar-on-the-web-cognizance-2018/20180920_153816/"><img alt="" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail" height="113" src="https://alamshahbaz.files.wordpress.com/2018/10/20180920_153816.jpg?w=150&amp;h=113" width="150" /></a>

<p>Volunteers helping participants with their scenes.</p>

<a href="https://alamshahbaz.wordpress.com/2018/10/04/vr-and-ar-on-the-web-cognizance-2018/20180921_153359/"><img alt="" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail" height="113" src="https://alamshahbaz.files.wordpress.com/2018/10/20180921_153359.jpg?w=150&amp;h=113" width="150" /></a>
<a href="https://alamshahbaz.wordpress.com/2018/10/04/vr-and-ar-on-the-web-cognizance-2018/img_20180921_155136/"><img alt="" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail" height="113" src="https://alamshahbaz.files.wordpress.com/2018/10/img_20180921_155136.jpg?w=150&amp;h=113" width="150" /></a>
<a href="https://alamshahbaz.wordpress.com/2018/10/04/vr-and-ar-on-the-web-cognizance-2018/20180921_162122/"><img alt="" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail" height="113" src="https://alamshahbaz.files.wordpress.com/2018/10/20180921_162122.jpg?w=150&amp;h=113" width="150" /></a>
<a href="https://alamshahbaz.wordpress.com/2018/10/04/vr-and-ar-on-the-web-cognizance-2018/20180921_114446/"><img alt="" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail" height="113" src="https://alamshahbaz.files.wordpress.com/2018/10/20180921_114446.jpg?w=150&amp;h=113" width="150" /></a>
<a href="https://alamshahbaz.wordpress.com/2018/10/04/vr-and-ar-on-the-web-cognizance-2018/20180921_114419/"><img alt="" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail" height="113" src="https://alamshahbaz.files.wordpress.com/2018/10/20180921_114419.jpg?w=150&amp;h=113" width="150" /></a>

<p>Sharing the best pratices with the students and prize distribution.</p>
<p> </p>
<div class="wp-caption alignnone" id="attachment_1106" style="width: 1228px;"><img alt="IMG_20180921_150009" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1106" src="https://alamshahbaz.files.wordpress.com/2018/10/img_20180921_150009.jpg?w=788" /><p class="wp-caption-text" id="caption-attachment-1106">Dedication shown by the participants.</p></div>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">This is dedication.</p>
<p>They want to learn code, even if they don’t have laptop with them.<a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/WebVR?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#WebVR</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/aframevr?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@aframevr</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/mozillareps?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@mozillareps</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/pransh15?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@pransh15</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/MozillaIN?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@MozillaIN</a> <a href="https://t.co/qD9p3ZxxJw">pic.twitter.com/qD9p3ZxxJw</a></p>
<p>— Md Shahbaz Alam (@mdsbzalam) <a href="https://twitter.com/mdsbzalam/status/1043081813764141056?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 21, 2018</a></p></blockquote>
<p> </p>
<div class="wp-caption alignnone" id="attachment_1112" style="width: 1344px;"><img alt="20180920_163316" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1112" src="https://alamshahbaz.files.wordpress.com/2018/10/20180920_163316.jpg?w=788" /><p class="wp-caption-text" id="caption-attachment-1112">Our Team</p></div>
<p> </p>]]>
  </description>
  <pubDate>Thu, 04 Oct 2018 17:14:23 +0000</pubDate>
  
</item>

<item>
  <title>Official Reps Blog - Rep of the Month – September 2018</title>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.mozilla.org/mozillareps/?p=567</guid>
  <link>https://blog.mozilla.org/mozillareps/2018/10/04/rep-of-the-month-september-2018/</link>
  <description>
    <![CDATA[<div class="cooked">
<p>Please join us in congratulating <a href="https://reps.mozilla.org/u/umesh/" rel="nofollow noopener">Umesh Agarwal</a>, our Rep of the Month for September 2018!</p>
<p>Umesh is from Kharagpur, India and works as Big Data Splunk Architect &amp; Administrator. He is an Open Source Geek and his other areas of interest are Cyber Security and Big Data Analysis. He is a passionate Mozillian and an amazing contributor for more than 6 years. Umesh served as Reps Council Member in 2016 and currently he is an active Reps Mentor.</p>
<div class="lightbox-wrapper">
<p><a class="lightbox" href="https://discourse-paas-production-content.s3.dualstack.us-east-1.amazonaws.com/original/3X/a/0/a0c07f62cf697d85e72d33389edfdd20386448cc.jpeg" rel="nofollow noopener" title="f43c076687039f667a686107d865fea1.jpg"><img alt="f43c076687039f667a686107d865fea1" height="500" src="https://discourse-paas-production-content.s3.dualstack.us-east-1.amazonaws.com/original/3X/a/0/a0c07f62cf697d85e72d33389edfdd20386448cc.jpeg" width="500" /></a></p>
<div class="meta"><span class="informations"> </span></div>
</div>
<p>He manages the Mozilla India Gear Store based in Pune, India. Umesh is a localization community manager for the Hindi language. He has recently successfully hosted <a href="https://wiki.mozilla.org/India/Mozilla_Hindi_Marathi_Gujarati_Community_Meet-up_2018" rel="nofollow noopener">‘Mozilla L10n Hindi, Marathi, Gujrati Community Meetup 2018’</a> held in Pune on 1st – 2nd of September 2018. This event was part of the Mozilla L10n community events in 2018. The event was of very high standard, productive and ended up with great success metrics. Approximately twenty leaders of four regional languages traveled from various parts of the country to participate in the event.</p>
<p>Thanks Umesh, keep rocking the Open Web! <img alt=":tada:" class="emoji" src="https://discourse.mozilla.org/images/emoji/twitter/tada.png?v=6" title=":tada:" /> <img alt=":tada:" class="emoji" src="https://discourse.mozilla.org/images/emoji/twitter/tada.png?v=6" title=":tada:" /></p>
<p><a href="https://discourse.mozilla.org/t/rep-of-the-month-september-2018/32197">To congratulate him, please head over to the Discourse topic!</a></p>
</div>]]>
  </description>
  <pubDate>Thu, 04 Oct 2018 15:58:24 +0000</pubDate>
  
</item>

<item>
  <title>Mehul Patel - DevConfIN 2018</title>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.rowdymehul.com/?p=1634</guid>
  <link>http://www.rowdymehul.com/events/devconfin-2018/</link>
  <description>
    <![CDATA[<p><strong>DevConf.in 2018</strong> is the second annual Developers’ Conference to be organized by Red Hat in Bengaluru, India. It is meant to provide a platform to the local FOSS community participants to come together and engage in the knowledge sharing through technical talks, workshops, panel discussions, hackathon, and such activities.</p>
<p>More about my talk and conference can be found <a href="https://github.com/rowdymehul/devconfIN">here</a>;</p>
<p>Our goal is to promote and educate people about authentication &amp; authorization. Also, learn about the different concepts JS and how that make up an application secure.</p>
<p>As usual this time also, at end moment I’ve decided to attend this conference and since this conference is organized by <strong>Red Hat</strong> so I was quite excited to speak here. <strong>DevConf</strong> first time happening in India. This conference originally started on <strong>10 September 2009</strong>, this was the first ever conference organized by <strong>Red Hat Czech Republic</strong> in the <strong>Czech Republic</strong> and the rest is history.<span id="more-1634"></span></p>
<p>Due to flight delayed I reached the hotel late at night and was too tired but there some points left to add in the presentation. I was actually preparing some demos which I wanted to demonstrate to participants. Even after so much tired the energy level was same, thanks to Red Bull as well to keep me awake. <img alt="😀" class="wp-smiley" src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/12.0.0-1/72x72/1f600.png" style="height: 1em;" /></p>
<figure class="wp-caption aligncenter" id="attachment_1635" style="width: 1536px;"><a href="https://i1.wp.com/www.rowdymehul.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/DiBMjZoWsAY3ZNq.jpglarge.jpeg"><img alt="" class="wp-image-1635 size-full" height="1067" src="https://i1.wp.com/www.rowdymehul.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/DiBMjZoWsAY3ZNq.jpglarge.jpeg?resize=800%2C1067" width="800" /></a>Picture Credits: Viral Parmar</figure>
<p>I have talked on “<strong>JS Authentication with Auth0</strong>“. This was introductory talk about the JS Authentication, where we have discussed the role that Auth0 authentication plays in modern software development where it is a lot more than just the login screen.</p>
<div class="fitvids-video">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Speaking today at <a href="https://twitter.com/devconf_in?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@devconf_in</a> on JS authentication with <a href="https://twitter.com/auth0?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@auth0</a> . Seesion will be held in Room No 5, Christ University. </p>
<p>Looking forward to address amazing audience <img alt="😎" class="wp-smiley" src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/12.0.0-1/72x72/1f60e.png" style="height: 1em;" /> <a href="https://twitter.com/Auth0Ambassador?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@Auth0Ambassador</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/Auth0Community?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@Auth0Community</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/authentication?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#authentication</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Identity?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#Identity</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Security?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#Security</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/devconf18?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#devconf18</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/devconf?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#devconf</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/RedHat?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@RedHat</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/redhatopen?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@redhatopen</a> <a href="https://t.co/7H2REmaAuR">pic.twitter.com/7H2REmaAuR</a></p>
<p>— Mehul Patel (@rowdymehul) <a href="https://twitter.com/rowdymehul/status/1025609899571662849?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 4, 2018</a></p></blockquote>
<p></p></div>
<p>First, we gave a bit of background that Authentication and Authorization are two different processes. This time Viral Parmar who is a cybersecurity expert in his region join me for this session and shared some great trips to about online security.</p>
<p>I ’ve already discovered <a href="https://auth0.com">Auth0</a>, an Authentication as a Service. Using their JavaScript SDK you can able to offer social logins using Github, Facebook and much more from the web interface. At the time of writing it’s free for up to 7000 registered users and they offer a nice web interface to manage all users who signed up / logged in. More you can explore from <a href="https://auth0.com/opensource">here</a>;</p>
<h3>We have also covered the following points in the talk;</h3>
<ul>
<li>web security <span class="module__title__link">Vulnerabilities</span></li>
<li>Passwordless authentication</li>
<li>SSO</li>
<li>How to use <a href="https://auth0.com/opensource">Auth0</a> as authentication</li>
<li>Brute force <span class="module__title__link">attack</span></li>
</ul>
<p>At the end of the talk, we have received so many questions but mostly on <strong>SSO</strong> as participants are quite curious to know more about. Some were working professionals and there were asking about how they implement <strong>SSO</strong> on their business set up so all an all it was quite a healthy discussion. Some questions we have answered them after wrap up and over a cup of coffee in break session.</p>
<p>Also, while walking to booth sections got a chance to interact with many participants from the conference, some were known faces who attended our talk and some came up with new questions. This is the best part of being in the community where you will get a chance to exchange your knowledge and you always go back home with some new learning or experience.</p>
<div class="fitvids-video">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">After successful hosting of sessions in <a href="https://twitter.com/mozilla?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@mozilla</a> booth <a href="https://twitter.com/devconf_in?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@devconf_in</a> . The victory posture with <a href="https://twitter.com/iamVP7?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@iamVP7</a> and <a href="https://twitter.com/rowdymehul?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@rowdymehul</a> ! <a href="https://twitter.com/mozillareality?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@mozillareality</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/mozillareps?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@mozillareps</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/MozillaIN?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@MozillaIN</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/mozillaTN?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@mozillaTN</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/DevConf_in?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#DevConf_in</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/definefuture?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#definefuture</a> <a href="https://t.co/ZHbHJlIhNV">pic.twitter.com/ZHbHJlIhNV</a></p>
<p>— Bhuvana Meenakshi (@bhuvanakotees1) <a href="https://twitter.com/bhuvanakotees1/status/1027106057544323072?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 8, 2018</a></p></blockquote>
<p></p></div>
<p>In my every event I am always seeking for feedback’s from participants/attendees/visitors, doesn’t matter its positive or negative because if you know the feedback you can definitely work on it to improve for next time to make it better.</p>
<h4>Selfie with amazing open source peers.<img alt="😎" class="wp-smiley" src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/12.0.0-1/72x72/1f60e.png" style="height: 1em;" /></h4>
<h4><a href="https://i2.wp.com/www.rowdymehul.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/IMG_grrn2k.jpg"><img alt="" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1637" height="450" src="https://i2.wp.com/www.rowdymehul.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/IMG_grrn2k.jpg?resize=800%2C450" width="800" /></a>There is one of a favorite quote I would like mentioned here;</h4>
<blockquote>
<div>“<em>A conference is a gathering of people who singly can do nothing, but together can decide that nothing can be done.</em>”   – Fred Allen</div>
</blockquote>
<div></div>
<div></div>
<div>
<figure class="wp-caption aligncenter" id="attachment_1641" style="width: 4608px;"><a href="https://i1.wp.com/www.rowdymehul.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/IMG_20180805_160424.jpg"><img alt="" class="wp-image-1641 size-full" height="600" src="https://i1.wp.com/www.rowdymehul.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/IMG_20180805_160424.jpg?resize=800%2C600" width="800" /></a><strong>                                             Awesome people. <img alt="😍" class="wp-smiley" src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/12.0.0-1/72x72/1f60d.png" style="height: 1em;" /></strong></figure>
<h5 style="text-align: center;"><em><strong>Hope you enjoyed my blog! <img alt="🙂" class="wp-smiley" src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/12.0.0-1/72x72/1f642.png" style="height: 1em;" /></strong></em></h5>
</div>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>]]>
  </description>
  <pubDate>Fri, 14 Sep 2018 22:27:02 +0000</pubDate>
  
</item>

<item>
  <title>Bhuvana Meenakshi Koteeswaran - A day admist techie geeks #Devconf2018</title>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://kbmtechie.wordpress.com/?p=173</guid>
  <link>https://kbmtechie.wordpress.com/2018/09/09/a-day-admist-techie-geeks-devconf2018/</link>
  <description>
    <![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;"><img alt="42365695750_6352ba91be_z" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-178" src="https://kbmtechie.files.wordpress.com/2018/09/42365695750_6352ba91be_z.jpg?w=620" /></p>
<p><strong>Dates of the event: 04 &amp; 05, August, 2018</strong></p>
<p><strong>Venue : Christ University, Bangalore, India.</strong></p>
<p> </p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">This is the first conference as a speaker I attended and it turned out to be a great event with huge bunch of people interested in tech and only tech (I like this kind of community basically). The whole space around me was filled with chit-chats on technology, discussions about programming and fresh Open Source ideas. The decorum was well maintained with debates and discussions in workshops and speaker sessions, ultimately a lot of ideas shared. So, all  this can happen only in this interesting arena called “Devconf”.</p>
<p><img alt="DSC_0197" class="aligncenter  wp-image-212" height="354" src="https://kbmtechie.files.wordpress.com/2018/09/dsc_0197.jpg?w=199&amp;h=354" width="199" /></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Devconf 2018- India, is the second annual meetup organised by Redhat and one of the massive events for all the like minded tech savvy people under one roof. It was a 2-day conference and the first day the intensity of the summit was elevated with the keynote session by Ric Wheeler on his journey in Open Source. I went around for other talks and also was part of the Mozilla Booth where my contributions on WebVR were displayed.</p>

<a href="https://kbmtechie.wordpress.com/2018/09/09/a-day-admist-techie-geeks-devconf2018/dsc_0200/#main"><img alt="" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail" height="150" src="https://kbmtechie.files.wordpress.com/2018/09/dsc_0200.jpg?w=84&amp;h=150" width="84" /></a>
<a href="https://kbmtechie.wordpress.com/2018/09/09/a-day-admist-techie-geeks-devconf2018/44125734082_4d50f310b2_z/#main"><img alt="" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail" height="100" src="https://kbmtechie.files.wordpress.com/2018/09/44125734082_4d50f310b2_z.jpg?w=150&amp;h=100" width="150" /></a>

<p style="text-align: justify;">In the evening the most awaited part happened, I delivered my talk under the title : “Behind the screen: WebXR revealed”. It was very interesting to have assorted age group people and they were interested to learn more about what is Virtual/Augmented/ Mixed Reality. I demonstrated a few samples on how I used A-frame to create different VR/AR scenes. The best part is I had many people who spoke with me after the talk and how they very curious to go about this. Happened to meet much experienced audience from giant industries too and they discussed with me on how this technology can be of great help to improve their organisations.</p>

<a href="https://kbmtechie.wordpress.com/2018/09/09/a-day-admist-techie-geeks-devconf2018/43454957584_18e932b316_z/#main"><img alt="" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail" height="100" src="https://kbmtechie.files.wordpress.com/2018/09/43454957584_18e932b316_z.jpg?w=150&amp;h=100" width="150" /></a>
<a href="https://kbmtechie.wordpress.com/2018/09/09/a-day-admist-techie-geeks-devconf2018/43454959754_86ab074da4_z/#main"><img alt="" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail" height="100" src="https://kbmtechie.files.wordpress.com/2018/09/43454959754_86ab074da4_z.jpg?w=150&amp;h=100" width="150" /></a>
<a href="https://kbmtechie.wordpress.com/2018/09/09/a-day-admist-techie-geeks-devconf2018/dsc_0178/#main"><img alt="" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail" height="84" src="https://kbmtechie.files.wordpress.com/2018/09/dsc_0178.jpg?w=150&amp;h=84" width="150" /></a>

<p style="text-align: justify;">The second day was kick started with the keynote session by Christian Heimes, who spoke on security and efficient encryption techniques. I was fortunate to meet him in person on his visit to the Booth area and explained about the products we worked on. Definitely, he’s a man of good humane and is constantly in touch with me and eager enough to know more about my interest on AR/VR.</p>

<a href="https://kbmtechie.wordpress.com/2018/09/09/a-day-admist-techie-geeks-devconf2018/photo_2018-09-05_12-32-55/#main"><img alt="" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail" height="150" src="https://kbmtechie.files.wordpress.com/2018/09/photo_2018-09-05_12-32-55.jpg?w=113&amp;h=150" width="113" /></a>
<a href="https://kbmtechie.wordpress.com/2018/09/09/a-day-admist-techie-geeks-devconf2018/photo_2018-09-05_12-32-47/#main"><img alt="" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail" height="150" src="https://kbmtechie.files.wordpress.com/2018/09/photo_2018-09-05_12-32-47.jpg?w=113&amp;h=150" width="113" /></a>

<p style="text-align: justify;">These two days I enjoyed as it was like more of a carnival and this was a great opportunity to meet a lot of my fellow Mozillians. A lot of whom I was contacting virtually so I little struggled to recognise them <img alt="😛" class="wp-smiley" src="https://s0.wp.com/wp-content/mu-plugins/wpcom-smileys/twemoji/2/72x72/1f61b.png" style="height: 1em;" />   However, the multifacet community I had ever seen and always vibrant , so very proud a Mozillian.</p>

<a href="https://kbmtechie.wordpress.com/2018/09/09/a-day-admist-techie-geeks-devconf2018/photo_2018-08-07_23-54-59/#main"><img alt="" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail" height="112" src="https://kbmtechie.files.wordpress.com/2018/09/photo_2018-08-07_23-54-59.jpg?w=150&amp;h=112" width="150" /></a>
<a href="https://kbmtechie.wordpress.com/2018/09/09/a-day-admist-techie-geeks-devconf2018/photo_2018-09-09_13-42-01/#main"><img alt="" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail" height="84" src="https://kbmtechie.files.wordpress.com/2018/09/photo_2018-09-09_13-42-01.jpg?w=150&amp;h=84" width="150" /></a>
<a href="https://kbmtechie.wordpress.com/2018/09/09/a-day-admist-techie-geeks-devconf2018/photo_2018-08-07_23-54-19/#main"><img alt="" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail" height="150" src="https://kbmtechie.files.wordpress.com/2018/09/photo_2018-08-07_23-54-19.jpg?w=113&amp;h=150" width="113" /></a>

<p style="text-align: justify;">Thanks Devconf for giving me this opportunity and also I loved all the photography booths, they make me look like a popstar indeed <img alt="😛" class="wp-smiley" src="https://s0.wp.com/wp-content/mu-plugins/wpcom-smileys/twemoji/2/72x72/1f61b.png" style="height: 1em;" /></p>
<p><img alt="photo_2018-09-05_12-33-18" class="  wp-image-232 aligncenter" height="304" src="https://kbmtechie.files.wordpress.com/2018/09/photo_2018-09-05_12-33-18.jpg?w=228&amp;h=304" width="228" /></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Also the Twitter wall, I stood beside it often to check if my tweets came up there <img alt="😉" class="wp-smiley" src="https://s0.wp.com/wp-content/mu-plugins/wpcom-smileys/twemoji/2/72x72/1f609.png" style="height: 1em;" /></p>
<div class="embed-twitter">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Rockstar girls who <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/definefuture?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#definefuture</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/priynag?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@priynag</a> and <a href="https://twitter.com/bhuvanakotees1?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@bhuvanakotees1</a> from <a href="https://twitter.com/MozillaIN?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@MozillaIN</a>  at <a href="https://twitter.com/devconf_in?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@devconf_in</a> <a href="https://t.co/pfxzfUa3NL">pic.twitter.com/pfxzfUa3NL</a></p>
<p>— Mozilla TamilNadu (@mozillaTN) <a href="https://twitter.com/mozillaTN/status/1026048370391973888?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 5, 2018</a></p></blockquote>
<p></p></div>
<p style="text-align: justify;">All in all, Devconf is the colloquium where one can share, debate, invent and discover new ideas.</p>
<p>Kudos to the team and I loved the swags!</p>
<p><img alt="photo_2018-09-05_12-33-24" class="  wp-image-233 aligncenter" height="347" src="https://kbmtechie.files.wordpress.com/2018/09/photo_2018-09-05_12-33-24.jpg?w=463&amp;h=347" width="463" /></p>]]>
  </description>
  <pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 08:19:07 +0000</pubDate>
  
</item>

<item>
  <title>Official Reps Blog - Rep of the Month – August 2018</title>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.mozilla.org/mozillareps/?p=565</guid>
  <link>https://blog.mozilla.org/mozillareps/2018/08/27/rep-of-the-month-august-2018/</link>
  <description>
    <![CDATA[<div class="cooked">
<p>Please join us in congratulating <a href="https://reps.mozilla.org/u/abhi12ravi/" rel="nofollow noopener">Abhiram Ravikumar</a>, our Rep of the Month for August 2018!</p>
<p>Abhiram Ravikumar is an amazing contributor from Bangalore India and a long time Mozillian contributing as a Rep since November 2015. He is the so-called backbone of the Bangalore community keeping activities going in and around the region.</p>
<div class="lightbox-wrapper"><a class="lightbox" href="https://discourse-paas-production-content.s3.dualstack.us-east-1.amazonaws.com/original/3X/7/6/7695c9e870909070e24b6d373d39daa169ff61ae.jpeg" rel="nofollow noopener" title="www.libravatar.org.jpg"><img alt="org" height="500" src="https://discourse-paas-production-content.s3.dualstack.us-east-1.amazonaws.com/optimized/3X/7/6/7695c9e870909070e24b6d373d39daa169ff61ae_1_500x500.jpeg" width="500" /></a><p></p>
<div class="meta"><span class="informations"> </span></div>
</div>
<p>He is also a Rust contributor helping the Rust team evangelize the programming language by speaking at events and organizing them. As a Tech Speaker, he speaks about Rust, Blockchain, Machine Learning, Git and Open Source at events and conferences.</p>
<p>Abhiram is a part of the Mozilla India Rust focus group helping volunteers getting started with Rust. Professionally he works as a machine learning fellow at SAP Labs. A great example of contributions with passion towards open source, Abhiram surely stands out with his contributions to the community.</p>
<p>Thanks Abhiram, keep rocking the Open Web! <img alt=":tada:" class="emoji" src="https://discourse.mozilla.org/images/emoji/twitter/tada.png?v=6" title=":tada:" /> <img alt=":tada:" class="emoji" src="https://discourse.mozilla.org/images/emoji/twitter/tada.png?v=6" title=":tada:" /></p>
<p><a href="https://discourse.mozilla.org/t/rep-of-the-month-august-2018/31269">To congratulate him, head over to the Discourse post!</a></p>
</div>]]>
  </description>
  <pubDate>Mon, 27 Aug 2018 13:51:38 +0000</pubDate>
  
</item>

<item>
  <title>Viswaprasath KS - Devconf India 2018</title>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://vp7techie.wordpress.com/?p=872</guid>
  <link>https://vp7techie.wordpress.com/2018/08/11/devconf-india-2018/</link>
  <description>
    <![CDATA[<blockquote><p><a href="https://devconf.info/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">DevConf</a> Contributor Conferences are technology conference events for Linux and JBoss Developers, Admins, Linux and other open source project contributors, organized by Red Hat. This is the 2nd time happening at India, it was one of the amazing open source event I attended recently.</p></blockquote>
<p>Two months back CFP was released, as soon as I came to know about it applied for Mozilla Community booth, personally there was call from inside to apply for this meetup. We were very lucky our Mozilla community got opportunity to present various contribution areas at devconf, which is mostly dedicated to developers. And Priyanka shared about this in Mozilla India community mailing list.</p>
<p>This time MozillaIN community had Amazing booth where our focus is to share about <a href="https://aframe.io/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Aframe</a> , <a href="https://www.rust-lang.org/en-US/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Rust Language</a> , <a href="https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Mozilla/Add-ons/WebExtensions" rel="noopener" target="_blank">WebExtension</a></p>
<p><img alt="photo5990091300780748150" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-873" src="https://vp7techie.files.wordpress.com/2018/08/photo5990091300780748150.jpg?w=1140" /></p>
<p>Before Meetup, one of the first task is to bring design for Booth, our theme was based on Rust, Firefox Family (&amp; Webextesion), Aframe, we gave this requirements to <a href="https://github.com/mozilla/OpenDesign/issues/215" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Mozilla Open Design</a> team, and one of contributor from India Tanzeel Khan brought the beautiful design (above one). But due to some issues were not  able to print this, but in the large LCD TV we showed this majestic poster during break (when we are not showing demo).</p>
<p>Second major task was to bring pull contributors who are going to speak at various sessions and also volunteers who can be at booth. Our plan is to make sure minimum 3 are present at any moment  at booth. At first invited Ramdayal, Abhiram and other speakers, they brought in huge number of other Mozillians who will participate.</p>
<p><strong>Day 1</strong></p>
<p>The Day 1 started with amazing show by Christ University students. Then Ric Wheeler started Keynote <strong>“Open source is better for companies/businesses, communities and developers”</strong> of Devconf. Once Keynote is done, we (Ram dayal, Bhuvana and myself) started towards Exhibition area to setup up Mozilla booth. It was start of the day, there were already many open source booth setup by other communities ( Elastic, FSMK, devopedia , Openshift and so on..).</p>
<p>Soon we setup the Mozilla Booth, large number of attendees started joining us. Soon Abhiram joined us to help and share about Rust Language. He started to share about Rust and also about his Amazing rust series which is available in lynda.com for 1 month trial. He brought the QR code ready so whoever wants to learn can scan and visit website directly. Sharing his Tweet which he made after event.</p>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">I published a programming course on <a href="https://twitter.com/rustlang?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@rustlang</a>, ideal for beginners. Do check it out and hope it helps! FYI – <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/rust?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#rust</a> is a systems level programming lang that’s super fast and memory efficient. <img alt="🦊" class="wp-smiley" src="https://s0.wp.com/wp-content/mu-plugins/wpcom-smileys/twemoji/2/72x72/1f98a.png" style="height: 1em;" /><img alt="🦀" class="wp-smiley" src="https://s0.wp.com/wp-content/mu-plugins/wpcom-smileys/twemoji/2/72x72/1f980.png" style="height: 1em;" /><img alt="🌍" class="wp-smiley" src="https://s0.wp.com/wp-content/mu-plugins/wpcom-smileys/twemoji/2/72x72/1f30d.png" style="height: 1em;" /> It just hit 4.5 K views. Woot! <img alt="🙏" class="wp-smiley" src="https://s0.wp.com/wp-content/mu-plugins/wpcom-smileys/twemoji/2/72x72/1f64f.png" style="height: 1em;" /> <a href="https://twitter.com/mozilla?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@mozilla</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/MozLearn?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@MozLearn</a> <a href="https://t.co/wSIhkj8cm9">https://t.co/wSIhkj8cm9</a> <a href="https://t.co/trwKtUuzSb">pic.twitter.com/trwKtUuzSb</a></p>
<p>— Abhiram Ravikumar (@abhi12ravi) <a href="https://twitter.com/abhi12ravi/status/1026855444718014464?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 7, 2018</a></p></blockquote>
<p>At the mean time, on another side Ramdayal was sharing his experience about WebVR.  Rakhi was sharing about Mozilla Contribution in general, I was setting up with the Code demo for WebExtension.  Bhuvana was helping me to setup her <a href="https://bhuvanameenakshik.github.io/Pongal_WebVR_wishes/index.html" rel="noopener" target="_blank">WebVR demo</a> , old but we can use this to explain about Aframe simply.</p>
<p>After their session <a href="https://twitter.com/rowdymehul" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Mehul Patel</a> and <a class="external text" href="https://twitter.com/viralparmarhack" rel="nofollow">Viral Parmar</a>  came to Mozilla booth and sharing their knowledge about Rust and Privacy. Our Swag superstar <a href="https://twitter.com/pathfinderpc" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Prathamesh Chavan</a> traveled from Pune to Bangalore, and without taking any break he reached venue ( remember Bangalore airport to Venue will take around an hour).</p>
<p>Around afternoon, <a href="http://Shivam Singhal" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Shivam Singhal</a> gave his Session on WebExtension and <a href="https://twitter.com/bhuvanakotees1" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Bhuvana</a> gave her session on WebXR. And also <a href="https://twitter.com/lavish205" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Lavish Aggarwal</a> joined us and started sharing about WebExtension.</p>
<p><img alt="dig" class="size-full wp-image-874 aligncenter" src="https://vp7techie.files.wordpress.com/2018/08/img_20180804_152628.jpg?w=1140" /></p>
<p>During one of the free moment we Mozilla TechSpeakers got chance to click ourself <img alt="❤" class="wp-smiley" src="https://s0.wp.com/wp-content/mu-plugins/wpcom-smileys/twemoji/2/72x72/2764.png" style="height: 1em;" /></p>
<p><img alt="cof" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-875" src="https://vp7techie.files.wordpress.com/2018/08/img_20180804_163642.jpg?w=1140" /></p>
<p>Around 5:30 PM we all Mozillians left after having some casual talks like what we are going to focus on future, and exchanged lot of interesting ideas. Around 750+ members might have joined us at booth.</p>
<p>Second day started at 9:00 AM as usual. We made sure no one is waiting for us. The crowd was comparatively less at the morning as we had Keynote starting.</p>
<p>We are joined by <a href="https://twitter.com/jyotsna17gupta" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Jyotsna Gupta</a> , Lavish , <a href="https://twitter.com/TushkiSpeaks" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Tushar Arora</a> , Abraar Syed , pooja and many others (sorry forgetting the names). At times went to other booths and goto learn interesting projects like Foreman, Elastic.</p>
<p><img alt="gupta" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-880" src="https://vp7techie.files.wordpress.com/2018/08/gupta.jpeg?w=1140" /></p>
<p><a href="https://twitter.com/Diipeshmonga" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Dipesh monga</a> was giving his talk on second day about Dark side of Internet of things.</p>
<p><img alt="dipnesh.jpeg" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-881" src="https://vp7techie.files.wordpress.com/2018/08/dipnesh.jpeg?w=1140" /></p>
<p>At the second afternoon, I requested a click with <a href="https://twitter.com/Sayak_Sarkar" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Sayak</a>, its not easy to catch him, I have been to pune twice for <a href="https://vp7techie.wordpress.com/2018/04/27/coep-foss-meetup-2018/">COEP FOSS Meetup</a> and <a href="https://vp7techie.wordpress.com/2018/02/19/gnunify-2018/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">GNUinfy</a> 2018 but was not able to meet him. He is one of the very good friend and we used to talk randomly for very long time. Along with us we have <a href="https://twitter.com/sw4rn4v4" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Swarnava Sengupta</a>  a very calm person who is amazing contributor to AMO advisory board and Mehul who is actively bring more rust contributors.</p>
<p><img alt="IMG_20180805_145454" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-877" src="https://vp7techie.files.wordpress.com/2018/08/img_20180805_145454.jpg?w=1140" /></p>
<p>On Second Day evening I was fortune to meet Deb, one of the long time Mozillian who was looked like Coding God for community members from Mozilla India, he is one of the greatest Mozillian I have met.</p>
<p><img alt="IMG_20180805_181535" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-876" src="https://vp7techie.files.wordpress.com/2018/08/img_20180805_181535.jpg?w=1140" /></p>
<p>We tried to capture some of group pictures, for sure some contributors who actively were in booth or giving talks are missing in pictures.</p>
<p><img alt="(JPEG Image, 1280 × 720 pixels)" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-879" src="https://vp7techie.files.wordpress.com/2018/08/jpeg-image-1280c2a0c397c2a0720-pixels.jpeg?w=1140" /></p>
<p>Thanks to each and everyone who made this Devconf a amazing experience. It is one of the most recommended event and each developer should try to attend. We can get opportunity to meet many amazing people here.</p>]]>
  </description>
  <pubDate>Fri, 10 Aug 2018 20:08:04 +0000</pubDate>
  
</item>

<item>
  <title>Official Reps Blog - Rep of the Month – July 2018</title>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.mozilla.org/mozillareps/?p=558</guid>
  <link>https://blog.mozilla.org/mozillareps/2018/08/10/rep-of-the-month-july-2018/</link>
  <description>
    <![CDATA[<div class="cooked">
<p>Please join us in congratulating <a href="https://reps.mozilla.org/u/Liv/" rel="nofollow noopener">Lívia Takács</a>, our Rep of the Month for July 2018!</p>
<p>Livia is a UI developer and visual designer from Hungary and has been part of the Reps program for a bit more than a year. In that time she organized a lot of events with different communities (like LibreOffice) and also workshops.</p>
<div class="lightbox-wrapper">
<p><a class="lightbox" href="https://discourse-paas-production-content.s3.amazonaws.com/original/3X/4/2/42d28bad219b632f3736b0dbd9e03318e4f20bdf.jpg" rel="nofollow noopener" title="99327b7dc22fc651f4019467a59b0cbb.jpg"><img alt="99327b7dc22fc651f4019467a59b0cbb" height="400" src="https://discourse-paas-production-content.s3.amazonaws.com/optimized/3X/4/2/42d28bad219b632f3736b0dbd9e03318e4f20bdf_1_400x400.jpeg" width="400" /></a></p>
<div class="meta"><span class="informations"> </span></div>
</div>
<p>She also organizes Mozilla Hungary community meetings and a few months ago she organized the <a href="https://reps.mozilla.org/e/firefox-support-sprint-5/" rel="nofollow noopener">Firefox Support Sprint</a> in Budapest.</p>
<p>She is a mentor and teacher at specific workshops where she teaches JavaScript and localization, such as <a href="https://reps.mozilla.org/e/mozskool-4/" rel="nofollow noopener">MozSkool</a> teaching JavaScript to 15-18 years old girls and <a href="https://reps.mozilla.org/e/mozscope-workshop-5/" rel="nofollow noopener">MozScope</a> localization workshops. This is a great example that a community builder can organize events but also mentor and teach new people to help growing the local community.</p>
<p>Thanks Lívia, keep rocking the Open Web! <img alt=":tada:" class="emoji" src="https://cdn-production.discourse.mozilla-community.org/images/emoji/twitter/tada.png?v=5" title=":tada:" /> <img alt=":tada:" class="emoji" src="https://cdn-production.discourse.mozilla-community.org/images/emoji/twitter/tada.png?v=5" title=":tada:" /></p>
<p><a href="https://discourse.mozilla.org/t/rep-of-the-month-july-2018/30819">Please head over to Discourse to congratulate her!</a></p>
</div>]]>
  </description>
  <pubDate>Fri, 10 Aug 2018 09:18:49 +0000</pubDate>
  
</item>

<item>
  <title>Official Reps Blog - Onboarding team for 2nd half of 2018</title>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.mozilla.org/mozillareps/?p=556</guid>
  <link>https://blog.mozilla.org/mozillareps/2018/08/08/onboarding-team-for-2nd-half-of-2018/</link>
  <description>
    <![CDATA[<p><em>This blogpost was composed by <a href="https://reps.mozilla.org/u/Mte90/">Daniele Scasciafratte</a></em></p>
<p>As we have entered the second half of the year, the Reps Council has worked on updating  the Onboarding Screening Team for 2018-2.</p>
<p>The scope of this team is to help on evaluating the new applications to the Reps program by helping the Reps Council on this process.</p>
<p>In June we opened a call for the new team members on <a href="https://discourse.mozilla.org/t/do-you-want-join-the-onboarding-screening-team-for-2018-2/29713">https://discourse.mozilla.org/t/do-you-want-join-the-onboarding-screening-team-for-2018-2/29713</a></p>
<p>We’ve got 13 applications in total. Out of them 9 applications were fitting in the Selection Criteria defined on <a href="https://wiki.mozilla.org/ReMo/Webinar/Screening">https://wiki.mozilla.org/ReMo/Webinar/Screening</a>,  you can find the people that applied is on <a href="https://github.com/mozilla/Reps/issues/333">https://github.com/mozilla/Reps/issues/333</a>.</p>
<p>After 2 weeks the Reps Council voted and chose the new members.</p>
<p>The new members of the team for the next 6 months are:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://reps.mozilla.org/u/Mad_Maks/">Tim Maks van den Broek</a></li>
<li><a href="https://reps.mozilla.org/u/gmontagu/">Gabriela Montagu</a></li>
<li><a href="https://reps.mozilla.org/u/rtsayles/">Robby Sayles</a></li>
<li><a href="https://reps.mozilla.org/u/david_ross/">David Ross</a></li>
</ul>
<p>The previous team members were:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://reps.mozilla.org/u/Mad_Maks/">Tim Maks van den Broek</a></li>
<li><a href="https://reps.mozilla.org/u/vi5halc/">Vishal Chavan</a></li>
<li><a href="https://reps.mozilla.org/u/akayannick98/">Aka Brou Yannick N</a></li>
<li><a href="https://reps.mozilla.org/u/gmontagu/">Gabriela Montagu</a></li>
</ul>
<p> </p>
<p>The previous  team worked on reviewing 17 applications in 7 rounds in the last 7 months. Thanks a lot for your hard work!</p>
<p>Looking into the  numbers of applications compared to the 2018-1 team (<a href="https://blog.mozilla.org/mozillareps/2018/02/15/reps-on-boarding-team/">https://blog.mozilla.org/mozillareps/2018/02/15/reps-on-boarding-team/</a>) the number of applications have declined compared to the previous year.</p>
<p>The new team will start to work soon (we have about 3 applications in queue). A Reps Council Member will also join the team, focusing on communications between applicants and the evaluation of the team.</p>
<p>If you want to congratulate your fellows Reps you can do it in this thread: https://discourse.mozilla.org/t/onboarding-screening-team-2018-2/30794</p>]]>
  </description>
  <pubDate>Wed, 08 Aug 2018 15:11:26 +0000</pubDate>
  
</item>

<item>
  <title>Official Reps Blog - Reps Council at SF All Hands 2018</title>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.mozilla.org/mozillareps/?p=552</guid>
  <link>https://blog.mozilla.org/mozillareps/2018/07/20/reps-council-at-sf-all-hands-2018/</link>
  <description>
    <![CDATA[<p><em>This post was written by <a href="https://reps.mozilla.org/u/prathamesh/">Prathamesh Chavan</a></em></p>
<p><b>TL;DR</b></p>
<p><i>The All Hands is a special time of the year where Mozilla employees along with core volunteers gather for a week of many meetings and brainstorming. The</i><a href="https://wiki.mozilla.org/All_Hands/SanFrancisco"><i> All Hands Wiki page</i></a><i> has more information about the general setting. During the All Hands, the Reps Council participated in the Open Innovation meetings as well as had meetings about improve 2018 planning. </i></p>
<p>The Mozilla All-Hands was organized between 11th June to 15th June 2018 in San Francisco. All Hands are a unique and special opportunity for all paid staff and our most impactful volunteers to come together, in person, to share experiences and interact with people they may not normally work with.</p>
<p>This year’s All Hands was a great learning experience for the Reps Council and Peers.</p>
<p>The Reps Council worked more on the projects which could directly or indirectly help the community and align the plan for the community for the next quarters.</p>
<p>One of the first things that we made was a little recap of what we have done in the first half:</p>
<p><a href="http://blog.mozilla.org/mozillareps/files/2018/07/reps_council.jpg"><img alt="" class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-553" height="241" src="http://blog.mozilla.org/mozillareps/files/2018/07/reps_council-252x241.jpg" width="252" /></a></p>
<p>The Reps Council members were invited to join the different meetings which were focused on Localization of Firefox, the Addon sprint campaigns to define the final plan and Diversity &amp; Inclusion.</p>
<p>The status of Mission Driven Mozillians and the Mozilla Group experiment in India was also shared with the Reps Council. The Reps Council was very interested to understand how the program can fit in and align itself with the new opportunities.</p>
<p>The Reps Council also ran a check on the issues opened in <a href="https://github.com/mozilla/reps/issues">https://github.com/mozilla/reps/issues</a> and assigned tasks on the issues which were pending or open since a while.</p>
<p>The Reps Council and Peers discussed some of the important things which are as follows :</p>
<p>– Achievements in the past quarter</p>
<p>– Mozilla Reps Logo</p>
<p>– Mozilla Reps Newsletter team</p>
<p>– Prioritize tickets for the Reps Portal</p>
<p>– Collecting ideas about data gathering to enable data-driven decisions</p>
<p>– Issues on priorities</p>
<p>– Failure and Success of the Reps program</p>
<p>– Mission Driven Mozillians</p>
<p>– H2 plan</p>
<p>There was a meeting on the H2 plan to discuss and assign priorities. A blogpost about this plan would be shared soon.</p>
<p>The Open Innovation Team shared the numbers of the Sprints of this half of the year where there was an huge involvement of our Reps and communities.</p>
<p>The All Hands was quite productive for the Reps Council and the things which were discussed would start be getting reflected in the present quarter (July, August, September).</p>
<p>Useful Links:</p>
<ul>
<li>Sessions recorded: <a href="https://onlinexperiences.com/scripts/Server.nxp?LASCmd=AI:1;F:US!100&amp;PreviousLoginCount=2&amp;ForceProfileToBeFilledOut=0&amp;DisplayItem=NULL&amp;ShowKey=44908&amp;ShowFrameFormatOverride=NULL&amp;RandomValue=1531273113048">https://onlinexperiences.com/scripts/Server.nxp?LASCmd=AI:1;F:US!100&amp;PreviousLoginCount=2&amp;ForceProfileToBeFilledOut=0&amp;DisplayItem=NULL&amp;ShowKey=44908&amp;ShowFrameFormatOverride=NULL&amp;RandomValue=1531273113048</a></li>
</ul>
<p>Schedule:<a href="https://sanfranciscoallhandsjune2018.sched.com/"> https://sanfranciscoallhandsjune2018.sched.com/</a></p>
<div class="wp-caption aligncenter" id="attachment_554" style="width: 262px;"><a href="http://blog.mozilla.org/mozillareps/files/2018/07/reps-council-and-peers.jpg"><img alt="" class="size-medium wp-image-554" height="126" src="http://blog.mozilla.org/mozillareps/files/2018/07/reps-council-and-peers-252x126.jpg" width="252" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Reps Council and Peers in All Hands (missing Henrik Mitsch)</p></div>]]>
  </description>
  <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jul 2018 12:39:37 +0000</pubDate>
  
</item>

<item>
  <title>Official Reps Blog - In loving memory of Abbackar DIOMANDE</title>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.mozilla.org/mozillareps/?p=549</guid>
  <link>https://blog.mozilla.org/mozillareps/2018/07/18/in-loving-memory-of-abbackar-diomande/</link>
  <description>
    <![CDATA[<p>It brings us great sadness to share with you the recent news about one of our dear Rep we will so fondly remember. Abbackar DIOMANDE from Ivory Coast is unfortunately no longer with us.</p>
<p>Diomande, was a Mozillian from Bouake, Ivory Coast and was contributing in various Mozilla projects including SUMO and L10n.<br />
He was a local community builder, that helped to build a healthy local community in his country while lately he had also taken the role of a Resources Rep, helping his fellow Mozillians on organizing local initiatives.</p>
<p><a href="http://blog.mozilla.org/mozillareps/files/2018/07/diomande.jpg"><img alt="" class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-550" height="448" src="http://blog.mozilla.org/mozillareps/files/2018/07/diomande-252x448.jpg" width="252" /></a><br />
His passing is finding us sadden and shocked. His contributions helped our community intensively and while we have a heavy heart, we know that his passion and inspiration will sustain with us.</p>
<p>Our condolences to his family and friends.</p>
<p><b>Bellow are some words about Diomande and his work from his community members in French</b></p>
<blockquote><p>Puisse Dieu t’accueillir dans son royaume Diomande. Mes Condoléances à toute la famille.</p>
<p>Diomandé a été un de mes meilleurs mentorés, il a aimé et est toujours resté fan de Mozilla , avec le coeur il a su toujours selon sa façon conduire sa passion pour Mozilla.<br />
Tu n’a pas souffert, que la terre te soit légère et tu puisse trouver la paix. Repose en paix Diomandé.<br />
Mes condoléances à toute ta famille, tes amis qui t’aimaient et toute la famille Mozilla.</p>
<p>Rip Cher ami , le passage est obligatoire , Puisse Dieu te reserver un acceuille céleste digne de tes apports volontaires , Mozillians from Pigier</p>
<p>Courage, oui grand courage à la famille, un genie ne meurt jamais. Abbackar n’est pas mort, il nous attend juste de l’autre côté de la rive. Abbackar n’est pas mort, Abbackar vivra toujours.</p>
<p>Diomandé été un des contributeur de Mozilla, à travers tous ses ateliers ou actions menées pour la communauté, ses traces resterons à jamais, elles continueront de parler de lui. Je retiens à lui, un grand homme plein de valeurs, son époque sera marqué par des traces indélibiles. ( Wilfried N’Guessan )</p>
<p>Diomandé était un bosseur, un battant qui a aimé trop le développement d’applications. Il a proposé des solutions innovantes . Mes respects pour chaque bonne action qu’il a fait pour ce monde. (Ange Bagui)</p>
<p>Un MozBoy est pati. Un arbuste qui avait toutes les aptitudes pour devenir une grande arbre avec de grande branches et un gros spectre d’ombre. La communauté a perdu un véritable passionné. YAKO A TOUS !!!</p>
<p>Cher ami, c’est avec les larmes aux yeux et une grande tristesse que je redige cette note. Tu vas nous manquer!</p></blockquote>]]>
  </description>
  <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jul 2018 12:35:46 +0000</pubDate>
  
</item>

<item>
  <title>Official Reps Blog - H2 2018 Reps Plan for the Council</title>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.mozilla.org/mozillareps/?p=544</guid>
  <link>https://blog.mozilla.org/mozillareps/2018/07/16/544/</link>
  <description>
    <![CDATA[<p><em>This blogpost was authored by </em><a href="https://reps.mozilla.org/u/Mte90/"><em>Daniele Scasciafratte</em></a></p>
<h2>What we have done</h2>
<p>In the first half of the year, our focus was to align the program with <a href="https://discourse.mozilla.org/tags/mission-mozillians">Mission Driven Mozillians</a> and prepare the mandatory Reps onboarding course to ensure it aligns with the D&amp;I work. We have also started improving the understanding of issues of different Reps roles like Mentors and Alumni.</p>
<p>We also worked on administration issues like the transition of inactive Reps to Alumni, the cleanup of old Reps applications still open after years and wrong mentors assigned to profiles and the improvement of our reporting system. Last but not least, we moved to the creation of expertise teams that took over everyday work day tasks from the Council (newsletter and onboarding).</p>
<p>We’ve chosen to split our ideas and tasks in 3 different areas for the next half of the year (with percentage):</p>
<ul>
<li>Prepare the ground for Mission Driven Mozillians: 45%</li>
<li>Visible wins: 45%</li>
<li>Miscellaneous: 10%</li>
</ul>
<h2 style="text-align: left;">Prepare the ground for Mission Driven Mozillians</h2>
<p>The Reps program is working to prepare the ground for Mission Driven Mozillians and there are different tasks and issues to face for that.</p>
<p>The most important point for the Reps Council is the Roles of Reps inside the communities. We know that in Mozilla there are a lot of international communities, local community and project specific communities, and we need to understand and be ready to support all of them.</p>
<p>We gathered different ideas that we will investigate soon:</p>
<ul>
<li>Role of Reps
<ul>
<li>Update all the Reps about the last updates of the Mission Driven Mozillians program
<ul>
<li>Understanding and agreement on Leadership Agreement</li>
<li>Start conversations on where Reps belong/Reps Role</li>
<li>We are already working on:
<ul>
<li>Restart Newsletter with a new team</li>
<li>Discussion about migrating the Reps mailing list to Discourse</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Create courses for various roles
<ul>
<li>Review Team and Mentors already have a course</li>
<li>We are working on a new onboarding course</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Skills criteria for various roles
<ul>
<li>Every role has a skillset and we are working to improve them as requirements</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Mozilla Groups (MDM)
<ul>
<li>How they fit inside the Reps program
<ul>
<li>This is an experiment and we need to understand how the program can fit to be part of this initiative</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Onboarding
<ul>
<li>New SOPs for various roles/teams
<ul>
<li>We updated SOPs in the past and we need to define where we need to update them</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Courses inside the program
<ul>
<li>Few roles have courses but for Reps we need to define if we can do general courses or if we can find them already available</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>CPG Alignment (update the Reps with updated CPG information, add it as mandatory part to the onboarding course)</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<h2 style="text-align: left;">Visible wins</h2>
<p>The program also needs to be more visible inside Mozilla and the others communities, so we’ve chosen to focus on 3 different areas:</p>
<ul>
<li>Communication
<ul>
<li>Discover new areas where Reps are missing
<ul>
<li>There are a lot of communities where we don’t have a large representation or there is no interest</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Reps news to all Mozilla
<ul>
<li>Share what Reps are doing, for example during the Weekly Monday Project Call</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Statistics
<ul>
<li>Showcase events inside Mozilla
<ul>
<li>Improve the sharing of statistics about what volunteers are doing</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Campaigns
<ul>
<li>Plan for more than 3 weeks out
<ul>
<li>Let the community be aware of a new campaign in advice</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Pocket involvement
<ul>
<li>Part of Mozilla but there is no involvement of volunteers right now</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Create an event asset repository
<ul>
<li>Events often require the same resources such as graphics or links, we need to gather them</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<h2 style="text-align: left;">Miscellaneous</h2>
<p>The last area that we chose are the miscellaneous ideas, something that does not block the program’s goals but can improve it, at the same time this has low priority:</p>
<ul>
<li>Improving mentee/mentors relationship</li>
<li>Improving understanding of Alumni role</li>
<li>Improve reps-tweet social usage</li>
<li>Style guidelines for the community</li>
<li>Reporting activities
<ul>
<li>Encourage Reps to report activities
<ul>
<li>Without reports it’s difficult to do data-driven decisions</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Understand issues Reps face with reporting</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p>This list of ideas will be evaluated in the next quarters by the Council and as usual we are open to feedback!</p>]]>
  </description>
  <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jul 2018 14:34:26 +0000</pubDate>
  
</item>

<item>
  <title>Viswaprasath KS - Mozofest 2018</title>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://vp7techie.wordpress.com/?p=863</guid>
  <link>https://vp7techie.wordpress.com/2018/07/08/mozofest-2018/</link>
  <description>
    <![CDATA[<p>Mozofest  is an event organized by <a href="https://srmkzilla.net/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">SRMKzilla</a> club each and every year. This year they had big plans for this event. Usually they used limited number of events this year they had Speaker series, Hackathon and other events which educate about internet.</p>
<p><img alt="mozofest" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-867" src="https://vp7techie.files.wordpress.com/2018/07/mozofest.jpg?w=1140" /></p>
<p>Pic Credits: Mozofest Team from SRMKzilla.</p>
<p>I was asked to filter the Call for proposals this year and also to judge the hackathon along with Karthick, Dinesh and Jayesh.</p>
<p>It was 3 days events, and on first day small quiz competition , coding event and other happened.</p>
<p>On 2nd day, Jayesh organized  Hands-on session on Rust and on another side Bhuvana &amp; Karan ganeshan was giving session on WebVR. At the end of 2nd day around 5.00 PM 24 hours hackathon was started.</p>
<p>Rust Workshop Agenda</p>
<ul>
<li>
<ul>
<li>
<ul>
<li><span style="font-family: Times New Roman, serif;"><span style="font-size: medium;">Mozilla and rust</span></span></li>
<li><span style="font-family: Times New Roman, serif;"><span style="font-size: medium;">What is rust? Why rust?</span></span></li>
<li><span style="font-family: Times New Roman, serif;"><span style="font-size: medium;">Projects where rust is used</span></span></li>
<li><span style="font-family: Times New Roman, serif;"><span style="font-size: medium;">Features of rust</span></span></li>
<li><span style="font-family: Times New Roman, serif;"><span style="font-size: medium;">Ongoing projects on Rust</span></span></li>
<li><span style="font-family: Times New Roman, serif;"><span style="font-size: medium;">Hands on Rust</span></span></li>
<li><span style="font-family: Times New Roman, serif;"><span style="font-size: medium;">Q &amp; A Session</span></span></li>
<li><span style="font-family: Times New Roman, serif;"><span style="font-size: medium;">Subscriptions to rust mailing lists and channels</span></span></li>
<li><span style="font-family: Times New Roman, serif;"><span style="font-size: medium;">SWAG Distribution</span></span></li>
<li><span style="font-family: Times New Roman, serif;"><span style="font-size: medium;">Feedback and Wrap up session</span></span></li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p>On 3rd day, we had our  <strong>SRM FOSS Meetup</strong>, which was the most awaited moment.</p>
<p>This FOSS meetup was inaugurated by long time Open source contributor from Chennai.</p>
<p><img alt="SRM_FOSS" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-864" src="https://vp7techie.files.wordpress.com/2018/07/srm_foss.png?w=1140" /></p>
<p>Again on Day 3, we had a small introduction talk on Rust by Jayesh and WebVR by Bhuvana.</p>
<p><img alt="webVr" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-865" src="https://vp7techie.files.wordpress.com/2018/07/webvr.jpg?w=1140" /></p>
<p>We are amazing number of sessions by Mozillians.</p>
<ol>
<li>Python 3 by Sriram.</li>
<li>Getting Started to Open source by Balaji.</li>
<li>Rust by Jayesh.</li>
<li>WebVR by Bhuvana.</li>
<li>Contributing to L10N by Dhinesh.</li>
<li>QA by Aditya</li>
<li>Why WebCompact is important by Karthikeyan.</li>
<li>Getting Started with Privacy by Sayaji.</li>
<li>Auth0 by Mehul.</li>
<li>WebExtension by Khaleel.</li>
<li>PWA by Viswaprasath.</li>
</ol>
<p>On the evening I gave a basic introduction Progressive Web Apps and Service workers by using a small demo (creating simple About us page).</p>
<p><img alt="PWA" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-866" src="https://vp7techie.files.wordpress.com/2018/07/pwa.jpg?w=1140" /></p>
<p>After all the session were over on that day, we were given opportunity to judge hackathon projects.</p>
<ol>
<li>Karthikeyan.</li>
<li>Dinesh</li>
<li>Jayesh</li>
<li>Mehul</li>
<li>and myself.</li>
</ol>
<p>It was very organized. Over 600 people from different parts of Tamilnadu came to booth, workshops , talks.</p>]]>
  </description>
  <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jul 2018 12:30:28 +0000</pubDate>
  
</item>

<item>
  <title>Md Shahbaz Alam - LinuxCon China</title>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alamshahbaz.wordpress.com/?p=1081</guid>
  <link>https://alamshahbaz.wordpress.com/2018/07/05/linuxcon-china/</link>
  <description>
    <![CDATA[<p>LinuxCon China was a technical conference for developers, operations experts (architects, sys admins, devops), business, compliance and legal leadership and other professionals to come together in an informal setting to learn from open source experts, have fascinating discussions, collaborate with peers, and gain a competitive advantage with innovative open solutions.</p>
<p>This year I got an opportunity to talk about and represent Auth0 and Mozilla at LinuxCon. It was a 3-day conference where My first talk was based on Serverless where I was representing Auth0 and next day I was representing Mozilla with A-frame and WebVR theme.</p>
<p><img alt="IMG_20180626_092158" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1086" src="https://alamshahbaz.files.wordpress.com/2018/07/img_20180626_092158-e1530764692916.jpg?w=788" /></p>
<p>The first day was really amazing as I had to visit all the sponsor’s booth where I got swags and most importantly networking. My talk on Serverless was at 16:20 Chinese Time. It was wonderful to see many attendees waiting for the talk, I started the <a href="https://slides.com/mdsbzalam/lc3-china/">presentation</a> where I discussed the basics of Client-Server architecture and why we need security layer and how one can get started with serverless. The response of the talk was really good as many came after the session for the get started link and to clear their doubts. It was a good day at the conference.</p>

<a href="https://alamshahbaz.wordpress.com/2018/07/05/linuxcon-china/img_20180626_142830/"><img alt="" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail" height="150" src="https://alamshahbaz.files.wordpress.com/2018/07/img_20180626_142830.jpg?w=113&amp;h=150" width="113" /></a>
<a href="https://alamshahbaz.wordpress.com/2018/07/05/linuxcon-china/img_20180626_090953/"><img alt="" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail" height="150" src="https://alamshahbaz.files.wordpress.com/2018/07/img_20180626_090953.jpg?w=113&amp;h=150" width="113" /></a>
<a href="https://alamshahbaz.wordpress.com/2018/07/05/linuxcon-china/img_20180626_140959/"><img alt="" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail" height="113" src="https://alamshahbaz.files.wordpress.com/2018/07/img_20180626_140959.jpg?w=150&amp;h=113" width="150" /></a>
<a href="https://alamshahbaz.wordpress.com/2018/07/05/linuxcon-china/img_20180626_140732/"><img alt="" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail" height="113" src="https://alamshahbaz.files.wordpress.com/2018/07/img_20180626_140732.jpg?w=150&amp;h=113" width="150" /></a>

<p>The second day, I had an open session at the CNCC, where I was given a space where attendees came to interact and know about the project. The project I was having was of A-frame and WebVR. It was really fun to interact with the Chinese attendees as many were unable to understand or speak English, so I had to use VPN to use Google Translate( good translation <img alt="🙂" class="wp-smiley" src="https://s0.wp.com/wp-content/mu-plugins/wpcom-smileys/twemoji/2/72x72/1f642.png" style="height: 1em;" /> ). Many were excited to know about A-frame since it requires a very little amount of background in computer science to get started. I have shared the links with them via email and wechat. It was a good day to conclude the conference and very happy to represent both Mozilla and Auth0.</p>

<a href="https://alamshahbaz.wordpress.com/2018/07/05/linuxcon-china/img_20180627_101439/"><img alt="" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail" height="113" src="https://alamshahbaz.files.wordpress.com/2018/07/img_20180627_101439.jpg?w=150&amp;h=113" width="150" /></a>
<a href="https://alamshahbaz.wordpress.com/2018/07/05/linuxcon-china/img_20180627_101301/"><img alt="" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail" height="150" src="https://alamshahbaz.files.wordpress.com/2018/07/img_20180627_101301.jpg?w=113&amp;h=150" width="113" /></a>

<p>Sorry for not taking lot of pics. Thank you and enjoy the panda kick<img alt="IMG_20180626_121206" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1089" src="https://alamshahbaz.files.wordpress.com/2018/07/img_20180626_121206.jpg?w=788" /></p>]]>
  </description>
  <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jul 2018 04:43:27 +0000</pubDate>
  
</item>

<item>
  <title>Nino Vranesic - Hack all the things</title>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.elnino.si/post/175384669542</guid>
  <link>http://blog.elnino.si/post/175384669542</link>
  <description>
    <![CDATA[The term “hacker” can refer to someone or an activity with either good or bad intentions. The...]]>
  </description>
  <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jun 2018 22:14:18 +0000</pubDate>
  
</item>

<item>
  <title>Official Reps Blog - Rep of the Month – May 2018</title>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.mozilla.org/mozillareps/?p=542</guid>
  <link>https://blog.mozilla.org/mozillareps/2018/06/22/rep-of-the-month-may-2018/</link>
  <description>
    <![CDATA[<div class="cooked">
<p>Please join us in congratulating <a href="https://reps.mozilla.org/u/prathamesh/" rel="nofollow noopener">Prathamesh Chavan</a>, our Rep of the Month for May 2018!</p>
<p>Prathamesh is from Pune, India and works as a Technical Support Engineer at Red Hat. From his very early days in the Mozilla community, Prathamesh used his excellect people skills to spread the community to different colleges and to evangelise many of the upcoming projects, products and Mozilla initiatives. Prathamesh is also a very resourceful person. Due to this, he did a great job at organizing some great events at Pune and creare many new Mozilla Clubs across the city there.</p>
<div class="lightbox-wrapper">
<p><a class="lightbox" href="https://discourse-paas-production-content.s3.amazonaws.com/original/3X/9/e/9e2ff4bafa27272879197d407a2f7f47930eeec3.jpg" rel="nofollow noopener" title="ad79ac8cab406498f2d8168484b3525b.jpg"><img alt="ad79ac8cab406498f2d8168484b3525b" height="500" src="https://discourse-paas-production-content.s3.amazonaws.com/optimized/3X/9/e/9e2ff4bafa27272879197d407a2f7f47930eeec3_1_500x500.jpg" width="500" /></a></p>
<div class="meta"><span class="informations"> </span></div>
</div>
<p>As a Mozilla Reps Council member, Prathamesh has done some great work and has shown great leadership skills. He is always proactive in sharing important updates with the bigger community as well as raising his hand at every new initiative.</p>
<p>Thanks Prathamesh, keep rocking the Open Web!</p>
<p><a href="https://discourse.mozilla.org/t/rep-of-the-month-may-2018/29547">Please congratulate him by heading over to the Discourse topic.</a></p>
</div>]]>
  </description>
  <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jun 2018 08:30:16 +0000</pubDate>
  
</item>

<item>
  <title>Bhuvana Meenakshi Koteeswaran - Taking WebXR to the most energetic gen</title>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://kbmtechie.wordpress.com/?p=159</guid>
  <link>https://kbmtechie.wordpress.com/2018/05/29/taking-webxr-to-the-most-energetic-gen/</link>
  <description>
    <![CDATA[<p><strong>Venue: Academic heights public school, Hyderabad</strong></p>
<p><strong>Date: 20.05.2018</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">I in the first place wondered whether a topic like WebXR going to complicate the audience I targeted for the day. My audience included 50+ kids, their parents and their guardians of the AHP school. But when I showed the crowd the VR googles and asked the question what is it and what does that deal with, I got answers from 5 kids. With no doubt the kids were familiar with Virtual Reality as they had played games in malls and game arcades in their city. Also they were familiar with Augmented Reality as they had played Pokemon Go in their mobile phones. This eventually made my job easy.</p>

<p><img alt="IMG_2139.JPG" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-274" height="303" src="https://kbmtechie.files.wordpress.com/2018/05/img_2139.jpg?w=404" width="404" /></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">I amused them with the fusing results of AR and VR and how this can lead to WebXR. They loved experimenting with the VR googles. They in fact gave solutions on how their education system can be improvised with technologies like these. It was very much vibrant to see these kids who wanted to make their classrooms more interesting.</p>

<p><img alt="2.jpg" class="  wp-image-273 aligncenter" height="249" src="https://kbmtechie.files.wordpress.com/2018/05/21.jpg?w=190&amp;h=249" width="190" /></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">The afternoon session was mainly focussed for parents and guardians. I emphasised on why this gen must be involved in learning latest technology. Also in most parts of India after a girl child finishes her studies, about 70-80% percent are married at an earlier age (that is before they getting an industry ot real technology exposure), so application of knowledge is very less. To overcome this I shared ideas and motivated the parents to allow their girls to freely explore what they need in life in terms of technology or any other innovation. Furthermore, I took myself as an example and told them my journey and how I got into Mozilla and also how Mozilla helps its women contributors through its Womoz program.</p>
<p><img alt="IMG_2205.JPG" class="aligncenter  wp-image-271" height="234" src="https://kbmtechie.files.wordpress.com/2018/05/img_22051.jpg?w=313&amp;h=234" width="313" /></p>
<p> </p>
<p>The final touch as usual, no matter whatever the age group my audience fall into, they always love the swags from Mozilla.</p>
<p><img alt="1.jpg" class="  wp-image-272 aligncenter" height="218" src="https://kbmtechie.files.wordpress.com/2018/05/11.jpg?w=289&amp;h=218" width="289" /></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">As a closing note, I thank AHP school, Hyderabad for inviting me as a speaker for their Summer School progam 2018. Also my humblest gratitude to Mozilla and Shahbaz (my Reps mentor) for always encouraging me to participate in these wonderful events.</p>]]>
  </description>
  <pubDate>Tue, 29 May 2018 10:20:01 +0000</pubDate>
  
</item>

<item>
  <title>Bhuvana Meenakshi Koteeswaran - Organise things right!</title>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://kbmtechie.wordpress.com/?p=145</guid>
  <link>https://kbmtechie.wordpress.com/2018/05/15/organise-things-right/</link>
  <description>
    <![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;">The Global Sprint which was going throughout the world on various projects made Fahima and me to think about the event in our home town too. So I took the initiative to organise all things required for this event. I thought this way I would also learn a lot on event organisation and hosting.</p>
<p><img alt="photo_2018-05-11_13-34-54" class="  wp-image-262 aligncenter" height="277" src="https://kbmtechie.files.wordpress.com/2018/05/photo_2018-05-11_13-34-541.jpg?w=370&amp;h=277" width="370" /></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">We had 15+ participants who actively took part in this event. The event was focussed on SOHW(Spread Open Healthy Web) project and explained in what ways the participants can do their part in this project.</p>
<p><img alt="IMG_2107" class="  wp-image-263 aligncenter" height="290" src="https://kbmtechie.files.wordpress.com/2018/05/img_21071.jpg?w=387&amp;h=290" width="387" /></p>
<p> </p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">In this project we had various issues and its main objective was to be a single point of access to the resources thus helping the newbies to start their contributions. The issue had various interesting topics like making memes, designing logo and also many stuffs related to building the webpage for this particular project. Eventually, there were many options to contribute.</p>
<p><img alt="IMG_2099.JPG" class="  wp-image-264 aligncenter" height="168" src="https://kbmtechie.files.wordpress.com/2018/05/img_20991.jpg?w=225&amp;h=168" width="225" /></p>
<p>In the afternoon, we attended the global online conference call where everyone got an opportunity to speak about their projects. It was indeed amazing to see other projects happening world-wide. Found that this sprint was indeed spread across miles and had a great impact in relevant to current technologies and open source.</p>
<p><img alt="photo_2018-05-11_22-33-04" class="  wp-image-265 alignleft" height="231" src="https://kbmtechie.files.wordpress.com/2018/05/photo_2018-05-11_22-33-041.jpg?w=308&amp;h=231" width="308" />   <img alt="photo_2018-05-11_22-32-56.jpg" class="  wp-image-266 alignright" height="231" src="https://kbmtechie.files.wordpress.com/2018/05/photo_2018-05-11_22-32-561.jpg?w=308&amp;h=231" width="308" /></p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
<p><img alt="Dc7Z2ebV4AI-J-n" class="  wp-image-267 aligncenter" height="160" src="https://kbmtechie.files.wordpress.com/2018/05/dc7z2ebv4ai-j-n1.jpg?w=284&amp;h=160" width="284" /></p>
<p>Finally, we concluded the event with some feedback from the participants and also distributed the swags. We are very much grateful Smt. Sujatha, Principal, Sai Bhuvaneswari Vidyalaya N&amp;P school, for sponsoring a beautiful venue. The event was a great success and also we had contributors to this project from overseas where they worked in remote.</p>
<p><img alt="photo_2018-05-11_22-42-12.jpg" class=" size-full wp-image-268 alignnone" src="https://kbmtechie.files.wordpress.com/2018/05/photo_2018-05-11_22-42-121.jpg?w=620" /></p>
<p>Thanks Mozilla for giving us this wonderful opportunity and swags <img alt="🙂" class="wp-smiley" src="https://s0.wp.com/wp-content/mu-plugins/wpcom-smileys/twemoji/2/72x72/1f642.png" style="height: 1em;" /></p>
<p><img alt="photo_2018-05-11_13-33-19.jpg" class="aligncenter  wp-image-269" height="284" src="https://kbmtechie.files.wordpress.com/2018/05/photo_2018-05-11_13-33-191.jpg?w=379&amp;h=284" width="379" /></p>
<p> </p>]]>
  </description>
  <pubDate>Tue, 15 May 2018 05:31:24 +0000</pubDate>
  
</item>

<item>
  <title>Official Reps Blog - Rep of the Month – April 2018</title>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.mozilla.org/mozillareps/?p=540</guid>
  <link>https://blog.mozilla.org/mozillareps/2018/05/08/rep-of-the-month-april-2018/</link>
  <description>
    <![CDATA[<div class="cooked">
<p>Please join us in congratulating <a href="https://reps.mozilla.org/u/david_ross/" rel="nofollow noopener">David Ross</a>, our Rep of the Month for April 2018!</p>
<p>David is a Mozillian living the UK and active in a lot of different Mozilla projects. In his day job he is building an Open Source Fitness platform. You might have seen him at the past few MozFests in London. Last year he did a great job wrangling the Privacy&amp;Security space.</p>
<div class="lightbox-wrapper">
<p><a class="lightbox" href="https://discourse-paas-production-content.s3.amazonaws.com/original/3X/1/5/1513ff2c18b2fcc64e51ca06eb94c83535e31ba6.jpg" rel="nofollow noopener" title="6e9ef66996c0fc22dd0908e80dc6de47.jpg"><img alt="6e9ef66996c0fc22dd0908e80dc6de47" height="500" src="https://discourse-paas-production-content.s3.amazonaws.com/optimized/3X/1/5/1513ff2c18b2fcc64e51ca06eb94c83535e31ba6_1_500x500.jpg" width="500" /></a></p>
<div class="meta"><span class="informations"> </span></div>
</div>
<p>In the past few months David has <a href="https://reps.mozilla.org/reports/rep/david_ross/" rel="nofollow noopener">organized several MozCoffees in London</a> as well as online meetings for the London community. This is part of an effort to re-activate the UK<br />
community he took on. David likes to plan ahead and he already has 7 upcoming activities he is going to participate at, including an event in summer of 2019 (that’s not a typo)! Last but not least he was a nominee for the <a href="https://discourse.mozilla.org/t/important-council-elections-spring-2018-nominee-q-a/27331/11">recent Council election</a>.</p>
<p>Thanks David, keep rocking the Open Web!</p>
<p><a href="https://discourse.mozilla.org/t/rep-of-the-month-april-2018/28330">Head over to discourse to congratulate him!</a></p>
</div>]]>
  </description>
  <pubDate>Tue, 08 May 2018 15:09:18 +0000</pubDate>
  
</item>

<item>
  <title>Viswaprasath KS - COEP FOSS Meetup 2018</title>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://vp7techie.wordpress.com/2018/04/27/coep-foss-meetup-2018/</guid>
  <link>https://vp7techie.wordpress.com/2018/04/27/coep-foss-meetup-2018/</link>
  <description>
    <![CDATA[<p>This is my second visit to Pune, after my recent <a href="https://iamvp7.github.io//GNUNify_18">GNUify</a> event. GNUNify was mainly focused for Student developers, the target audience were getting started with Open source community. COeP Foss Meetup had well experienced developers and students who are contributing for FOSS community more than 1 year. Abhijit who is the professor at COEP and helping lot of students to get started with community. He is an amazing person I meet, who came forward to share his thoughts about my presentation and spends time with students and motivates them a lot.</p>
<p><img alt="COEP Talk on Stage" src="https://iamvp7.github.io//assets/2018/coep_talk.JPG" /></p>
<p>The hall was really big filled with 200 attendees. Energy was really good and I was really excited to give the presentation. For this presentation I have been showing the demo with Commands API and tabs.ExecuteScript API. The internet was really slow during my presentation, due to this therewas some breakage in the flow. Abhijit Sir, came forward to share his Mobile internet and I was able to show the demo of my Youtube Extension.</p>
<p>Some of the questions came around the Chrome Compatibility, and one of the long time Mozillian Friend Ankit gave suggestions in improving the Extensions which is used for demo.</p>
<p><img alt="COEP Ankit Question" src="https://iamvp7.github.io//assets/2018/coep_ankit.JPG" /></p>
<p>After my session we had amazing session by Kushal Das on SecureDrop. Then we had a session by Rahulkrishnan on Docker.</p>
<p>After the session we had a small Tea break session, where contributors from various projects came and had informal discussion. Some of the contributors who tried to become Mozilla Reps or tried to contribute to various projects shared the pros and cons in community.</p>
<p>In the evening I went to Ankit home and meet his family, had a very good tea time with them. After that we went to the near by mall and tried some amazing local food.</p>
<p>I personally felt this is amazing Meetup I have been. I really felt bad I didnt plan to attend the second day of the event. In upcoming years I will make sure to give talk on this Meetup. Personal thanks to Vikrant (student from coep), who was with me for the whole day.</p>]]>
  </description>
  <pubDate>Fri, 27 Apr 2018 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  
</item>

<item>
  <title>Md Shahbaz Alam - WebVR @ LPU</title>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alamshahbaz.wordpress.com/?p=1056</guid>
  <link>https://alamshahbaz.wordpress.com/2018/04/27/webvr-lpu/</link>
  <description>
    <![CDATA[<p>Lovely Professional University is a private university situated in Jalandhar, Punjab, India. It is a well know educational institutions in the country with around 34000 students and over 130 programs. Mrinal and I were invited to LPU for a workshop on WebVR ( Virtual Reality ). We reached LPU on 17th April and visited the campus.</p>
<div class="wp-caption alignnone" id="attachment_1075" style="width: 798px;"><img alt="DSC_0002" class="alignright size-large wp-image-1075" src="https://alamshahbaz.files.wordpress.com/2018/04/dsc_0002.jpg?w=788&amp;h=526" /><p class="wp-caption-text" id="caption-attachment-1075">The morning started with a good cup of tea</p></div>
<p>We reached the auditorium on time. And yes it was filled with 1300 students. One of the biggest auditorium I have seen till now.</p>
<p><img alt="DSC_0013" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1062" src="https://alamshahbaz.files.wordpress.com/2018/04/dsc_0013.jpg?w=788" /></p>
<p>The event started with a brief introduction of speakers and then I started the explaining the difference between Virtual Reality, Augmented Reality and Mixed Reality. Also Why we need these technologies?</p>
<p><img alt="_DSC3335" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1073" src="https://alamshahbaz.files.wordpress.com/2018/04/dsc3335-1.jpg?w=788" /></p>
<p>Started with the Aframe Presentation slide to explain the basics of WebVR and A-frame. Students were really interested to know more about it.</p>

<a href="https://alamshahbaz.wordpress.com/2018/04/27/webvr-lpu/_dsc3346-2/"><img alt="" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail" height="100" src="https://alamshahbaz.files.wordpress.com/2018/04/dsc3346-1.jpg?w=150&amp;h=100" width="150" /></a>
<a href="https://alamshahbaz.wordpress.com/2018/04/27/webvr-lpu/dsc_0010/"><img alt="" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail" height="100" src="https://alamshahbaz.files.wordpress.com/2018/04/dsc_0010.jpg?w=150&amp;h=100" width="150" /></a>
<a href="https://alamshahbaz.wordpress.com/2018/04/27/webvr-lpu/dsc_0011/"><img alt="" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail" height="100" src="https://alamshahbaz.files.wordpress.com/2018/04/dsc_0011.jpg?w=150&amp;h=100" width="150" /></a>

<p>After a while, students were getting bored, so I started with Virtual Girlfriend story ( Prathamesh’s story it is ) to explain the difference of VR, AR, and MR. And what all application we can build and solve real problems.</p>
<div class="jetpack-video-wrapper"></div>
<p>The event was really good, students asked many questions related to Mozilla, it’s product and Open Source in general. Would love to visit again <img alt="🙂" class="wp-smiley" src="https://s0.wp.com/wp-content/mu-plugins/wpcom-smileys/twemoji/2/72x72/1f642.png" style="height: 1em;" /></p>
<p><img alt="DSC_0053" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1057" src="https://alamshahbaz.files.wordpress.com/2018/04/dsc_0053.jpg?w=788" /></p>
<p>Event pics can be found <a href="https://www.shortto.com/mozillaevent" rel="noopener">https://www.shortto.com/mozillaevent</a></p>]]>
  </description>
  <pubDate>Fri, 27 Apr 2018 05:59:03 +0000</pubDate>
  
</item>

<item>
  <title>Official Reps Blog - Rep of the Month – March 2018</title>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.mozilla.org/mozillareps/?p=537</guid>
  <link>https://blog.mozilla.org/mozillareps/2018/04/10/rep-of-the-month-march-2018/</link>
  <description>
    <![CDATA[<div class="d-editor-preview">
<p>Please join us in congratulating <a href="https://reps.mozilla.org/u/shahbaz/">Md Shahbaz Alam</a>, our Rep of the Month for March 2018!</p>
<p>Shahbaz is a Full Stack Developer and Tech Evangelist by profession. He loves to talk about WebVR and auth0, he single-handedly created a Mozilla community in his home town Ranchi once he moved there. He is a Reps Mentor, Reps Resource member and community builder and loves traveling, cooking, organizing/speaking at events/conferences.</p>
<p><img alt="db97f712472e32f666e6a7bdea7614da" height="500" src="https://discourse-paas-production-content.s3.amazonaws.com/original/3X/9/c/9cb1b9d6d8c754447cb8a7167e9de1e20104c719.jpeg" width="500" /></p>
<p>Recently Shahbaz has been speaking at <a href="https://alamshahbaz.wordpress.com/2018/03/28/virtual-reality-hackfest-iit-ism-dhanbad/">Virtual Reality @ Hackfest in Dhanbad</a> as well as at <a href="https://alamshahbaz.wordpress.com/2018/03/26/footprints-2018/">FootPrintsX8</a>. He also organized <a href="https://reps.mozilla.org/e/rust-hack-mits/">Rust hack MITS</a>. You can also read more about his contributions in 2017 in his <a href="https://alamshahbaz.wordpress.com/2018/03/06/mozilla-contribution-2017-thanks-to-mozilla-and-mozillians/">blog post</a>.</p>
<p>Thank you Shahbaz, keep rocking the open Web! <img alt=":tada:" class="emoji" src="https://cdn-production.discourse.mozilla-community.org/images/emoji/twitter/tada.png?v=5" title=":tada:" /> <img alt=":tada:" class="emoji" src="https://cdn-production.discourse.mozilla-community.org/images/emoji/twitter/tada.png?v=5" title=":tada:" /></p>
<p><a href="https://discourse.mozilla.org/t/rep-of-the-month-march-2018/27532">Head over to Discourse to congratulate him!</a></p>
</div>]]>
  </description>
  <pubDate>Tue, 10 Apr 2018 09:05:18 +0000</pubDate>
  
</item>

<item>
  <title>Michael Kohler - 10 Years as a Mozilla Volunteer</title>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">https://michaelkohler.info/2018/04/09/mozilla-10-years-mozillian/</guid>
  <link>https://michaelkohler.info/2018/04/09/mozilla-10-years-mozillian/</link>
  <description>
    <![CDATA[<p>March 10th, 2018 marked my 10 year anniversary as a Mozilla volunteer. I wanted to write this blog post for quite some time now, but as y</p>]]>
  </description>
  <pubDate>Mon, 09 Apr 2018 19:29:11 +0000</pubDate>
  
</item>

<item>
  <title>Md Shahbaz Alam - Virtual Reality @ Indian Institute of Technology (BHU)</title>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alamshahbaz.wordpress.com/?p=1023</guid>
  <link>https://alamshahbaz.wordpress.com/2018/04/09/virtual-reality-indian-institute-of-technology-bhu/</link>
  <description>
    <![CDATA[<p>Again trio has come together for a wonderful event. This time it was IIT-BHU. The event started with the introduction of the speakers, Shahbaz, Umesh and Prathamesh ( trio aka SUP ). Prathamesh started the session explaining the difference between VR, AR, and MR. People were amazed to know that they will be creating their VR experience after the brief presentation.</p>
<p>After Prathamesh, I talked about basics of WebVR and how easy it is to build in just a few lines of codes.</p>
<p><img alt="Screenshot from 2018-04-09 23-30-28.png" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1046" src="https://alamshahbaz.files.wordpress.com/2018/04/screenshot-from-2018-04-09-23-30-28.png?w=788" /></p>
<p>The hacking began with remixing Hello World example on glitch.</p>
<p>In this blog, I’ll be using more pics to describe what happened in the event.</p>
<div class="wp-caption alignnone" id="attachment_1040" style="width: 970px;"><img alt="30411972_1767850706615216_1382256102330073088_n" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1040" src="https://alamshahbaz.files.wordpress.com/2018/04/30411972_1767850706615216_1382256102330073088_n.jpg?w=788" /><p class="wp-caption-text" id="caption-attachment-1040">How many of you know Virtual Reality?</p></div>
<p> </p>

<a href="https://alamshahbaz.wordpress.com/2018/04/09/virtual-reality-indian-institute-of-technology-bhu/30415176_1767851866615100_6830931062340714496_n/"><img alt="" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail" height="100" src="https://alamshahbaz.files.wordpress.com/2018/04/30415176_1767851866615100_6830931062340714496_n.jpg?w=150&amp;h=100" width="150" /></a>
<a href="https://alamshahbaz.wordpress.com/2018/04/09/virtual-reality-indian-institute-of-technology-bhu/30412338_1767852739948346_2512713914366558208_n/"><img alt="" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail" height="100" src="https://alamshahbaz.files.wordpress.com/2018/04/30412338_1767852739948346_2512713914366558208_n.jpg?w=150&amp;h=100" width="150" /></a>
<a href="https://alamshahbaz.wordpress.com/2018/04/09/virtual-reality-indian-institute-of-technology-bhu/30415649_1767852503281703_6555136832714047488_n/"><img alt="" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail" height="100" src="https://alamshahbaz.files.wordpress.com/2018/04/30415649_1767852503281703_6555136832714047488_n.jpg?w=150&amp;h=100" width="150" /></a>
<a href="https://alamshahbaz.wordpress.com/2018/04/09/virtual-reality-indian-institute-of-technology-bhu/30441239_1767851299948490_4446010459597832192_n/"><img alt="" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail" height="100" src="https://alamshahbaz.files.wordpress.com/2018/04/30441239_1767851299948490_4446010459597832192_n.jpg?w=150&amp;h=100" width="150" /></a>

<p>WebVR mentors helping participants in solving their problems.</p>
<p> </p>

<a href="https://alamshahbaz.wordpress.com/2018/04/09/virtual-reality-indian-institute-of-technology-bhu/30265151_1767851563281797_6771791273935241216_n/"><img alt="" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail" height="100" src="https://alamshahbaz.files.wordpress.com/2018/04/30265151_1767851563281797_6771791273935241216_n.jpg?w=150&amp;h=100" width="150" /></a>
<a href="https://alamshahbaz.wordpress.com/2018/04/09/virtual-reality-indian-institute-of-technology-bhu/30441638_1767852939948326_7705285308866101248_n/"><img alt="" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail" height="100" src="https://alamshahbaz.files.wordpress.com/2018/04/30441638_1767852939948326_7705285308866101248_n.jpg?w=150&amp;h=100" width="150" /></a>
<a href="https://alamshahbaz.wordpress.com/2018/04/09/virtual-reality-indian-institute-of-technology-bhu/30531011_1767852109948409_2935770679808622592_n/"><img alt="" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail" height="100" src="https://alamshahbaz.files.wordpress.com/2018/04/30531011_1767852109948409_2935770679808622592_n.jpg?w=150&amp;h=100" width="150" /></a>
<a href="https://alamshahbaz.wordpress.com/2018/04/09/virtual-reality-indian-institute-of-technology-bhu/30414698_1767852759948344_3856214989186531328_n/"><img alt="" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail" height="100" src="https://alamshahbaz.files.wordpress.com/2018/04/30414698_1767852759948344_3856214989186531328_n.jpg?w=150&amp;h=100" width="150" /></a>
<a href="https://alamshahbaz.wordpress.com/2018/04/09/virtual-reality-indian-institute-of-technology-bhu/30440663_1767851249948495_1474246321761157120_n/"><img alt="" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail" height="100" src="https://alamshahbaz.files.wordpress.com/2018/04/30440663_1767851249948495_1474246321761157120_n.jpg?w=150&amp;h=100" width="150" /></a>

<p>Participants helping each other and more focus on the challenge. Yes, we do have our famous WebVR contest here too. Best scenes get an A-frame tee.</p>

<a href="https://alamshahbaz.wordpress.com/2018/04/09/virtual-reality-indian-institute-of-technology-bhu/30415294_1767853283281625_5747484953008930816_n/"><img alt="" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail" height="100" src="https://alamshahbaz.files.wordpress.com/2018/04/30415294_1767853283281625_5747484953008930816_n.jpg?w=150&amp;h=100" width="150" /></a>
<a href="https://alamshahbaz.wordpress.com/2018/04/09/virtual-reality-indian-institute-of-technology-bhu/30411685_1767851459948474_6878517689367658496_n/"><img alt="" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail" height="100" src="https://alamshahbaz.files.wordpress.com/2018/04/30411685_1767851459948474_6878517689367658496_n.jpg?w=150&amp;h=100" width="150" /></a>
<a href="https://alamshahbaz.wordpress.com/2018/04/09/virtual-reality-indian-institute-of-technology-bhu/30516036_1767851779948442_7291559896745508864_n/"><img alt="" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail" height="100" src="https://alamshahbaz.files.wordpress.com/2018/04/30516036_1767851779948442_7291559896745508864_n.jpg?w=150&amp;h=100" width="150" /></a>
<a href="https://alamshahbaz.wordpress.com/2018/04/09/virtual-reality-indian-institute-of-technology-bhu/30412228_1767851539948466_8412135762128011264_n/"><img alt="" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail" height="100" src="https://alamshahbaz.files.wordpress.com/2018/04/30412228_1767851539948466_8412135762128011264_n.jpg?w=150&amp;h=100" width="150" /></a>

<p>Time to see the VR experience on the headset. Participants loved their first experience and the best part was, they were seeing their own imagination and faces show all.</p>

<a href="https://alamshahbaz.wordpress.com/2018/04/09/virtual-reality-indian-institute-of-technology-bhu/30412497_1767853709948249_7538065026393833472_n/"><img alt="" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail" height="100" src="https://alamshahbaz.files.wordpress.com/2018/04/30412497_1767853709948249_7538065026393833472_n.jpg?w=150&amp;h=100" width="150" /></a>
<a href="https://alamshahbaz.wordpress.com/2018/04/09/virtual-reality-indian-institute-of-technology-bhu/30414970_1767853723281581_1179580632901091328_n/"><img alt="" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail" height="100" src="https://alamshahbaz.files.wordpress.com/2018/04/30414970_1767853723281581_1179580632901091328_n.jpg?w=150&amp;h=100" width="150" /></a>
<a href="https://alamshahbaz.wordpress.com/2018/04/09/virtual-reality-indian-institute-of-technology-bhu/30264857_1767853289948291_4022191792727261184_n/"><img alt="" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail" height="100" src="https://alamshahbaz.files.wordpress.com/2018/04/30264857_1767853289948291_4022191792727261184_n.jpg?w=150&amp;h=100" width="150" /></a>

<p>Playing with the LEAP, <span class="st"><em>Leap</em> Motion’s hand tracking technology is designed to be embedded directly into VR/AR headsets.</span></p>
<p> </p>
<div class="wp-caption alignnone" id="attachment_1025" style="width: 970px;"><img alt="30516200_1767852283281725_6949116751166570496_n" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1025" src="https://alamshahbaz.files.wordpress.com/2018/04/30516200_1767852283281725_6949116751166570496_n.jpg?w=788" /><p class="wp-caption-text" id="caption-attachment-1025">Trio with IIT-BHU Event Team</p></div>
<p> </p>
<p>Following are the Scenes created by participants:</p>

<a href="https://alamshahbaz.wordpress.com/2018/04/09/virtual-reality-indian-institute-of-technology-bhu/screenshot-from-2018-04-09-23-52-36/"><img alt="" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail" height="76" src="https://alamshahbaz.files.wordpress.com/2018/04/screenshot-from-2018-04-09-23-52-36.png?w=150&amp;h=76" width="150" /></a>
<a href="https://alamshahbaz.wordpress.com/2018/04/09/virtual-reality-indian-institute-of-technology-bhu/screenshot-from-2018-04-09-23-51-11/"><img alt="" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail" height="74" src="https://alamshahbaz.files.wordpress.com/2018/04/screenshot-from-2018-04-09-23-51-11.png?w=150&amp;h=74" width="150" /></a>
<a href="https://alamshahbaz.wordpress.com/2018/04/09/virtual-reality-indian-institute-of-technology-bhu/screenshot-from-2018-04-09-23-50-46/"><img alt="" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail" height="76" src="https://alamshahbaz.files.wordpress.com/2018/04/screenshot-from-2018-04-09-23-50-46.png?w=150&amp;h=76" width="150" /></a>
<a href="https://alamshahbaz.wordpress.com/2018/04/09/virtual-reality-indian-institute-of-technology-bhu/screenshot-from-2018-04-09-23-50-33/"><img alt="" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail" height="75" src="https://alamshahbaz.files.wordpress.com/2018/04/screenshot-from-2018-04-09-23-50-33.png?w=150&amp;h=75" width="150" /></a>
<a href="https://alamshahbaz.wordpress.com/2018/04/09/virtual-reality-indian-institute-of-technology-bhu/screenshot-from-2018-04-09-23-50-07/"><img alt="" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail" height="76" src="https://alamshahbaz.files.wordpress.com/2018/04/screenshot-from-2018-04-09-23-50-07.png?w=150&amp;h=76" width="150" /></a>
<a href="https://alamshahbaz.wordpress.com/2018/04/09/virtual-reality-indian-institute-of-technology-bhu/screenshot-from-2018-04-09-23-49-47/"><img alt="" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail" height="76" src="https://alamshahbaz.files.wordpress.com/2018/04/screenshot-from-2018-04-09-23-49-47.png?w=150&amp;h=76" width="150" /></a>

<p>Visit the following link to experience the beauty of the WebVR.</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://wheat-gold.glitch.me/" rel="nofollow">https://wheat-gold.glitch.me/</a></li>
<li><a href="https://picayune-rainbow.glitch.me/" rel="nofollow">https://picayune-rainbow.glitch.me/</a></li>
<li><a href="https://capable-bonsai.glitch.me/" rel="nofollow">https://capable-bonsai.glitch.me/</a></li>
<li><a href="https://fortune-area.glitch.me/" rel="nofollow">https://fortune-area.glitch.me/</a></li>
<li><a href="https://picayune-rainbow.glitch.me/" rel="nofollow">https://picayune-rainbow.glitch.me/</a></li>
<li><a href="https://capable-bonsai.glitch.me/" rel="nofollow">https://capable-bonsai.glitch.me/</a></li>
<li><a href="https://ruby-number.glitch.me/" rel="nofollow">https://ruby-number.glitch.me/</a></li>
<li><a href="https://cherry-raven.glitch.me/" rel="nofollow">https://cherry-raven.glitch.me/</a></li>
<li><a href="https://thirsty-drawer.glitch.me/" rel="nofollow">https://thirsty-drawer.glitch.me/</a></li>
<li><a href="https://misty-jasmine.glitch.me/" rel="nofollow">https://misty-jasmine.glitch.me/</a></li>
<li><a href="https://stormy-bow.glitch.me/" rel="nofollow">https://stormy-bow.glitch.me/</a></li>
<li><a href="https://marked-double.glitch.me/" rel="nofollow">https://marked-double.glitch.me/</a></li>
<li><a href="https://planet-pan.glitch.me/" rel="nofollow">https://planet-pan.glitch.me/</a></li>
<li><a href="https://versed-button.glitch.me/" rel="nofollow">https://versed-button.glitch.me/</a></li>
<li><a href="https://dazzling-attempt.glitch.me/" rel="nofollow">https://dazzling-attempt.glitch.me/</a></li>
<li><a href="http://confused-kitty.glitch.me/" rel="nofollow">http://confused-kitty.glitch.me/</a></li>
<li><a href="https://handsome-sunflower.glitch.me/" rel="nofollow">https://handsome-sunflower.glitch.me/</a></li>
<li><a href="https://hospitable-brian.glitch.me/" rel="nofollow">https://hospitable-brian.glitch.me/</a></li>
<li><a href="https://fair-lan.glitch.me/" rel="nofollow">https://fair-lan.glitch.me/</a></li>
<li><a href="https://elated-duke.glitch.me/" rel="nofollow">https://elated-duke.glitch.me/</a></li>
<li><a href="https://quixotic-detective.glitch.me/" rel="nofollow">https://quixotic-detective.glitch.me/</a></li>
<li><a href="https://pool-mallet.glitch.me/" rel="nofollow">https://pool-mallet.glitch.me/</a></li>
</ul>
<p>It was a wonderful event, really love the enthusiasm of the participants. Full pack auditorium is what you often see in colleges. Will be in the loop with the participants and will be bringing them to the next stage.</p>
<div class="wp-caption alignnone" id="attachment_1024" style="width: 970px;"><img alt="30264892_1767851166615170_2645475936216023040_n" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1024" src="https://alamshahbaz.files.wordpress.com/2018/04/30264892_1767851166615170_2645475936216023040_n.jpg?w=788" /><p class="wp-caption-text" id="caption-attachment-1024">Yup, we are back again and will be seen again.</p></div>
<p> </p>]]>
  </description>
  <pubDate>Mon, 09 Apr 2018 18:25:31 +0000</pubDate>
  
</item>

<item>
  <title>Official Reps Blog - Reps of the Month – February 2018</title>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.mozilla.org/mozillareps/?p=535</guid>
  <link>https://blog.mozilla.org/mozillareps/2018/04/01/reps-of-the-month-february-2018/</link>
  <description>
    <![CDATA[<div class="d-editor-preview">
<p>Please join us in congratulating <a href="https://reps.mozilla.org/u/ziggymaes/">Ziggy Maes</a> and <a href="https://reps.mozilla.org/u/Anthony/">Anthony Maton</a>, our Reps of the Month for February 2018!</p>
<h1>Ziggy</h1>
<p>Ziggy is a long time Mozillian that is involved in organizing our presence at FOSDEM or managing the volunteers at the Mozilla Festival. Together with Anthony he started working on both <a href="https://discourse.mozilla.org/t/fosdem-2018-call-for-papers/21453">finding speakers for the DevRoom</a> but also to be sure we have <a href="https://discourse.mozilla.org/t/fosdem-2018-call-for-volunteers/23327">a good presence at the booth too</a>. This work was spread around 3 months so we are definitely grateful for their effort.</p>
<p><a href="https://scontent.ftsr1-1.fna.fbcdn.net/v/t1.0-9/13321817_1128016540577216_7677615269855043556_n.jpg?_nc_cat=0&amp;oh=4ab2e763c35135e8d5fb2219d69f1dff&amp;oe=5B318567" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"> <img src="https://scontent.ftsr1-1.fna.fbcdn.net/v/t1.0-9/13321817_1128016540577216_7677615269855043556_n.jpg?_nc_cat=0&amp;oh=4ab2e763c35135e8d5fb2219d69f1dff&amp;oe=5B318567" /> </a></p>
<h1>Anthony</h1>
<p>Anthony is pretty fresh in the Reps role but he has been a Mozillian for a long time now. Part of he Belgium community, he engages with the Francophone community at the same. His latest big effort was organizing Mozilla’s activities at FOSDEM together with Ziggy, both the <a href="https://discourse.mozilla.org/t/fosdem-2018-call-for-papers/21453">call for speakers for the DevRoom</a> and our <a href="https://discourse.mozilla.org/t/fosdem-2018-call-for-volunteers/23327">presence at the booth</a> during those two days.</p>
<p><img alt="jpg%20large" height="500" src="https://discourse-paas-production-content.s3.amazonaws.com/original/3X/5/d/5d09b097b04e9f672421f7bd7ac15ce6a02280c3.jpg" width="375" /></p>
<p>Thank you Ziggy and Anthony, keep rocking the open Web!</p>
<p><a href="https://discourse.mozilla.org/t/reps-of-the-month-february-2018/27260">Join us in congratulating them on Discourse!</a></p>
</div>]]>
  </description>
  <pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2018 14:36:02 +0000</pubDate>
  
</item>

<item>
  <title>Bhuvana Meenakshi Koteeswaran - A day as a speaker @ SRMkzilla</title>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://kbmtechie.wordpress.com/?p=132</guid>
  <link>https://kbmtechie.wordpress.com/2018/04/01/a-day-as-a-speaker-srmkzilla/</link>
  <description>
    <![CDATA[<p> </p>
<p><strong>Date: 24<sup>th</sup> March,2018</strong></p>
<p><strong>Venue: SRM University, Chennai</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">The day started with the inauguration by the chief guest, Mr. Raaman. It was an interesting talk on Linux forum and how open source plays the real trend in today’s world. I was very glad and proud to be amidst of great speakers who were very much senior to me in age and also in experience.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><img alt="photo_2018-09-10_13-18-24.jpg" class="  wp-image-276 aligncenter" height="196" src="https://kbmtechie.files.wordpress.com/2018/04/photo_2018-09-10_13-18-24.jpg?w=196&amp;h=196" width="196" /></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">My session happened in the second half slot and I initially gave a small pitching about my talk and audience who were interested to know more took part in my session. Surprisingly, I had 50+ enthusiastic audiences who were very keen to know the tricks and magic hidden in WebXR. I shared my in detail on how WebXR works followed by definitions on WebVR, WebAR and WebMR. Furthermore, I amused my participants with my demos and gave them an idea on how this technology can be used in real time for useful applications. Moreover, I shared about the WebVR Challenge and how to approach the same.</p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>

<a href="https://kbmtechie.wordpress.com/2018/04/01/a-day-as-a-speaker-srmkzilla/photo_2018-04-01_18-06-57/#main"><img alt="" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail" height="100" src="https://kbmtechie.files.wordpress.com/2018/04/photo_2018-04-01_18-06-57.jpg?w=150&amp;h=100" width="150" /></a>
<a href="https://kbmtechie.wordpress.com/2018/04/01/a-day-as-a-speaker-srmkzilla/photo_2018-04-01_18-06-44/#main"><img alt="" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail" height="113" src="https://kbmtechie.files.wordpress.com/2018/04/photo_2018-04-01_18-06-44.jpg?w=150&amp;h=113" width="150" /></a>

<p style="text-align: justify;">Finally, it was a different experience and I happened to gather around lot more knowledge through the sessions handled by my co-speaker viz.,</p>
<ul style="text-align: justify;">
<li><strong>Jayesh on Rust</strong></li>
<li><strong>Sayaji on privacy</strong></li>
<li><strong>Anand on QA</strong></li>
<li><strong>Viswaprasath on Web-extensions</strong></li>
<li><strong>Mehul on Auth0</strong></li>
<li><strong>Karthikeyan on Anscible</strong></li>
<li><strong>Janani on R language </strong></li>
</ul>
<p> </p>

<a href="https://kbmtechie.wordpress.com/2018/04/01/a-day-as-a-speaker-srmkzilla/photo_2018-04-01_18-05-54/#main"><img alt="" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail" height="84" src="https://kbmtechie.files.wordpress.com/2018/04/photo_2018-04-01_18-05-54.jpg?w=150&amp;h=84" width="150" /></a>
<a href="https://kbmtechie.wordpress.com/2018/04/01/a-day-as-a-speaker-srmkzilla/photo_2018-04-01_18-05-47/#main"><img alt="" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail" height="84" src="https://kbmtechie.files.wordpress.com/2018/04/photo_2018-04-01_18-05-47.jpg?w=150&amp;h=84" width="150" /></a>

<p style="text-align: justify;">These people  were amazing and it was worth networking with them. The day ended perfect and thanks to all the coordinators of  the SRMkzilla who made this a grand event.</p>
<div class="embed-twitter">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Great time spent with my cospeakers <a href="https://twitter.com/iamVP7?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@iamVP7</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hellokarthic?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@hellokarthic</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/dinesh_mv?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@dinesh_mv</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/jayeshkattar?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@jayeshkattar</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/imSriramB?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@imSriramB</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/rowdymehul?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@rowdymehul</a> and many. <a href="https://t.co/dSXedsnk7M">pic.twitter.com/dSXedsnk7M</a></p>
<p>— Bhuvana Meenakshi (@bhuvanakotees1) <a href="https://twitter.com/bhuvanakotees1/status/977513314187067393?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">March 24, 2018</a></p></blockquote>
<p></p></div>]]>
  </description>
  <pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2018 13:04:04 +0000</pubDate>
  
</item>

<item>
  <title>Md Shahbaz Alam - Virtual Reality @ Hackfest, IIT (ISM) Dhanbad</title>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alamshahbaz.wordpress.com/?p=1010</guid>
  <link>https://alamshahbaz.wordpress.com/2018/03/28/virtual-reality-hackfest-iit-ism-dhanbad/</link>
  <description>
    <![CDATA[<p>HackFest is IIT(ISM) Dhanbad’s 36-hour annual hackathon organized by the Computer Science and Engineering Society (CSES) and ACM Student Chapter, IIT(ISM) Dhanbad.</p>
<p>The event started with an introduction of speakers. <a href="https://reps.mozilla.org/u/prathamesh/">Prathamesh</a>, <a href="https://reps.mozilla.org/u/umesh/">Umesh</a>, and <a href="https://reps.mozilla.org/u/shahbaz/">Shahbaz</a> ( yep it’s me ), since we had limited time with us. So it was a quick talk-demo-workshop.</p>
<p><img alt="FB_IMG_1522232299546" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1014" src="https://alamshahbaz.files.wordpress.com/2018/03/fb_img_1522232299546.jpg?w=788" /></p>
<p>Prathamesh started with his favorite virtual girlfriend story to explain the concept of  Virtual Reality, Augmented Reality and Mixed Reality. After a long and tiring hackathon, the audience seems interested and was into it.</p>
<p><img alt="FB_IMG_1522232272809" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1015" src="https://alamshahbaz.files.wordpress.com/2018/03/fb_img_1522232272809.jpg?w=788" /></p>
<p>I talked about the basics of WebVR, why we brought the VR on Web and what are their advantages. Used Kevin’s presentation for explaining the concept in details with his amazing presentation (<a href="https://aframevr.github.io/aframe-presentation-kit/" rel="nofollow">https://aframevr.github.io/aframe-presentation-kit/</a>).</p>
<p>After explaining what WebVR is, we asked participants to visit <a href="https://aframe.io/" rel="nofollow">https://aframe.io/</a> and remix the hello world example on  <a href="http://glitch.com/" rel="nofollow">http://glitch.com/</a></p>
<p> </p>

<a href="https://alamshahbaz.wordpress.com/2018/03/28/virtual-reality-hackfest-iit-ism-dhanbad/photo6177018611193981025/"><img alt="" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail" height="84" src="https://alamshahbaz.files.wordpress.com/2018/03/photo6177018611193981025.jpg?w=150&amp;h=84" width="150" /></a>
<a href="https://alamshahbaz.wordpress.com/2018/03/28/virtual-reality-hackfest-iit-ism-dhanbad/photo6177018611193981011/"><img alt="" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail" height="84" src="https://alamshahbaz.files.wordpress.com/2018/03/photo6177018611193981011.jpg?w=150&amp;h=84" width="150" /></a>
<a href="https://alamshahbaz.wordpress.com/2018/03/28/virtual-reality-hackfest-iit-ism-dhanbad/fb_img_1522232305675/"><img alt="" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail" height="100" src="https://alamshahbaz.files.wordpress.com/2018/03/fb_img_1522232305675.jpg?w=150&amp;h=100" width="150" /></a>

<div class="jetpack-video-wrapper"></div>
<p>Due to the limited amount of time, participants couldn’t finish their idea. So we gave them a contest, where top 5 scenes will get a surprise gift from us.</p>
<p>And here comes, what we love most. After event photograph with the participants.</p>
<p><img alt="FB_IMG_1522232311427" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1017" src="https://alamshahbaz.files.wordpress.com/2018/03/fb_img_1522232311427.jpg?w=788" /></p>
<p>We will be seen together soon in IIT-BHU.</p>
<p><img alt="photo6177165099643545606" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1012" src="https://alamshahbaz.files.wordpress.com/2018/03/photo6177165099643545606.jpg?w=788" /></p>]]>
  </description>
  <pubDate>Wed, 28 Mar 2018 15:15:53 +0000</pubDate>
  
</item>

<item>
  <title>Md Shahbaz Alam - Footprints 2018</title>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alamshahbaz.wordpress.com/?p=998</guid>
  <link>https://alamshahbaz.wordpress.com/2018/03/26/footprints-2018/</link>
  <description>
    <![CDATA[<p>WebMR is a new technology which is in its initial stages. WebMR was the thing which has brought a huge participation at Baroda.</p>
<p>Everyone was eagerly waiting for us. Event started with a brief introduction of the speakers. Prathamesh Chavan and I talked about our love to open source.</p>

<a href="https://alamshahbaz.wordpress.com/2018/03/26/footprints-2018/img_20180224_103016_bokeh/"><img alt="" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail" height="113" src="https://alamshahbaz.files.wordpress.com/2018/03/img_20180224_103016_bokeh.jpg?w=150&amp;h=113" width="150" /></a>
<a href="https://alamshahbaz.wordpress.com/2018/03/26/footprints-2018/img_20180224_095537/"><img alt="" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail" height="84" src="https://alamshahbaz.files.wordpress.com/2018/03/img_20180224_095537.jpg?w=150&amp;h=84" width="150" /></a>

<p>Prathamesh talked about the differences of WebVR WebAR and WebMR. His way of relating things to virtual girlfriend has brought a new spark in attendees.</p>
<p><img alt="IMG_20180224_134118" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1003" src="https://alamshahbaz.files.wordpress.com/2018/03/img_20180224_134118.jpg?w=788" /></p>
<p> </p>
<p>I talked about basics of Virtual reality and why we have brought the VR on Web. And how easy it is to code and experience the same.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><img alt="IMG_20180224_145209" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1001" src="https://alamshahbaz.files.wordpress.com/2018/03/img_20180224_145209.jpg?w=788" /><br />
<img alt="IMG_20180224_093838" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1008" src="https://alamshahbaz.files.wordpress.com/2018/03/img_20180224_093838.jpg?w=788" /><img alt="IMG_20180224_103742" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1005" src="https://alamshahbaz.files.wordpress.com/2018/03/img_20180224_103742.jpg?w=788" /><br />
Lunch time, we went to Nosh Farmaiye, best place in town for chicken kebabs. Must place to visit when you’re in town.</p>
<p><img alt="IMG_20180224_123451" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1004" src="https://alamshahbaz.files.wordpress.com/2018/03/img_20180224_123451.jpg?w=788" /></p>
<p>After the lunch we started the hand-on session of WebVR . And to do so nothing is better than a hello world example. We have used glitch to live demo the scenes.</p>
<p>First day concluded with the prize distribution to the top 5 teams.</p>
<p><img alt="IMG_20180225_085802" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-999" src="https://alamshahbaz.files.wordpress.com/2018/03/img_20180225_085802.jpg?w=788" /></p>
<p>Second day started with WebAR, I explained the differences and similarities in AR and VR. Here again started with hello world example using hero marker.<br />
And talked about new features of AR and VR.</p>

<a href="https://alamshahbaz.wordpress.com/2018/03/26/footprints-2018/img_20180224_160339/"><img alt="" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail" height="84" src="https://alamshahbaz.files.wordpress.com/2018/03/img_20180224_160339.jpg?w=150&amp;h=84" width="150" /></a>
<a href="https://alamshahbaz.wordpress.com/2018/03/26/footprints-2018/img_20180224_142250/"><img alt="" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail" height="84" src="https://alamshahbaz.files.wordpress.com/2018/03/img_20180224_142250.jpg?w=150&amp;h=84" width="150" /></a>

<p>Definitely one day we would do a full session on WebMR.</p>]]>
  </description>
  <pubDate>Mon, 26 Mar 2018 17:23:45 +0000</pubDate>
  
</item>

<item>
  <title>Bhuvana Meenakshi Koteeswaran - My first talk on WebXR</title>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://kbmtechie.wordpress.com/?p=128</guid>
  <link>https://kbmtechie.wordpress.com/2018/03/18/my-first-talk-on-webxr/</link>
  <description>
    <![CDATA[<p> </p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Date: 17.03.2018</strong></p>
<p><strong>Venue : PES University, Bangalore, India.</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">This was my first presentation on WebXR as my previous talks were mostly focused on WebVR and projects related to it. There were around 150+ enthusiastic participants who actively participated in this event.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><img alt="IMG_20180317_160448.jpg" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-281" height="284" src="https://kbmtechie.files.wordpress.com/2018/03/img_20180317_160448.jpg?w=758" width="379" /></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">The morning first half session, I briefed about Mozilla and its projects. As the students haven’t come across Mozilla rather than its Firefox browser, I got this platform to rightly propagate about the community and how they can involve themselves in volunteer contributions both as individual and as an institution.  I mainly emphasized on:</p>
<ul>
<li>Add-ons/ Webextensions</li>
<li>Localisation</li>
<li>SuMo</li>
<li>QA</li>
<li>WebVR</li>
<li>Mozilla Mixed reality</li>
</ul>
<p style="text-align: justify;">The forenoon second half session involved a deep dive into WebXR. I found the audience struck with surprise on how technology has rapidly grown and how Mozilla is also into the competition.  After giving a detailed notion on WebXR I showed a few demos on my contributions to WebVR and WebAR.</p>
<div class="embed-twitter">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Showed my demos on WebVR and WebAR <a href="https://twitter.com/aframevr?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@aframevr</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/mozillaTN?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@mozillaTN</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/mozilla?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@mozilla</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/WebVRrocks?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@WebVRrocks</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/MozillaIN?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@MozillaIN</a> <a href="https://t.co/WfE95NU0J2">pic.twitter.com/WfE95NU0J2</a></p>
<p>— Bhuvana Meenakshi (@bhuvanakotees1) <a href="https://twitter.com/bhuvanakotees1/status/975020250642001920?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">March 17, 2018</a></p></blockquote>
<p></p></div>
<p style="text-align: justify;">During the intervals the students got a chance to experience Virtual Reality world using VR googles.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">There was a feedback form to be filled by my audience and based on this I was about to predict the count of participants for my afternoon session. To my surprise almost 80% of the attendees came forward for the hands-on session.</p>
<div class="embed-twitter">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Hands-on session was energetic followed by a small contest <a href="https://twitter.com/aframevr?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@aframevr</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/WebVRrocks?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@WebVRrocks</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/mozillareality?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@mozillareality</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/mozilla?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@mozilla</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/MozillaIN?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@MozillaIN</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/mozillaTN?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@mozillaTN</a> <a href="https://t.co/UcBCF4i52Z">pic.twitter.com/UcBCF4i52Z</a></p>
<p>— Bhuvana Meenakshi (@bhuvanakotees1) <a href="https://twitter.com/bhuvanakotees1/status/974999641233092609?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">March 17, 2018</a></p></blockquote>
<p></p></div>
<p style="text-align: justify;">I initially helped with two different Hello World programs using A-frame. Later I hosted a mini hackathon that is, to create a WebVR or WebAR application on either “<strong>Informative Pokemon world</strong>” or “<strong>Press for Progress-International Women’s day 2018</strong>”.  Almost everyone gave a very unique try and within 30 minutes they were competing enthusiastically. Finally, I got the tiresome task of choosing the winner of the contest and I appreciated them with A-frame T-shirts. The students were indeed glad to take away the swags and were contented for the time they had invested.</p>
<div class="embed-twitter">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Experiments tried out by the attendees which I admired <a href="https://twitter.com/aframevr?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@aframevr</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/mozillaTN?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@mozillaTN</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/mozilla?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@mozilla</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/WebVRrocks?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@WebVRrocks</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/mozillareality?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@mozillareality</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/MozillaIN?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@MozillaIN</a> <a href="https://t.co/nMomvgHc3F">pic.twitter.com/nMomvgHc3F</a></p>
<p>— Bhuvana Meenakshi (@bhuvanakotees1) <a href="https://twitter.com/bhuvanakotees1/status/975034667194753025?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">March 17, 2018</a></p></blockquote>
<p></p></div>
<p> </p>
<div class="embed-twitter">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Winners of the contest were rewarded!Scenes on 'Pokémon world' and 'Press for Progress' @aframevr@mozillaTN@mozilla@MozillaIN@mozillareality <a href="https://t.co/AdP1nT1CkZ">pic.twitter.com/AdP1nT1CkZ</a></p>
<p>— Bhuvana Meenakshi (@bhuvanakotees1) <a href="https://twitter.com/bhuvanakotees1/status/975001726867595265?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">March 17, 2018</a></p></blockquote>
<p></p></div>
<p> </p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">My sincere thanks to the Computer Science department of PES University, Bangalore for helping me to get the happiness, because true satisfaction comes only in sharing. Also the coordinators and volunteers did a perfect job to make this show a grand success.</p>]]>
  </description>
  <pubDate>Sun, 18 Mar 2018 17:12:22 +0000</pubDate>
  
</item>

<item>
  <title>Sanyam Khurana - International Women's Day with WoMoz in Delhi</title>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">tag:www.sanyamkhurana.com,2018-03-15:blog/womoz-international-womens-day-delhi.html</guid>
  <link>https://www.sanyamkhurana.com/blog/womoz-international-womens-day-delhi.html</link>
  <description>
    <![CDATA[<p>We all know that every year, 8th March is celebrated as International Women's Day. It is a focal point in the movement for women's rights. On this occasion, all the Open Source communities in and around Delhi came forward to hold a mega-meetup to encourage more women to take active part in Open Source &amp; Tech on March 10, 2018.</p>
<p>We were astonished to see the huge turn around of 180 people including 150+ women participants.</p>
<img alt="Group photo of all attendees" src="http://www.sanyamkhurana.com/blog/feeds/images/womoz-womens-day-1.jpg" />
<p>Mozilla Delhi, PyDelhi, PyLadies Delhi, LinuxChix India, Women Who Code Delhi, Women Who Go Delhi, Women Techmakers Delhi, and Women in Machine Learning and Data Science were the communities helped up in shaping the event.</p>
<p>Here are some of the volunteers who helped to make the event possible</p>
<img alt="Group photo of volunteers" src="http://www.sanyamkhurana.com/blog/feeds/images/womoz-womens-day-2.jpeg" />
<p>We had 3 main technical talks which were all presented by Women having a decade of experience working in the technical field. Apart from that, we had several other lightening talks and community talks.</p>
<img alt="Group photo of volunteers" src="http://www.sanyamkhurana.com/blog/feeds/images/womoz-womens-day-3.jpg" />
<p><a class="reference external" href="https://twitter.com/a2batic">Kanika</a> gave a lightening talk on "WoMoz" &amp; encouraged students to contribute to Mozilla.</p>
<img alt="Group photo of volunteers" src="http://www.sanyamkhurana.com/blog/feeds/images/womoz-womens-day-4.jpg" />
<p>Later, <a class="reference external" href="https://twitter.com/ErSanyamKhurana">I got a chance to</a> give a lightening talk on "Why you should contribute to Open Source", to help &amp; encourage folks to contribute to Open Source projects.</p>
<img alt="Group photo of volunteers" src="http://www.sanyamkhurana.com/blog/feeds/images/womoz-womens-day-5.jpg" />
<p>I want to thank everyone who helped with the event &amp; Adobe for sponsoring the venue. Don't forget to join the Open Source groups in &amp; around Delhi that you're interested in. As always, if you need any help on contributing, drop me a mail at Sanyam [at] SanyamKhurana [dot] com.</p>
<p>You can check out more <a class="reference external" href="https://drive.google.com/drive/folders/1pIUUpHB-HW1tw4asoLxpZ1c2-fQONpOt">photos of the event from here</a></p>]]>
  </description>
  <pubDate>Wed, 14 Mar 2018 21:21:00 +0000</pubDate>
  
</item>

<item>
  <title>Tanzeel Khan - Discussion: Aadhaar and Right to Privacy in India @ Delhi NCR</title>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://khantanzeel.wordpress.com/?p=592</guid>
  <link>https://khantanzeel.wordpress.com/2018/03/09/discussion-aadhaar-and-right-to-privacy-in-india-delhi-ncr/</link>
  <description>
    <![CDATA[<p>To assess the status of Aadhaar Campaign in India and plan future initiatives to safeguard the right to privacy in India, a Talk Session was held at SpringHouse Gurugram on March 9 2018. Senior Global Policy Manager of Mozilla Jochai Ben along with his colleagues and the members of Mozilla India Community in Delhi discussed the … <a class="more-link" href="https://khantanzeel.wordpress.com/2018/03/09/discussion-aadhaar-and-right-to-privacy-in-india-delhi-ncr/">Continue reading <span class="screen-reader-text">Discussion: Aadhaar and Right to Privacy in India @ Delhi NCR</span></a></p>]]>
  </description>
  <pubDate>Fri, 09 Mar 2018 05:23:30 +0000</pubDate>
  
</item>

<item>
  <title>Robert Reyes - Three (03) Mozilla Talks in a Week!</title>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.bobreyes.com/myblog/?p=5481</guid>
  <link>https://www.bobreyes.com/myblog/three-03-mozilla-talks-in-a-week/</link>
  <description>
    <![CDATA[<p>I was able to squeeze delivery of three (03) Mozilla talks during the week of 05 to 11 February 2018. To chronicle what has transpired during these three (03) events, I have this blog post… Prof. Belay Montes’ Class at UP Diliman I was invited by Prof. Belay Montes to give a technology talk to […]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.bobreyes.com/myblog/three-03-mozilla-talks-in-a-week/" rel="nofollow">Three (03) Mozilla Talks in a Week!</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.bobreyes.com/myblog" rel="nofollow">Bob Reyes Dot Com</a>.</p>]]>
  </description>
  <pubDate>Wed, 07 Mar 2018 07:08:04 +0000</pubDate>
  
</item>

<item>
  <title>Official Reps Blog - New Review Team Member 2018</title>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.mozilla.org/mozillareps/?p=533</guid>
  <link>https://blog.mozilla.org/mozillareps/2018/03/06/new-review-team-member-2018/</link>
  <description>
    <![CDATA[<p>Hi amazing Reps!</p>
<p>We’re so very happy to announce the new Review Team members who have just been officially on boarded. Welcome <a href="https://reps.mozilla.org/u/michaelkohler/">Michael</a>, <a href="https://reps.mozilla.org/u/pushpita_dey/">Pushpita</a>, <a href="https://reps.mozilla.org/u/hashrocket/">Jason</a>, and <a href="https://reps.mozilla.org/u/thephoenixbird/">Arturo</a> to the team!</p>
<p><a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/106119858@N08/39942940414/in/dateposted-public/" title="Review Team 2018"><img alt="Review Team 2018" class="aligncenter" height="500" src="https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4607/39942940414_565c388009.jpg" width="500" /></a>The Review Team is a specialized group responsible in reviewing and approving or rejecting every budget requests made by Mozilla Reps. This team is working in close coordination and supervision of Reps Council. The new Review Team will replace the old members and team up with the 3 remaining members to continue the work for a year. You can check more information about The Review Team in this <a href="https://wiki.mozilla.org/ReMo/Review_Team">wiki page</a>.</p>
<p>Last but not least, I would also like to thank and appreciate the previous Review Team members <a href="https://reps.mozilla.org/u/alamanda/">Dian Ina</a>, <a href="https://reps.mozilla.org/u/priynag/">Priyanka</a>, <a href="https://reps.mozilla.org/u/FaisalAziz/">Faisal</a>, and <a href="https://reps.mozilla.org/u/Flore/">Flore</a> for all their contribution for the past year in the Review Team. Your contribution &amp; dedication has been a great help for the program so far. We can’t thank you enough for that.</p>
<p>Please join me to congratulate all of them on the <a href="https://discourse.mozilla.org/t/new-review-team-member-2018/26318">Discourse topic</a>!</p>]]>
  </description>
  <pubDate>Tue, 06 Mar 2018 13:31:07 +0000</pubDate>
  
</item>

<item>
  <title>Md Shahbaz Alam - Maker Fest 2018</title>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alamshahbaz.wordpress.com/?p=982</guid>
  <link>https://alamshahbaz.wordpress.com/2018/03/06/maker-fest-2018/</link>
  <description>
    <![CDATA[<p><a href="http://makerfest.com">Makerfest</a> has been a place to explore and learn from all the makers and collaborators. This is my 2nd consecutive year as Volunteer from Mozilla India. This time I was there to represent Auth0 and talk about its service.</p>
<p>I joined the Mozilla booth for the WebVR session, a joint session taken by <a href="https://reps.mozilla.org/u/prathamesh/">Prathamesh</a> and me. We talked about the Virtual Reality on Web and played with the sample codes. Not to forget the VR experience provided to the attendees.</p>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en"><a href="https://twitter.com/mdsbzalam?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@mdsbzalam</a> with the <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/WebVR?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#WebVR</a> demo. <img alt="🕶" class="wp-smiley" src="https://s0.wp.com/wp-content/mu-plugins/wpcom-smileys/twemoji/2/72x72/1f576.png" style="height: 1em;" /><a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/MozillaAtMF18?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#MozillaAtMF18</a> <a href="https://t.co/eLFzWTyJsk">pic.twitter.com/eLFzWTyJsk</a></p>
<p>— Mozilla Gujarat (@mozguj) <a href="https://twitter.com/mozguj/status/949583630183022593?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">January 6, 2018</a></p></blockquote>
<p><code>Doing good is part of our code.</code></p>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="ro">Exploring Best of Mozilla VR <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/MozillaAtMF18?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#MozillaAtMF18</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/makerFest2018?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#makerFest2018</a> <a href="https://t.co/rMBIyMDb8Y">pic.twitter.com/rMBIyMDb8Y</a></p>
<p>— Nilima Chavan (@NilimaC04) <a href="https://twitter.com/NilimaC04/status/949586834501316608?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">January 6, 2018</a></p></blockquote>
<p> </p>
<p>It was a wonderful event, happy to come back next year again.</p>
<p>For detail report of this event, please follow <a href="http://www.rowdymehul.com/mozilla/maker-fest-2018/">Mehul’s blog</a></p>
<p>This is how the booth looked. <a class="twitter-hashtag pretty-link js-nav" href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/MozillaAtMF18?src=hash"><s>#</s><b><strong>MozillaAtMF18</strong></b></a></p>
<p><img alt="DS7Su3CXkAApMep.jpg:large.jpeg" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-984" src="https://alamshahbaz.files.wordpress.com/2018/03/ds7su3cxkaapmep-jpglarge.jpeg?w=788" /></p>]]>
  </description>
  <pubDate>Tue, 06 Mar 2018 07:15:15 +0000</pubDate>
  
</item>

<item>
  <title>Viswaprasath KS - Prayatna 2018</title>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://vp7techie.wordpress.com/2018/03/05/prayatna-2018/</guid>
  <link>https://vp7techie.wordpress.com/2018/03/05/prayatna-2018/</link>
  <description>
    <![CDATA[<p>Prayatna is one of the prime Technical fest organised by MIT, Anna University Chennai. It is an yearly where the number of students participating will be very high.</p>
<p>This year our community organized One day workshop of WebExtension. This time Balaji who developed amazing Add-ons previously and student from SRM University came forward to give session about his Add-ons and the WebExtension API he has used.</p>
<p>We started the session at 10:30 AM. First I gave talk on what are the different areas of Contribution where students can focus and which will be helpful to imrpove their professional skill set. Then I was giving the introduction of WebExtension.</p>
<p><img alt="WebExtension workshop at Prayatna" src="https://iamvp7.github.io//assets/2018/IMG_20180303_111115.jpg" /></p>
<p>By afternoon we gave a general introduction about what is WexExtension. After the lunch session Balaji started explaning his WebExtension <a href="https://addons.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/addon/live-editor/?src=search">Live Editor</a></p>
<p>After that we went for small Hands-on Session.  In this session we were using Commands API to build our own custom commands.</p>
<p>Around 50+ students attended the session. Around 30+ received the follow up Email. It was one of the diverse group of students. Students across tamilnadu came. The reach about Mozilla community is good and many were interested to know about FSA program.</p>]]>
  </description>
  <pubDate>Mon, 05 Mar 2018 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  
</item>

<item>
  <title>Viswaprasath KS - KGiSL Mozactivate 2018</title>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://vp7techie.wordpress.com/2018/03/02/kgisl-mozactivate-2018/</guid>
  <link>https://vp7techie.wordpress.com/2018/03/02/kgisl-mozactivate-2018/</link>
  <description>
    <![CDATA[<p>KGiSL community space is very close to every Mozillian around Tamilnadu, we had our first meetup there. There are lot of events related to Mozilla and open source communities happen at this space. After so long time I got opportunity to come to this space and share my knowledge about the WebExtension.</p>
<p>For this event, I personally started training 6 students before the event. My main goal is to make sure they are in good position to explore more about WebExtensions and answer the questions which are asked by their friends during session. It is like Train the trainers. We in Mozilla India community are doing great job by developing many WebExtensions but at the same time the number of trainers are less and it started increasing slowly in past few days.</p>
<p>On the event day around 35 students appeared, the attendence was very less due to the Job Fair  happening in the city all of the sudden. Till Friday evening there were good amount of registration but sudden announcement of Job fair made Final year and Third year students to go there. They are the main audience of the session. But some of them turned up.</p>
<p>During this session I was discussing about ContextMenu, as the students will be more interested to hack them compared to any other API. The students present were able to grasp the knowledge very quickly. One of the interesting thing happned to me for the first time is, I have to work without computer; yes on that day I was using the Black board to teach students and this is the first time I am doing it. Explaining using Black board was very interesting and I was very happy to do it.</p>
<p><img alt="WebExtension workshop at KGiSL" src="https://iamvp7.github.io//assets/2018/Kgisl_hack.jpg" /></p>
<p>I was excited to know two of the attendees developed their extension and pushed them to AMO.</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/ShankarDhandapani/WebExtensions">Translator</a></li>
<li><a href="https://addons.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/addon/search-selection/">Search</a></li>
</ul>
<p><a href="https://mozillatn.github.io/KiTE/blog/KGISL-ADDON-Hack">Blog post by KGiSL club</a></p>
<p>Most intersting and must needed part is, Sriram created Video about his extension, how he developed and explained his code, how to run it in browser. This is one of the great job done. I used to suggest many students about this, and Many techspeakers are now focusing on creating video tutorials, thanks to Sriram as he started at this early time.</p>
<p></p><div class="jetpack-video-wrapper"></div><p></p>
<p>In future I will be collobrating with this students and planning to continue creating more vidoes about WebExtensions.  This will be really helpful and we can bring more students as TechSpeakers in future.</p>]]>
  </description>
  <pubDate>Fri, 02 Mar 2018 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  
</item>

<item>
  <title>Sanyam Khurana - MozAMU: Mozilla Addons Development at AMU</title>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">tag:www.sanyamkhurana.com,2018-03-01:blog/mozilla-addons-dev-amu.html</guid>
  <link>https://www.sanyamkhurana.com/blog/mozilla-addons-dev-amu.html</link>
  <description>
    <![CDATA[<p>It all started with PyCon India. I met a few students of Aligarh Muslim University who were trying to teach about FOSS in their college. A few them were already contributing to <a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/coala/coala">Coala</a>. We talked a bit and they were discussing problems they were facing to run that community. I already started a Mozilla community at my college in the earlier days. Since I brought up a lot of folks from my college community in the event, we together discussed <em>How to nurture FOSS communities in college</em> as part of PyCon India Open Spaces. Here is a glimpse of the same:</p>
<img alt="PyCon India Open Spaces on how to nurture FOSS communities in college" class="align-center" src="http://www.sanyamkhurana.com/blog/feeds/images/moz-addons-amu-1.jpeg" />
<p>Later, these folks were excited and invited me as a speaker at their college. A lot of planning happened for the event and we were in touch almost daily for different things. We planned the event one and a half month in advance. Finally, on 24th Feb 2018, we decided to have a full-day event around FOSS at Aligarh Muslim University.</p>
<p>We left from Delhi at around 6:30 AM in the morning. We then halted at a cafe known as <cite>Break Point</cite> around Aligarh to have breakfast. We reached the university at around 10:20 AM.</p>
<p>We took some time to test the entire set-up and the event began at around 11:30 AM. I took the first session on <strong>Why you should contribute to Open Source</strong>. We discussed the question that somehow pops up sooner or later into everyone's mind while contributing to Open Source: <strong>What's in it for me?</strong>.</p>
<p>We discussed various pathways one can begin contributing to Open Source Projects like <strong>coding, writing docs, managing team, advocacy, documentation, translation, bug triaging, reviews, organization skills, soft skills</strong> &amp; tons of other things that come as a by-product.</p>
<img alt="Curious &amp; enthusiastic attendees learning about different contribution pathways in FOSS" class="align-center" src="http://www.sanyamkhurana.com/blog/feeds/images/moz-addons-amu-9.jpg" />
<p>You can find the slides here: <a class="reference external" href="http://sanyamkhurana.com/presentations/why-foss">Why you should contribute to Open Source?</a>.</p>
<img alt="Curious &amp; enthusiastic attendees at Mozilla AMU" class="align-center" src="http://www.sanyamkhurana.com/blog/feeds/images/moz-addons-amu-2.jpg" />
<p>We had a break for sometime and then started with the much awaited <strong>Add-ons session</strong>. Everyone was very excited to start learning to develop add-ons. I began with explaining the initial setup details &amp; discussed JSON briefly to bring everyone on the same page. To make most out of the event, We also organized a few events previously to teach basics of JavaScript &amp; JSON so that students so that they do not feel overwhelmed with the add-ons development.</p>
<img alt="Curious &amp; enthusiastic attendees learning from Sanyam Khurana (CuriousLearner)" class="align-center" src="http://www.sanyamkhurana.com/blog/feeds/images/moz-addons-amu-3.jpg" />
<p>Then Shashank (<a class="reference external" href="http://github.com/realslimshanky">@realslimshanky</a>) took over and discussed <tt class="docutils literal">manifest.json</tt> and it's importance. Later we developed a simple addon -- borderify, which displays a border on every site the user visits. Some students also modified their scripts to make their add-ons do different things and posted them on twitter. Shashank, me and Shivam Singhal (<a class="reference external" href="http://github.com/championshuttler">@championshuttler</a>) helped everyone with their problems during the development phase.</p>
<img alt="Curious &amp; enthusiastic attendees learning from Sanyam Khurana (CuriousLearner)" class="align-center" src="http://www.sanyamkhurana.com/blog/feeds/images/moz-addons-amu-4.jpg" />
<p>Since all of us are devs, we were able to quickly resolve queries of students. One of the most important things I noticed is that often people misspell either the name of their manifest file or some key in their manifest people resulting their add-on to not load during the debugging phase.</p>
<p>A lot of them then created addons on their own and modified their previously created borderify addon to do more stuff. I've tried to <a class="reference external" href="https://gist.github.com/CuriousLearner/1a4b08dbf642be8e4dfeb9544c9ab4c9">collect some of them here</a>. For a more verbose list you can visit Twitter and search tweets tagging me (<a class="reference external" href="http://twitter.com/ErSanyamKhurana">@ErSanyamKhurana</a> with <a class="reference external" href="https://twitter.com/search?q=%23MozAMU">#MozAMU</a>.</p>
<p>Imaginations ran wild and one of the attendee created an addon that replaces the word <tt class="docutils literal">Google</tt> with <tt class="docutils literal">Mozilla</tt> on every web page. You can see <a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/husainhz7/GoogleMozilla/">his hack here</a></p>
<p>To make the session more interesting we gave add-ons stickers to anyone who answers the question about what we were just telling them. A lot of folks praised and tweeted about the addons they were generating. We were able to generate <strong>10,000+ impressions with more than 4,000+ accounts reached on Twitter for #MozAMU</strong>.</p>
<img alt="Twitter Outreach report on no of impressions created for #MozAMU" class="align-center" src="http://www.sanyamkhurana.com/blog/feeds/images/moz-addons-amu-11.png" />
<img alt="Twitter Outreach report on top contributors created for #MozAMU" class="align-center" src="http://www.sanyamkhurana.com/blog/feeds/images/moz-addons-amu-12.png" />
<p>You can <a class="reference external" href="https://tweetreach.com/reports/20714737">read the full report here</a>.</p>
<p>Till this time, I never introduced to anyone about who am I and most importantly not listed any of my contributions in any of the projects. I don't want them to feel overwhelmed and assume that we people have some sort of superpowers that we're able to patch bugs in any FOSS project. I always make it a point to encourage them and help them land their first patch.</p>
<p>And my introduction summed that up in just one line <tt class="docutils literal">I'm one of you <span class="pre">--</span> a part of the community</tt>.</p>
<img alt="Sanyam Khurana (CuriousLearner) teaching about essential things to learn while contributing to FOSS projects" class="align-center" src="http://www.sanyamkhurana.com/blog/feeds/images/moz-addons-amu-13.png" />
<p>We then hopped on to discuss <strong>How do I start contributing to Open Source?</strong> where we specifically discussed <strong>How to find bugs on different projects through Bugzilla &amp; Bugsahoy</strong>.</p>
<img alt="Enthusiastic folks learning about contributions for Sanyam Khurana (CuriousLearner)" class="align-center" src="http://www.sanyamkhurana.com/blog/feeds/images/moz-addons-amu-7.jpg" />
<p>You can find the <a class="reference external" href="http://www.sanyamkhurana.com/presentations/foss/#/">slides here</a>. Then I discussed other Open Source projects I've contributed to like <em>CPython, Django, Oppia, Mozilla's Devtools, Gecko-Engine &amp; tried to find out similarities in various bug trackers.</em> We then had a group photo with some of the attendees.</p>
<img alt="Group photo at Mozilla AMU" class="align-center" src="http://www.sanyamkhurana.com/blog/feeds/images/moz-addons-amu-5.jpg" />
<p>It was already 5 PM and we didn't go for Lunch since students kept us busy with their questions during the lunch break too :P</p>
<img alt="Curious &amp; enthusiastic students asking questions in break" class="align-center" src="http://www.sanyamkhurana.com/blog/feeds/images/moz-addons-amu-8.jpg" />
<p>So, we decided to hop-on to a restaurant nearby with the core-team of students that helped in organizing the event with so much enthusiasm.</p>
<img alt="Curious &amp; enthusiastic attendees at Mozilla AMU" class="align-center" src="http://www.sanyamkhurana.com/blog/feeds/images/moz-addons-amu-10.jpg" />
<p>Then we clicked one last photo before leaving Aligarh at around 7:00 PM with the core-volunteers of the event who helped in all the preparations for the event.</p>
<img alt="Group photo Mozilla AMU" class="align-center" src="http://www.sanyamkhurana.com/blog/feeds/images/moz-addons-amu-6.jpg" />
<p>In the end, I would like to congratulate the students for making so wonderful arrangements and pushing up the FOSS community in their college. I hope they will now start landing patches in different FOSS projects &amp; we'll all meet again soon.</p>]]>
  </description>
  <pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 11:41:00 +0000</pubDate>
  
</item>

<item>
  <title>Mehul Patel - Maker Fest 2018</title>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.rowdymehul.com/?p=1502</guid>
  <link>http://www.rowdymehul.com/mozilla/maker-fest-2018/</link>
  <description>
    <![CDATA[<p><strong><a href="http://makerfest.com/">MakerFest</a></strong> has always been very closed to my heart because from here what my journey as a #Mozillian started and as result, this is my 2nd <span class="author-a-lr5p8oq6az72zuyz78zz86zz65zy">consecutive year as a Lead organizer and 3rd year as a volunteer from <a href="https://twitter.com/MozillaIN"><strong>Mozilla India</strong></a>. <img alt="😎" class="wp-smiley" src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/11/72x72/1f60e.png" style="height: 1em;" /></span></p>
<p><a href="https://i2.wp.com/www.rowdymehul.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/DSw_FUdWsAAQUHC.jpg-large.jpg"><img alt="" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1516" height="540" src="https://i2.wp.com/www.rowdymehul.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/DSw_FUdWsAAQUHC.jpg-large.jpg?resize=720%2C540" width="720" /></a></p>
<p><span class="author-a-lr5p8oq6az72zuyz78zz86zz65zy">This </span><span class="author-a-lr5p8oq6az72zuyz78zz86zz65zy">year, <strong><a href="https://www.makerfest.com/" rel="noopener">Makerfest</a></strong></span><span class="author-a-lr5p8oq6az72zuyz78zz86zz65zy"> is back with </span><span class="author-a-lr5p8oq6az72zuyz78zz86zz65zy">awesomeness upgrades – 150+ makers, 50 workshops, 25 awesome speakers, and </span><span class="author-a-lr5p8oq6az72zuyz78zz86zz65zy">30,000+ spectators.</span></p>
<p><strong>A Brief Introduction to Maker Fest:</strong></p>
<p>Maker Fest is the Indian continuation of Maker Faire hosted across America, Europe, Africa and Japan. Maker Faire, which launched in California in 2006, now hosts hundreds of thousand attendees. It is the amalgamation of festivals celebrating the innovators and an art show with booths for inventors, demonstrations, and workshops for attendees.</p>
<p><span class="author-a-lr5p8oq6az72zuyz78zz86zz65zy"><a href="https://blog.mozillaindia.org/1935"><strong> Mozilla India</strong></a> is partnering with India’s largest Maker Festival, <a href="https://reps.mozilla.org/e/mozilla-india-makerfest-18-ahmedabad/"><em><strong>Maker Fest 2018</strong></em></a> for the 5th consecutive year. <a href="https://blog.mozillaindia.org/1935">More</a></span><span id="more-1502"></span></p>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Proud partner of <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/MakerFest18?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#MakerFest18</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/MakerFest2018?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#MakerFest2018</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/MozillaAtMF18?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#MozillaAtMF18</a> Visit at stall No. 49 . <a href="https://t.co/TmPrVbL5rM">pic.twitter.com/TmPrVbL5rM</a></p>
<p>— Mozilla India (@MozillaIN) <a href="https://twitter.com/MozillaIN/status/949264417283235840?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">January 5, 2018</a></p></blockquote>
<p></p>
<p><strong>Maker Fest</strong> is about developing a great maker community where people can learn and share about making. Creators, artists and hobbyist across the country are invited to present their contemporary applications of ideas using the vast ocean of art, science and technology.</p>
<p>The schedule can be found <a href="https://public.etherpad-mozilla.org/p/remo-mozilla-india-makerfest-18-ahmedabad">here</a> :</p>
<blockquote><p>We are loaded with topics to interact with you on. Come soon if you haven’t, already and if you have, come again to interact anyway! <img alt="🙂" class="wp-smiley" src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/11/72x72/1f642.png" style="height: 1em;" /></p></blockquote>
<p><a href="https://i2.wp.com/www.rowdymehul.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/DS7Su3CXkAApMep.jpg-large.jpg"><img alt="" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1504" height="389" src="https://i2.wp.com/www.rowdymehul.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/DS7Su3CXkAApMep.jpg-large.jpg?resize=720%2C389" width="720" /></a></p>
<h4><strong>First, Let me introduced to you with my super energetic squad of Maker Fest 2018.</strong></h4>
<p><strong>Pranshu, Rishita</strong> and <strong>Prathamesh</strong> led the charge for <strong>#WebVR</strong> at the <strong>#MakerFest2018</strong>. Equipped with VR Demos, they helped people recognize the power to do more with simpler tools through <a href="https://aframe.io/"><strong>AFrame</strong></a>.</p>
<p><a href="https://i0.wp.com/www.rowdymehul.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/photo_2018-01-08_17-05-07.jpg"><img alt="" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1507" height="540" src="https://i0.wp.com/www.rowdymehul.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/photo_2018-01-08_17-05-07.jpg?resize=720%2C540" width="720" /></a></p>
<h5><strong>Some explored tweets :</strong></h5>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Experiencing the VR world <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/WebVR?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#WebVR</a> at <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/MakerFest2018?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#MakerFest2018</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/MozillaAtMF18?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#MozillaAtMF18</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/mozilla?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@mozilla</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/mozillareps?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@mozillareps</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/mozguj?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@mozguj</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/mozillareality?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@mozillareality</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/mozillavr?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@mozillavr</a> <a href="https://t.co/ThZbTag8Lh">pic.twitter.com/ThZbTag8Lh</a></p>
<p>— Mehul Patel (@rowdymehul) <a href="https://twitter.com/rowdymehul/status/949516817784913922?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">January 6, 2018</a></p></blockquote>
<p></p>
<p><strong>HariOm, Kamlesh, Nilima, Drashti</strong> and Haard have been working on <a href="https://pontoon.mozilla.org/"><strong>Pontoon</strong> </a>by contributing in their languages to make their favourite browser accessible for people who would want to use their browser in their favourite language! <img alt="❤" class="wp-smiley" src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/11/72x72/2764.png" style="height: 1em;" /></p>
<p><a href="https://i2.wp.com/www.rowdymehul.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/photo_2018-01-08_17-04-56.jpg"><img alt="" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1508" height="960" src="https://i2.wp.com/www.rowdymehul.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/photo_2018-01-08_17-04-56.jpg?resize=720%2C960" width="720" /></a></p>
<p>During the fest, our volunteers met different age groups and found one thing common is that <em><strong>‘Language matters on the internet</strong></em>‘ and that’s why Localization is the important part of the web where it will open doors for all age groups where language is no more barriers.</p>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="und">Language matters on Internet. We had group of college professor who wrote feedback in sanskrit- संस्कृतम् and Gujarati <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/MozillaAtMF18?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#MozillaAtMF18</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Makerfest2018?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#Makerfest2018</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/mozilla_l10n?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@mozilla_l10n</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/MakerFestMJFF?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@MakerFestMJFF</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/MozillaIN?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@MozillaIN</a> <a href="https://t.co/KZSry0Iswa">pic.twitter.com/KZSry0Iswa</a></p>
<p>— Drashti (@drashtipandya1) <a href="https://twitter.com/drashtipandya1/status/950628438460850176?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">January 9, 2018</a></p></blockquote>
<p></p>
<p><strong>Sameer, Viral</strong> and <strong>Pranjal</strong> helped people realize <em>Why Privacy Matters</em>, and how Privacy is a Priority in today’s age!</p>
<p><a href="https://i0.wp.com/www.rowdymehul.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/photo_2018-01-08_17-04-53.jpg"><img alt="" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1509" height="960" src="https://i0.wp.com/www.rowdymehul.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/photo_2018-01-08_17-04-53.jpg?resize=720%2C960" width="720" /></a></p>
<p>We strongly believe that it is necessary for the people who use the web for various purpose to stay safe by understanding the impact of their digital footprint.</p>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">"Lightbeam" demonstrations an Firefox add-on that uses interactive visualizations to show you the first and third party sites you interact with on the Web. <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/MozillaAtMF18?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#MozillaAtMF18</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/makerFest2018?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#makerFest2018</a> <a href="https://t.co/6qXigmShJT">pic.twitter.com/6qXigmShJT</a></p>
<p>— Nilima Chavan (@NilimaC04) <a href="https://twitter.com/NilimaC04/status/949536019501797376?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">January 6, 2018</a></p></blockquote>
<p></p>
<p>I’m being the only <strong><a href="https://www.rust-lang.org/en-US/">Rust</a></strong> Contributor in the Squad for the MakerFest made people ponder about how this new-age language is secure, versatile, light and fast, All-in-One! Thanks, <a href="https://www.instagram.com/mozillagram/"><strong>@mozillagram</strong></a> for featuring me &amp; team. <img alt="😍" class="wp-smiley" src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/11/72x72/1f60d.png" style="height: 1em;" /></p>
<p><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/BdsrpYggicQ/" target="_blank" title="View on Instagram"><img alt="Instagram Photo" src="http://instagr.am/p/BdsrpYggicQ/media/?size=l" /></a></p>
<p> </p>
<p><a href="https://www.rust-lang.org/en-US/">Rust</a> is a systems programming language sponsored by Mozilla Research, which describes it as a “safe, concurrent, practical language”, supporting functional and imperative-procedural paradigms.</p>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Talking about Rust <a href="https://twitter.com/MakerFestMJFF?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@MakerFestMJFF</a><a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/MozillaAtMF18?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#MozillaAtMF18</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/MakerFest18?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#MakerFest18</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/MozillaIN?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#MozillaIN</a> <a href="https://t.co/ws7PE1kSeW">pic.twitter.com/ws7PE1kSeW</a></p>
<p>— Jayesh Katta Ramalingaiah (@jayeshkattar) <a href="https://twitter.com/jayeshkattar/status/950393305811963904?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">January 8, 2018</a></p></blockquote>
<p></p>
<p>Feel free to ping me anytime on telegram or twitter and I’m happy to share amazing things about Rust.</p>
<p><strong>On Day 2</strong>, we also had a workshop on VR &amp; Aframe, <em>You might be wondering what is </em><a href="https://aframe.io/"><strong>Aframe</strong></a>?</p>
<p><span class="st">Aframe is a web framework for building virtual reality experiences. Make WebVR with HTML and Entity-Component. Works on Vive, Rift, desktop, mobile platforms. Get started <a href="https://aframe.io/docs/0.7.0/introduction/">here</a> :<br />
</span></p>
<h5><strong>Announcement :</strong></h5>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Mozilla AR/VR session at Ahemdabad University Sharp 2:30  <a href="https://twitter.com/MakerFestMJFF?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@MakerFestMJFF</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/mozguj?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@mozguj</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/MozillaAtMF18?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#MozillaAtMF18</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/makerFest2018?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#makerFest2018</a> <a href="https://t.co/OxAqrdkovy">pic.twitter.com/OxAqrdkovy</a></p>
<p>— Nilima Chavan (@NilimaC04) <a href="https://twitter.com/NilimaC04/status/949534053031645185?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">January 6, 2018</a></p></blockquote>
<p></p>
<h5><strong>People explored VR during the workshop :</strong></h5>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="ro">Exploring Best of Mozilla VR  <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/MozillaAtMF18?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#MozillaAtMF18</a>  <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/makerFest2018?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#makerFest2018</a> <a href="https://t.co/rMBIyMDb8Y">pic.twitter.com/rMBIyMDb8Y</a></p>
<p>— Nilima Chavan (@NilimaC04) <a href="https://twitter.com/NilimaC04/status/949586834501316608?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">January 6, 2018</a></p></blockquote>
<p></p>
<p>We had 3 amazing <strong>WoMoz</strong> in our squad this time and all 3 have done a splendid job. Kudos to you. <img alt="👏" class="wp-smiley" src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/11/72x72/1f44f.png" style="height: 1em;" /></p>
<p><a href="https://i2.wp.com/www.rowdymehul.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/DS9YaOnVwAAX7rq.jpg-large.jpg"><img alt="" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1515" height="405" src="https://i2.wp.com/www.rowdymehul.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/DS9YaOnVwAAX7rq.jpg-large.jpg?resize=720%2C405" width="720" /></a>Thanks Girls for making it more diverse. The best example is this question by Indian housewives.</p>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Best part of <a href="https://twitter.com/MakerFestMJFF?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@MakerFestMJFF</a> is diversity of visitors. When Indian house wives asked, how <a href="https://twitter.com/mozilla?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@mozilla</a> will help them in day to day life <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/MozillaAtMF18?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#MozillaAtMF18</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/MakerFest2018?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#MakerFest2018</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/mozguj?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@mozguj</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/MozillaIN?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@MozillaIN</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/WoMozilla?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@WoMozilla</a> <a href="https://t.co/epJDFfQrvf">pic.twitter.com/epJDFfQrvf</a></p>
<p>— Drashti (@drashtipandya1) <a href="https://twitter.com/drashtipandya1/status/950632832526880769?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">January 9, 2018</a></p></blockquote>
<p></p>
<p>During this fest, <strong>Antonela </strong>who is Designer at <a href="https://twitter.com/torproject">Tor Project</a> gave us a surprise visit at our stall and we had a great discussion about privacy over the web and how <a href="https://www.torproject.org"><strong>Tor</strong> </a>&amp; <a href="https://www.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/new/"><strong>Firefox</strong></a> browser makes the web a better and secure place. One more thing, she has a super awesome smile. <img alt="😀" class="wp-smiley" src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/11/72x72/1f600.png" style="height: 1em;" /></p>
<div class="wp-caption aligncenter" id="attachment_1514" style="width: 1288px;"><a href="https://i0.wp.com/www.rowdymehul.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/photo_2018-02-25_14-26-56.jpg"><img alt="" class="wp-image-1514 size-full" height="405" src="https://i0.wp.com/www.rowdymehul.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/photo_2018-02-25_14-26-56.jpg?resize=720%2C405" width="720" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text"><strong>                             <em>Sharing #MozLove &lt;3 @firefox</em></strong></p></div>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">With <a href="https://twitter.com/holantonela?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@holantonela</a> Designer at <a href="https://twitter.com/torproject?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@torproject</a>. Glad to meet you and looking forward to working with you <img alt="👍" class="wp-smiley" src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/11/72x72/1f44d.png" style="height: 1em;" /><img alt="✌" class="wp-smiley" src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/11/72x72/270c.png" style="height: 1em;" /> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/MozillaAtMF18?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#MozillaAtMF18</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Makerfest2018?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#Makerfest2018</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/mozilla?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@mozilla</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/MozillaIN?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@MozillaIN</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/mozguj?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@mozguj</a> <a href="https://t.co/FkbiUZ1jrr">pic.twitter.com/FkbiUZ1jrr</a></p>
<p>— Mehul Patel (@rowdymehul) <a href="https://twitter.com/rowdymehul/status/950348560419250177?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">January 8, 2018</a></p></blockquote>
<p></p>
<p>Really appreciate the work done by the all the volunteers. I believe, v<span class="_Tgc _s8w _y9e">olunteers are doing <b>good</b> for others and the community, which provides a natural sense of accomplishment and being the team lead I have seen that in them. </span></p>
<p><span class="_Tgc _s8w _y9e">Hey Team, your role as a <b>volunteer</b> can also give me a sense of pride and identity. Thanks for your all hard work and I hope you enjoyed volunteering this fest.  </span></p>
<p><strong>Volunteers experience :</strong></p>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">It was fun interacting with a diverse set of people at the <a href="https://twitter.com/MakerFestMJFF?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@MakerFestMJFF</a> last weekend. Thanks, <a href="https://twitter.com/mozguj?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@mozguj</a> for the opportunity to participate in such an amazing event! <img alt="♥" class="wp-smiley" src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/11/72x72/2665.png" style="height: 1em;" /><img alt="🦊" class="wp-smiley" src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/11/72x72/1f98a.png" style="height: 1em;" /><a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/MakerFest2018?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#MakerFest2018</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/MozillaAtMF18?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#MozillaAtMF18</a> <a href="https://t.co/1FTjG7d7Re">pic.twitter.com/1FTjG7d7Re</a></p>
<p>— Pranshu Khanna <img alt="🌐" class="wp-smiley" src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/11/72x72/1f310.png" style="height: 1em;" /> (@pransh15) <a href="https://twitter.com/pransh15/status/950636631211388928?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">January 9, 2018</a></p></blockquote>
<p></p>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">A great experience interacting with a diverse audience and encouraging everyone to use the high performance <a href="https://twitter.com/firefox?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@firefox</a> Quantum and  helping people know how they can contribute towards Mozilla's mission <a href="https://twitter.com/MakerFestMJFF?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@MakerFestMJFF</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/MozillaAtMF18?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#MozillaAtMF18</a><a href="https://twitter.com/mozilla?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@mozilla</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/MozillaIN?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@MozillaIN</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/mozguj?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@mozguj</a> <a href="https://t.co/dzsr3FojVk">pic.twitter.com/dzsr3FojVk</a></p>
<p>— Rishita Bansal (@risbansal) <a href="https://twitter.com/risbansal/status/951643844696621056?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">January 12, 2018</a></p></blockquote>
<p></p>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Had an knowledgeable day today.<a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/MakerFest2018?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#MakerFest2018</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/MozillaAtMF18?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#MozillaAtMF18</a> <a href="https://t.co/uhbyXXqhWu">pic.twitter.com/uhbyXXqhWu</a></p>
<p>— Sumed Mistry (@sumedmistry) <a href="https://twitter.com/sumedmistry/status/949683218713726976?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">January 6, 2018</a></p></blockquote>
<p></p>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Here is my blog on Maker fest <a href="https://t.co/c28F07g5xo">https://t.co/c28F07g5xo</a>   <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/MozillaAtMF18?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#MozillaAtMF18</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/MozillaIN?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@MozillaIN</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Makerfest2018?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#Makerfest2018</a></p>
<p>— Nilima Chavan (@NilimaC04) <a href="https://twitter.com/NilimaC04/status/953339010646028288?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">January 16, 2018</a></p></blockquote>
<p></p>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Amazing experience <img alt="😍" class="wp-smiley" src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/11/72x72/1f60d.png" style="height: 1em;" /><img alt="😍" class="wp-smiley" src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/11/72x72/1f60d.png" style="height: 1em;" /> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/MozillaAtMF18?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#MozillaAtMF18</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/MozillaIN?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#MozillaIN</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/MozLove?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#MozLove</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Mo?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#Mo</a> <a href="https://t.co/gLaIwMO3d0">pic.twitter.com/gLaIwMO3d0</a></p>
<p>— Hariom Panchal (@Hariompanchal_7) <a href="https://twitter.com/Hariompanchal_7/status/951127177365352448?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">January 10, 2018</a></p></blockquote>
<p></p>
<h5><strong><em>Pure Creativity</em></strong> <img alt="😍" class="wp-smiley" src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/11/72x72/1f60d.png" style="height: 1em;" /></h5>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Posters made by Volunteers &amp; more to come <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/MakerFest2018?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#MakerFest2018</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/NilimaC04?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@NilimaC04</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/drashtipandya?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@Drashtipandya</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/sameer_bhatt5?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@sameer_bhatt5</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/pransh15?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@pransh15</a> <a href="https://t.co/4yZdnOLkib">pic.twitter.com/4yZdnOLkib</a></p>
<p>— Kämłèšh Sãhü (@Kvilpura) <a href="https://twitter.com/Kvilpura/status/949196799683846144?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">January 5, 2018</a></p></blockquote>
<p></p>
<p>In my every event I am always seeking for feedback’s from participants/attendees/visitors, doesn’t matter its positive or negative because if you know the feedback you can definitely work on it to improve for next time to make it better.</p>
<p><strong>Why is Feedback important?</strong> so I believe Feedback <span class="_Tgc _s8w">allows us to build and maintain communication with others and t</span>he most important information collected from post-event surveys is whether attendees found value in the event, whether it was worth their investment of time and resources, and whether they would participate in the event again.</p>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Feedbacks by people at our booth in <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/MakerFest?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#MakerFest</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/MakerFest2018?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#MakerFest2018</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/MakerFest18?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#MakerFest18</a><a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/MozillaAtMF18?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#MozillaAtMF18</a> <a href="https://t.co/t8YM7h3b7r">pic.twitter.com/t8YM7h3b7r</a></p>
<p>— Mozilla Gujarat (@mozguj) <a href="https://twitter.com/mozguj/status/949921049587564545?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">January 7, 2018</a></p></blockquote>
<p></p>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Come, interact and give us a Feedback. <img alt="📝" class="wp-smiley" src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/11/72x72/1f4dd.png" style="height: 1em;" /><a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/MakerFest2018?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#MakerFest2018</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/MozillaAtMF18?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#MozillaAtMF18</a> <a href="https://t.co/fJPvji4kjy">pic.twitter.com/fJPvji4kjy</a></p>
<p>— Mozilla Gujarat (@mozguj) <a href="https://twitter.com/mozguj/status/949560987077705734?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">January 6, 2018</a></p></blockquote>
<p></p>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Reviews are flowing in at the <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/MakerFest2018?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#MakerFest2018</a>, for the Mozilla volunteers at <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/MozillaAtMF18?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#MozillaAtMF18</a>. <img alt="🌸" class="wp-smiley" src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/11/72x72/1f338.png" style="height: 1em;" /><img alt="♥" class="wp-smiley" src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/11/72x72/2665.png" style="height: 1em;" /> <a href="https://t.co/ORYynmMmv5">pic.twitter.com/ORYynmMmv5</a></p>
<p>— Mozilla Gujarat (@mozguj) <a href="https://twitter.com/mozguj/status/949542733210898432?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">January 6, 2018</a></p></blockquote>
<p></p>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Visitor feedback <a href="https://twitter.com/MakerFestMJFF?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@MakerFestMJFF</a>  <a href="https://twitter.com/mozilla?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@mozilla</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/mozamo?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@mozamo</a> <br />1."Want more mail trackers in Firefox" <br />2. "Many addons not compatible with quantum"<br />And when we introduce <a href="https://twitter.com/FirefoxFocus?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@FirefoxFocus</a> They said already in love with it <img alt="🙂" class="wp-smiley" src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/11/72x72/1f642.png" style="height: 1em;" /> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/MozillaAtMF18?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#MozillaAtMF18</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/MozillaIN?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@MozillaIN</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/mozguj?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@mozguj</a> <a href="https://t.co/GLFA9AlNGf">pic.twitter.com/GLFA9AlNGf</a></p>
<p>— Drashti (@drashtipandya1) <a href="https://twitter.com/drashtipandya1/status/950626618933903360?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">January 9, 2018</a></p></blockquote>
<p></p>
<p>The Squad for <strong>#MakerFest2018</strong> made sure people knew about the Web they are in, and how fast and far they can go if they go together. Often questioned, why are we doing this? We let them know that we are mere volunteers who are working to make the huge Web we are a part of, a healthier and a better place to be in! <img alt="❤" class="wp-smiley" src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/11/72x72/2764.png" style="height: 1em;" /></p>
<p><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/BdpF73tgbgM/" target="_blank" title="View on Instagram"><img alt="Instagram Photo" src="http://instagr.am/p/BdpF73tgbgM/media/?size=l" /></a></p>
<blockquote>
<h3>Divided by Regions.United by one Open Web.We are <a href="https://www.instagram.com/explore/tags/oneinamozillian/">#OneInAMozillian</a>!<img alt="❤" class="wp-smiley" src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/11/72x72/2764.png" style="height: 1em;" /></h3>
</blockquote>
<h5 style="text-align: center;"><em><strong>Hope you enjoyed my blog! <img alt="🙂" class="wp-smiley" src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/11/72x72/1f642.png" style="height: 1em;" /></strong></em></h5>
<p> </p>
<h4>Curious<em><strong> to know more?</strong></em>  Follow the #MozillaAtMF18 hashtag on social media.</h4>
<h3 style="text-align: center;"><strong>Full Album – MakerFest 2018!</strong></h3>
<p><a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/rowdymehul/albums/72157692194961864" title="Maker Fest 2018 by rowdymehul, on Flickr"><img alt="IMG_2495" height="427" src="https://i1.wp.com/farm5.staticflickr.com/4660/40045468271_ce9645b949_z.jpg?resize=640%2C427&amp;ssl=1" width="640" /></a></p>
<p> </p>]]>
  </description>
  <pubDate>Sun, 25 Feb 2018 19:04:19 +0000</pubDate>
  
</item>

<item>
  <title>Mehul Patel - GSIndia Summit 2017</title>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.rowdymehul.com/?p=1488</guid>
  <link>http://www.rowdymehul.com/mozilla/gsindia-summit-2017/</link>
  <description>
    <![CDATA[<p><span class="author-a-z82zz66zom553pz122zz88z4az65zfz84ze"><a href="https://girlscriptsummit.tech/"><strong>GirlScript India Summit</strong></a> – It is the first ever women oriented technical festival of India hosted by GirlScript Foundation. It is a platform where students get a chance to polish their skills and explore their potential. The Technical fest will comprise of Events, Exhibitions, Guest Lectures and a lot more, which aims to provide holistic exposure to students.</span></p>
<p>The India Summit will cover the highlights of ‘Technical Industry’ such as AI and Advanced Machine Learning, Intelligent Apps (Virtual Personal Assistance), Intelligent Things (Robots, Drones, and Autonomous Vehicles), Virtual and Augmented Reality, Blockchain, and Cryptocurrency. It will also include the finest speakers from the technology industry and some successful women entrepreneurs who would like to share their story with us and how it feels like to be a women entrepreneur in India.</p>
<p><span class="author-a-z82zz66zom553pz122zz88z4az65zfz84ze"><strong>Goal:</strong> Introduce <a href="https://www.rust-lang.org/">Rust</a>, WebVR with enthusiastic students, experts who came at this summit. Also, It is a 2-day event that comprises of students from different universities across the country. Moreover, It is a platform where students get a chance to polish their skills and explore their potential. The Technical fest will comprise of Events, Exhibitions, Guest Lectures and a lot more, which aims to provide holistic exposure to students.</span><span id="more-1488"></span></p>
<p>Being Mozillian,  I believed that this event has a good potential to spread Mozilla mission so <a href="https://reps.mozilla.org/e/girlscript-india-summit/">Mozilla Reps</a> have supported the event by giving a talk on Rust &amp; WebVR which are the most emerging technologies nowadays.</p>
<p><a href="https://i2.wp.com/www.rowdymehul.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/photo_2018-02-23_23-34-01.jpg"><img alt="" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1491" height="540" src="https://i2.wp.com/www.rowdymehul.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/photo_2018-02-23_23-34-01.jpg?resize=720%2C540" width="720" /></a></p>
<p>Me(<a href="https://reps.mozilla.org/u/rowdymehul/">Mehul Patel</a>) &amp; <a href="https://reps.mozilla.org/u/methwanishagufta/">Shagufta Methwani</a> are the speaker from Mozilla and gave a talk on Rust &amp; WebVR respectively.</p>

<a href="http://www.rowdymehul.com/mozilla/gsindia-summit-2017/attachment/photo_2018-02-23_23-27-48/#main"><img alt="" class="attachment-full size-full" height="1280" src="https://i0.wp.com/www.rowdymehul.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/photo_2018-02-23_23-27-48.jpg?fit=1280%2C1280" width="1280" /></a>
<a href="http://www.rowdymehul.com/mozilla/gsindia-summit-2017/attachment/photo_2018-02-23_23-27-43/#main"><img alt="" class="attachment-full size-full" height="1280" src="https://i2.wp.com/www.rowdymehul.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/photo_2018-02-23_23-27-43.jpg?fit=1279%2C1280" width="1279" /></a>

<p><span class="author-a-n8m2z75zz85z1z88zz69zi0fz76zz87z1c">Started my talk by introducing them to Rust and why I’m using Rust? I believe, Rust is new enough that you can write useful stuff that would have already existed in other languages. It also gives a relatively familiar tool to the modern C++ developers, but in the much more consistent and reliable ways.</span></p>
<p>I believe, new system programming language solves a lot of common system programming bugs. Moreover here we have Cargo: Rust Package manager which helps to Improve your toolkit. And, Its best for Self-learning &amp; always have fun to do.</p>
<p>Please read the full story <a href="http://www.rowdymehul.com/why-should-i-use-rust/" rel="noopener">here</a>, this may explain you, <em><strong>why you should use </strong></em>Rust?</p>
<p>Then, we move ahead did some practicals where I have shown them small demos from our <a href="https://github.com/rusthacks/RustHack/tree/master/short_demo" rel="noopener">Rust Kits.</a></p>
<p>Event flow and agenda can be found <a href="https://public.etherpad-mozilla.org/p/remo-girlscript-india-summit">here</a> :</p>
<p><em><strong>You can find my presentation via below tweet :</strong> </em></p>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Sharing my talk presentation for GIRLSCRIPT SUMMIT 2017 on <a href="https://twitter.com/rustlang?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@rustlang</a> SpeakerDeck: <a href="https://t.co/W5Qc8MvP4Z">https://t.co/W5Qc8MvP4Z</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/Girlscript1?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@Girlscript1</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/mozillareps?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@mozillareps</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/ThisWeekInRust?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@ThisWeekInRust</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/gsindiasummit?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#gsindiasummit</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/rustlang?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#rustlang</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/rusthacks?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#rusthacks</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/rustindia?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#rustindia</a></p>
<p>— Mehul Patel (@rowdymehul) <a href="https://twitter.com/rowdymehul/status/941565564220211200?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 15, 2017</a></p></blockquote>
<p></p>
<p>It was always fun to play with Rust and glad that participants also enjoyed while <strong>rusty</strong> their hand.</p>
<p><em><strong>Tweet from GS Foundation :</strong></em></p>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Meet Mozilla Reps, Mentors &amp; TechSpeakers at India's 1st Women Oriented Techfest GirlScript India Summit <a href="https://twitter.com/mozTechSpeakers?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@mozTechSpeakers</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/mozillareps?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@mozillareps</a> <img alt="😍" class="wp-smiley" src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/11/72x72/1f60d.png" style="height: 1em;" /> <a href="https://t.co/jKHNRgPeeL">pic.twitter.com/jKHNRgPeeL</a></p>
<p>— GirlScriptFoundation (@Girlscript1) <a href="https://twitter.com/Girlscript1/status/939450106201247744?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 9, 2017</a></p></blockquote>
<p></p>
<p><em><strong>Some tweets from attendees :</strong></em></p>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en"><a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/GSindiasummit?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#GSindiasummit</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/aframe?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#aframe</a> Looking forward to learn more about it! A great presentation by <a href="https://twitter.com/shaguftamethwan?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@shaguftamethwan</a> <a href="https://t.co/1SXLuknIHs">pic.twitter.com/1SXLuknIHs</a></p>
<p>— Devanshi Vaishnav (@e2c19c66ba6c416) <a href="https://twitter.com/e2c19c66ba6c416/status/941961272513331201?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 16, 2017</a></p></blockquote>
<p></p>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en"><a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Hackathon?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#Hackathon</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/gsindiasummit?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#gsindiasummit</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/Girlscript1?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@Girlscript1</a> READY! <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/excessdenied?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#excessdenied</a> <a href="https://t.co/9rgJ0QfOuC">pic.twitter.com/9rgJ0QfOuC</a></p>
<p>— Devanshi Vaishnav (@e2c19c66ba6c416) <a href="https://twitter.com/e2c19c66ba6c416/status/941963477379268608?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 16, 2017</a></p></blockquote>
<p></p>
<p>Rustceans, Auth0, Tech Speakers &amp; Mozillians in one frame! Yay<img alt="😍" class="Emoji Emoji--forText" height="42" src="https://i0.wp.com/abs.twimg.com/emoji/v2/72x72/1f60d.png?resize=42%2C42&amp;ssl=1" title="Smiling face with heart-shaped eyes" width="42" /><img alt="🤗" class="Emoji Emoji--forText" height="41" src="https://i2.wp.com/abs.twimg.com/emoji/v2/72x72/1f917.png?resize=41%2C41&amp;ssl=1" title="Hugging face" width="41" /></p>
<p><a href="https://i0.wp.com/www.rowdymehul.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/photo_2018-02-23_23-34-07.jpg"><img alt="" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1492" height="411" src="https://i0.wp.com/www.rowdymehul.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/photo_2018-02-23_23-34-07.jpg?resize=720%2C411" width="720" /></a><em><strong>                                               Hope you enjoyed my blog!</strong> </em><img alt="🙂" class="wp-smiley" src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/11/72x72/1f642.png" style="height: 1em;" /></p>]]>
  </description>
  <pubDate>Fri, 23 Feb 2018 18:34:23 +0000</pubDate>
  
</item>

<item>
  <title>Viswaprasath KS - GNUnify 2018</title>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://vp7techie.wordpress.com/2018/02/19/gnunify-2018/</guid>
  <link>https://vp7techie.wordpress.com/2018/02/19/gnunify-2018/</link>
  <description>
    <![CDATA[<p>GNUnify is one of the amazing event where each and every year Mozilla India community make sure to participate. GNUnify is an annual gathering consisting of Free and Open Source software workshops, talks, seminars and BOFs (Birds of a feather), hosted by the Pune Linux User Group(PLUG) and the Symbiosis Institute of Computer Studies and Research(SICSR) in Pune, India. It is an amazing opportunity for people from FOSS communities all over India to meet each other and a good chance for newbies to find out how to get involved in FOSS projects and learn more about the free and open source culture. Mozilla has been actively participating at GNUnify since 2008!</p>
<p><img alt="GNUnify tracks" src="https://iamvp7.github.io//assets/2018/gnunify_18.jpg" /></p>
<p>This year along with the Mozilla contributors around pune I got opportunity to organise a workshop on WebExtension at GNUnify 2018. One of the main reason for my visit is to bring some more contributors to WebExtension community and bring more webdevelopers into WebExtension development.</p>
<p>Our Mozilla track was very strong we had some many topics to cover</p>
<ul>
<li>VR session by Prathamesh</li>
<li>Marathi localization session by Narendra</li>
<li>Cook up Firefox- Privacy Settings by Ankit</li>
<li>Rust session by Mehul</li>
<li>Hardware track by Tripad</li>
<li>WebExtensions Workshop by Viswaprasath</li>
</ul>
<p>In one room we had talks and in another room I was organising workshop. It was jam packed and very tight schedule, we Mozillians were not able to talk till 3 PM.</p>
<p>I was very excitied to talk on GNUnify, from 2015 (I wanted to talk about FirefoxOS previously) I wanted to give talk there as it was one of the big event we have related to open source technologies in India. As I got opportunity this year I was very happy to delivery it there.</p>
<p>I reached the venue sharply at 9:50 and was having some discussion with volunteers about the event in past and how it grew, the story they had about this event was amazing and it gave some more energy to me. And we started my session at 10:15, I started why we need WebExtension and backgrounds of it. But 10:35 the whole lab was filled with Students and Professors (I remember talking to 3 professor at middle of session and around 50 were there).</p>
<p>After some thoughts on WebExtension I showed them the demo of my favorite extension (Youtube controller), shared the story behind it. People got excited to know why I developed it, and the next one was to search a particular word in different search engine sites.</p>
<p>Around 11:15 we started to have hands-on session. First I started explaning them explaning about manifest.json and what are all the mandatory keys and values that has to be present, once they get familiar with it I started explaning the background.js file which we coded for our “search add-on”, using contextmenu. I showed the code sample with duckduckgo, but some of them understood the logic and tried to bring their favorite search engines (like Google, youtube, bing, wikipedia). Then we had a small break.  After this we developed another add-on where we will be having our own custom shortcut keys for close the tab.</p>
<p>The attendees were interested to learn more on hacking WebExtension API. One of the amazing unique thing they felt is they are able to build similar to browser internal features. They wanted to dig more and bring some amazing Extensions in future. The response from faculty and students is amazing. I had personal talk with students for more than a hour  and got chance to talk with Faculty who is handling Web Programming session. She shared it is interesting session and told she will ping back to discuss how WebExtensions can be made into their college syllabus.</p>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Viswaprasath has started his workshop on Building one extension for all browsers with web extensions APIs! <a href="https://t.co/sFZZDO08Sa">pic.twitter.com/sFZZDO08Sa</a></p>
<p>— GNUnify (@gnunify) <a href="https://twitter.com/gnunify/status/964733175422377986?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">February 17, 2018</a></p></blockquote>
<p><a href="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js">https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js</a></p>
<p>In future I am sure, lot of amazing contributors will be coming as a effect of this event. One note which I came to know at the end of event is most of Reps from India who are present today came from this event.</p>
<p>I personally would like to thank all the Mozillians around Pune who made my day great and memorable one. Special thanks for the care shown by Prathamesh parenets, I didnt felt I am going for the first time to his home. The garden at their home is really good and well glued with nature. I am inspired a little bit by his father, may be in future will start gardening in my apartment.</p>]]>
  </description>
  <pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2018 07:39:00 +0000</pubDate>
  
</item>

<item>
  <title>Mehul Patel - Google DevFest Ahmedabad 2017</title>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.rowdymehul.com/?p=1476</guid>
  <link>http://www.rowdymehul.com/rust/google-devfest-ahmedabad-2017/</link>
  <description>
    <![CDATA[<p><strong>Google Developers Group (GDG)</strong> – is open and volunteer geek community who create exciting projects and share experience about Google technologies with a passion and GDG Ahmedabad is one of the most active &amp; passionate community.  The aim of GDG DevFest Ahmedabad is to bring the world-class experts in Mobile and Web technologies to Gujarat, India for 1 day of sessions, workshops and showcases.</p>
<div class="wp-caption aligncenter" id="attachment_1480" style="width: 1610px;"><a href="https://i2.wp.com/www.rowdymehul.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/Screenshot-2018-2-14-GDG-DevFest-Ahmedabad-20171.png"><img alt="" class="wp-image-1480 size-full" height="359" src="https://i2.wp.com/www.rowdymehul.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/Screenshot-2018-2-14-GDG-DevFest-Ahmedabad-20171.png?resize=720%2C359" width="720" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Courtesy : <a href="http://devfest.gdgahmedabad.com/"><strong><em>http://devfest.gdgahmedabad.com/</em></strong></a></p></div>
<p>This year I’m one of the rockstars (People usually calling me) speaker at Web track. <span class="author-a-n8m2z75zz85z1z88zz69zi0fz76zz87z1c">This is the first time <strong>Mozilla</strong> participated at <strong>GDG DevFest Ahmedabad</strong> The fest involved developers and professionals all around. I gave a talk on <a href="https://www.rust-lang.org/en-US/">Rust programming</a> which is one of emerging technologies and one of the major focus of Mozilla these days. </span><span id="more-1476"></span></p>
<p>This time I’m going to change my blog style and going to include some real-time tweets which can get through about, how the complete session went. So, Let’s find out.</p>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">A session on "Introduction to Rust" <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/DevFestAhm?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#DevFestAhm</a> <a href="https://t.co/nVWW6JqvBW">pic.twitter.com/nVWW6JqvBW</a></p>
<p>— Aditya (@beingadityak_) <a href="https://twitter.com/beingadityak_/status/927099961396944896?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 5, 2017</a></p></blockquote>
<p></p>
<p>Started my talk by introducing them to Rust and why I’m using Rust? I believe, Rust is new enough that you can write useful stuff that would have already existed in other languages. It also gives a relatively familiar tool to the modern C++ developers, but in the much more consistent and reliable ways.</p>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">The play begins <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Rush?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#Rush</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/DevFestAhm?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#DevFestAhm</a> by <a href="https://twitter.com/rowdymehul?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@rowdymehul</a> <a href="https://t.co/7MvfhRIjne">pic.twitter.com/7MvfhRIjne</a></p>
<p>— Charmi Chokshi (@CharmiChokshi) <a href="https://twitter.com/CharmiChokshi/status/927097523809820672?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 5, 2017</a></p></blockquote>
<p></p>
<p><a href="https://www.rust-lang.org/en-US/" rel="noopener"><b>Rust</b> </a>is a systems programming language that runs blazingly fast, prevents segfaults, and guarantees thread safety. But, in my opinion, “<em>Rust is a good choice when you’d choose C++. You can also say, “Rust is a systems programming language that pursuing the trifecta: safe, concurrent, and fast.” I would say, Rust is an ownership-oriented programming language.”</em></p>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">. <a href="https://twitter.com/rowdymehul?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@rowdymehul</a> from <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Mozilla?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#Mozilla</a> is speaking On " Let's play with <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Rust?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#Rust</a> " and making his <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/session?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#session</a> very interactive after heavy lunch. <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/DevFestAhm?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#DevFestAhm</a> <a href="https://t.co/zfaW59zluo">pic.twitter.com/zfaW59zluo</a></p>
<p>— Ronak Ganatra (@GanatraRonak) <a href="https://twitter.com/GanatraRonak/status/927098462197334016?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 5, 2017</a></p></blockquote>
<p></p>
<p><em>Normally</em> people became ‘<em>lazy</em>‘ or ‘<em>sleepy</em>‘ after having lunch and moreover, if you get delicious Gujarati food then you can’t resist yourself to have. Upon that my talk was the first in line after lunch break so to having that in mind I have changed my talk style and from the start only I have tried to make the session interactive so the audience can also be part and their mind can be diverted. Guess what, It worked and people loved the interaction period. All an all we have a very healthy conversation during the session.</p>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Let's Play with Rust: Friendly Introduction<br />By Mehul Patel <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/DevFestAhm?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#DevFestAhm</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/DevFest17?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#DevFest17</a> <a href="https://t.co/YtAK3LvRUN">pic.twitter.com/YtAK3LvRUN</a></p>
<p>— Dhruv Pandya (dp) (@dhruvpandyadp) <a href="https://twitter.com/dhruvpandyadp/status/927099785928097792?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 5, 2017</a></p></blockquote>
<p></p>
<p>I believe, new system programming language solves a lot of common system programming bugs. Moreover here we have Cargo: Rust Package manager which helps to Improve your toolkit. And, Its best for Self-learning &amp; always have fun to do.</p>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Rust is the Best System Programming Language wow.. <a href="https://twitter.com/rowdymehul?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@rowdymehul</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/DevFestAhm?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#DevFestAhm</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/DevFest17?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#DevFest17</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/GDG?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#GDG</a><a href="https://twitter.com/GDGAhmedabad?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@GDGAhmedabad</a></p>
<p>— Nai Vishal (@Vish_Luv_56) <a href="https://twitter.com/Vish_Luv_56/status/927098970404294656?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 5, 2017</a></p></blockquote>
<p></p>
<p>According to recent The Stack Overflow survey, Rust is the most beloved among developers of all programming languages and frameworks.</p>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en"><a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/DevFest17?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#DevFest17</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/DevFestAhm?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#DevFestAhm</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/GDGAhmedabad?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#GDGAhmedabad</a> Anyone have more stickers then this guy on their laptop? <a href="https://t.co/en9WBCzF5z">pic.twitter.com/en9WBCzF5z</a></p>
<p>— Mit Patel (@TechnicalMit) <a href="https://twitter.com/TechnicalMit/status/927097211028213761?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 5, 2017</a></p></blockquote>
<p></p>
<p>Well, I don’t think. <img alt="😛" class="wp-smiley" src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/11/72x72/1f61b.png" style="height: 1em;" /></p>
<p><span class="_Tgc _s8w"><b>Feedback</b> is always valuable information for me as that will be used to make improvements in your work and help me to boost to do even better.  </span></p>
<p>When you got feedback about your talk from some experts speakers :</p>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Going to know more about Rust at <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/DevfestAhm?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#DevfestAhm</a> interesting session by <a href="https://twitter.com/rowdymehul?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@rowdymehul</a></p>
<p>— Hiren Dave (@hjdave) <a href="https://twitter.com/hjdave/status/927096997311422464?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 5, 2017</a></p></blockquote>
<p></p>
<p>Some more feedback from participants  :</p>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Great Session on Rust by <a href="https://twitter.com/rowdymehul?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@rowdymehul</a> <br />Nd well Explained New System Programming Language Rust… <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/DevFestAhm?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#DevFestAhm</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/DevFest17?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#DevFest17</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/GDG?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#GDG</a><a href="https://twitter.com/GDGAhmedabad?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@GDGAhmedabad</a></p>
<p>— Nai Vishal (@Vish_Luv_56) <a href="https://twitter.com/Vish_Luv_56/status/927106151065403393?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 5, 2017</a></p></blockquote>
<p></p>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Great interactive session by <a href="https://twitter.com/rowdymehul?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@rowdymehul</a> on RUST. Thanks for the sticker BTW. Its been fun so far at <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/DevFestAhm?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#DevFestAhm</a>. <a href="https://twitter.com/GDGAhmedabad?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@GDGAhmedabad</a></p>
<p>— Shubham Pachori (@spachori94) <a href="https://twitter.com/spachori94/status/927100210450493440?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 5, 2017</a></p></blockquote>
<p></p>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Very informative session <a href="https://t.co/Kfwpl1zDMP">https://t.co/Kfwpl1zDMP</a></p>
<p>— Maulik Rathod (@maulikrathod17) <a href="https://twitter.com/maulikrathod17/status/927133923255005185?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 5, 2017</a></p></blockquote>
<p></p>
<p>We got more than 100+ tweets during the talk, you can track them by #DevFestAhm. A huge shout out to all the rock star social media contributors for helping <b>GDGAhmedabad</b> to rock on Twitter!</p>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">[<a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/DevFestAhm?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#DevFestAhm</a> Twitter Report]: </p>
<p>2k Tweets | 385 Contributors | 3,93,348 Reach | 33,60,021 Impressions!!!</p>
<p>A huge shout out to all the rock star social media contributors for helping <a href="https://twitter.com/GDGAhmedabad?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@GDGAhmedabad</a> rock on Twitter! Keep Calm, Keep Tweeting!</p>
<p>CC: <a href="https://twitter.com/pareshmayani?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@pareshmayani</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/gdg?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@gdg</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/GDGDevfest2017?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#GDGDevfest2017</a> <a href="https://t.co/tjJZ8Xh2t9">pic.twitter.com/tjJZ8Xh2t9</a></p>
<p>— Moin Shaikh (@moingshaikh) <a href="https://twitter.com/moingshaikh/status/927574644705468416?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 6, 2017</a></p></blockquote>
<p></p>
<p>In frame with some enthusiast attendees. <img alt="😀" class="wp-smiley" src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/11/72x72/1f600.png" style="height: 1em;" /></p>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Super awesome event with energetic attendees <a href="https://twitter.com/GDGAhmedabad?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@GDGAhmedabad</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/DevFest17?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#DevFest17</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/GDG?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#GDG</a> Cc: <a href="https://twitter.com/rustlang?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@rustlang</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/mozilla?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@mozilla</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/mozillareps?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@mozillareps</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/mozTechSpeakers?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@mozTechSpeakers</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/rustlang?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#rustlang</a> <a href="https://t.co/CskGYjedxQ">pic.twitter.com/CskGYjedxQ</a></p>
<p>— Mehul Patel (@rowdymehul) <a href="https://twitter.com/rowdymehul/status/927271453397012480?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 5, 2017</a></p></blockquote>
<p></p>
<p>This was the best memento ever, Thank you GDG team. <img alt="🙂" class="wp-smiley" src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/11/72x72/1f642.png" style="height: 1em;" /></p>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Thank you <a href="https://twitter.com/GDGAhmedabad?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@GDGAhmedabad</a> for this memento<img alt="😍" class="wp-smiley" src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/11/72x72/1f60d.png" style="height: 1em;" /> it was pleasure to be part of panel of speaker at <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/DevFest17?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#DevFest17</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/rustlang?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#rustlang</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/DevFestAhm?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#DevFestAhm</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/rustindia?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#rustindia</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/GDG?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#GDG</a> </p>
<p>Cc: <a href="https://twitter.com/rustlang?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@rustlang</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/mozTechSpeakers?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@mozTechSpeakers</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/mozillareps?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@mozillareps</a> <a href="https://t.co/jbrM2QTwuq">pic.twitter.com/jbrM2QTwuq</a></p>
<p>— Mehul Patel (@rowdymehul) <a href="https://twitter.com/rowdymehul/status/928574632709406720?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 9, 2017</a></p></blockquote>
<p></p>
<p><em>Missed Google DevFestAhm?</em></p>
<p><strong>Check out, 360 experience of our #DevFestAhm event, <em>here you go</em> :</strong></p>
<div class="jetpack-video-wrapper"></div>
<p style="text-align: center;"><em><strong>Hope you enjoyed my blog!</strong> </em><img alt="🙂" class="wp-smiley" src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/11/72x72/1f642.png" style="height: 1em;" /></p>]]>
  </description>
  <pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2018 08:29:48 +0000</pubDate>
  
</item>

<item>
  <title>Nino Vranesic - Embracing the improvement psychology</title>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.elnino.si/post/170845327967</guid>
  <link>http://blog.elnino.si/post/170845327967</link>
  <description>
    <![CDATA[What would you do if you could do it all the time? Everybody is the happiest when they are doing...]]>
  </description>
  <pubDate>Tue, 13 Feb 2018 21:04:20 +0000</pubDate>
  
</item>

<item>
  <title>Sanyam Khurana - Web Extensions, Womoz &amp; Privacy</title>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">tag:www.sanyamkhurana.com,2018-01-23:blog/web-extensions-womoz-privacy.html</guid>
  <link>https://www.sanyamkhurana.com/blog/web-extensions-womoz-privacy.html</link>
  <description>
    <![CDATA[<p>A Saturday well spent teaching students about Open Source, Add-ons and Privacy.</p>
<p>We had an activity at Indira Gandhi Delhi Technical University for Women (IGDTUW)
for Addons, WoMoz and Privacy.</p>
<p>The session started with Trishul giving a talk on getting started with Add-ons.
He explained about Web Extensions and how they are useful. He also depicted some
of the extensions built by the community. He explained the use of <tt class="docutils literal">manifest</tt>
file and then students started making simple add-ons on their own. The
<a class="reference external" href="https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/Add-ons/WebExtensions/Your_first_WebExtension">borderify</a>
Web Extension was chosen to teach students. Me, Trishul and Shivam helped them
whenever they were stuck.</p>
<img alt="Web Extension session" src="http://www.sanyamkhurana.com/blog/feeds/images/moz-addons.jpg" />
<p>The next session was took by Faye on Women in Mozilla and how we can improve the
no of women contributors in the community.</p>
<img alt="Faye engaging participants" src="http://www.sanyamkhurana.com/blog/feeds/images/moz-addons-faye.jpg" />
<p>The third session was took by me where I discussed about <cite>What is FOSS</cite> and why
people should contribute to FOSS. We then discussed on various pathways one can
start contributing. We also discussed on finding bugs through BugZilla and Bugsahoy
for Mozilla.</p>
<p>Then Shashikanth discussed about importance of Privacy issues.</p>
<p>We ended the event with a capture of all enthusiastic faces in the meetup:</p>
<img alt="Group photo after Mozilla Web Extension session" src="http://www.sanyamkhurana.com/blog/feeds/images/moz-addons-group.jpg" />]]>
  </description>
  <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jan 2018 14:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
  
</item>

<item>
  <title>Sanyam Khurana - Moz-Fedora Day</title>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">tag:www.sanyamkhurana.com,2018-01-14:blog/moz-fedora-day.html</guid>
  <link>https://www.sanyamkhurana.com/blog/moz-fedora-day.html</link>
  <description>
    <![CDATA[<p>We recently organized Moz-Fedora Day, a one day event on promoting FOSS through
Mozilla &amp; Fedora at Investopad, Hauz Khas, Delhi on Jan 13, 2018. The aim was
to depict the usage of packaging &amp; building one of the Mozilla's project using Fedora.</p>
<img alt="Sanyam explaining about Mozilla &amp; it's mission" src="http://www.sanyamkhurana.com/blog/feeds/images/moz-fedora-day-4.jpg" />
<p>The core event focused on making the participants automate the build of any of
the Mozilla's open source project of their choice. The aim is to influence
people to switch to Linux as a build environment (We used Fedora for this)
and introduce the basics of the version control system (Mercurial in case of Mozilla).
The event will also introduce to Vagrant for running standardized virtual
machines for build environments.</p>
<img alt="Sanyam engaging participants on Moz-Fedora Day" src="http://www.sanyamkhurana.com/blog/feeds/images/moz-fedora-day-3.jpg" />
<p>The session began with Saurabh representing a bit about Fedora and other Linux
Distributions. I discussed about Mozilla, it's mission and different projects.
We then decided to package <a class="reference external" href="https://servo.org/">Servo</a> in Fedora and guided
folks through the steps to build the system. We used simple Vagrant setup to
package Servo project with Fedora.</p>
<img alt="Sanyam explaining about build systems" src="http://www.sanyamkhurana.com/blog/feeds/images/moz-fedora-day-2.jpg" />
<p>At the end of the event, we had a small discussion on how one can find bugs
through Bugzilla &amp; Bugsahoy. The presentation can be found here:
<a class="reference external" href="http://www.sanyamkhurana.com/presentations/foss/">http://www.sanyamkhurana.com/presentations/foss/</a></p>
<p>We also distributed some swags to folks who were able to make builds successfully.</p>
<img alt="Swag Distribution" src="http://www.sanyamkhurana.com/blog/feeds/images/moz-fedora-day-1.jpg" />
<p>Most of this was a hands-on session and I saw new faces who were truly excited to
learn about these things. A Saturday well spent, spreading the love of Open Source.</p>]]>
  </description>
  <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jan 2018 14:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
  
</item>

<item>
  <title>Sanyam Khurana - Ending the year with MozCoffee</title>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">tag:www.sanyamkhurana.com,2017-12-24:blog/mozcoffee-2017-end.html</guid>
  <link>https://www.sanyamkhurana.com/blog/mozcoffee-2017-end.html</link>
  <description>
    <![CDATA[<p>We had <tt class="docutils literal">MozCoffee Delhi</tt> on last Saturday, Dec 23, 2017. We had a lot of Rep
Attendees this time with other Mozillians. What would have been a better way to
end an year than the MozCoffee. From past various months, the activities in
Mozilla Delhi came to a stand still. But then we had MozCoffee planned in less
than a week. Thanks to my new mentor Trishul for arranging MozCoffee at Chaayos,
Connaught Place, New Delhi on 23rd December, 2017.</p>
<p>We gathered up at the venue in the evening and met a lot of new and old people.
We had Trishul, Faye, Sanyam, Tanzeel, Dvyik, Rajiv, Saurabh, Pushpita, Shivam, Tushar at the meetup.</p>
<p>The discussion started with Trishul explaining about his experience in All Hands Austin.
He told about various projects that have been identified by Mozilla as the major
areas of contributions. We discussed about both tech &amp; non-tech contributions
in various areas.</p>
<p>Near the end of the event, Trishul also helped me in explaining about addons.
Since I've previous experience with JS, it was pretty easy to pick that stuff up.</p>
<p>Finally, we had some amazing photographs which would now become a memory for all of us.</p>
<img alt="MozCoffee" src="http://www.sanyamkhurana.com/blog/feeds/images/mozcoffee-2017-end-1.jpg" />
<img alt="MozCoffee" src="http://www.sanyamkhurana.com/blog/feeds/images/mozcoffee-2017-end-2.jpg" />]]>
  </description>
  <pubDate>Sun, 24 Dec 2017 15:04:00 +0000</pubDate>
  
</item>

<item>
  <title>Viswaprasath KS - Year in review 2017</title>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://vp7techie.wordpress.com/2017/12/10/year-in-review-2017/</guid>
  <link>https://vp7techie.wordpress.com/2017/12/10/year-in-review-2017/</link>
  <description>
    <![CDATA[<p>2017 is one of the amazing year I had. I have dedicated it fully to  learn and share my knowledge about WebExtension and develop some WebExtension during my free time.</p>
<h1 id="january">January</h1>
<p>This is one of the best month and very good start of the year. In Tamilnadu we had lot of problems but we succesfully organised our first ever MozillaTN meetup, yes we were having amazing two day event where I was helping attendees to know about WebExtension. Before even the meetup some of the attendees started learning webextension, thanks to MDN and some of the articles I wrote <img alt="😉" class="wp-smiley" src="https://s0.wp.com/wp-content/mu-plugins/wpcom-smileys/twemoji/2/72x72/1f609.png" style="height: 1em;" /></p>
<h1 id="february">February</h1>
<p>This is one of the milestone month for me, I got an opportunity to share about WebExtension in our local ILUGC meetup.  ILUGC is one of the amazing community which is having the regular meetups for past 10+ years. Giving session there was really amazing and was an exciting one for me. Then at the last week I was able to visit SRM Univ after a long time and gave some basic introduction talk on WebExtension and Mozilla Community.</p>
<h1 id="march">March</h1>
<p>In march our MozillaTN community organised our first ever over night hackathon at KCG college of Technology chennai. We had 2 tracks WebVR and WebExtension. I was handling the WebExtension session and was mentoring the students on how to build it, and it is also my first hackathon with WebExtension development. Then  on the last week went to VIT chennai to share about WebExtension, It was one day session where introduced students with WebExtension and also had some coding session to develop a small addon to close the tab on click of browserAction button.</p>
<p>Between April and June sometime I was involved in developing some add-ons and wrote blog posts about them.</p>
<h1 id="july">July</h1>
<p>Went to KCG Community space and shared about WebExtension development. We had the half a session to understand about Tabs API.</p>
<p>And early July I started planning about WebExtension on-line series where planned to create vidoes and train attendes one API per day and discuss about them on how to use it for developing WebExtension.</p>
<h1 id="august">August</h1>
<p>Went Dhirajzilla engineering college at Salem and gave an introduction talk about WebExtension. The biggest gift and surprise I got from the students I was able to meet my under graduate professor there. That was the happiest moment and I was giving talk in front of my professor about WebExtension. She was amazing person and inspired us a lot, she played a major role in shaping me and my friends during our college days. And went to Sairam college to have a booth and tell students about Mozilla communities in booth and gave a short quick talk Why WebExtension are amazing.</p>
<h1 id="september">September</h1>
<p>This is one of the good month. We planned a good open hackaton (any students, employees can join) at out KCG community space. This is the first open hackathon in that community space and around 20+ attendees attended and demoed 6+ addons. Went to another hackathon at SNS College of Tech Coimbatore, where had amazing set of students with good knowledge of what they are going to develop.</p>
<h1 id="october">October</h1>
<p>SRM university approached us and wanted to have a good purely technical hands-on session. This time we had 2 days session again (my 3rd one in a row). I was showing different demo and people loved contextMenu and omnibar search and most of them showed demo on it. And they were interested in learning it continously and the guy who hosted us was amazing, thanks to Anirudh for this opportunity.</p>
<h1 id="november">November</h1>
<p>In November after a long time had opportunity to talk at over night hackathon along with Santhosh, Karthick, Trishul. It was amazing to see kids right from 13 years. Some of them showed amazing demo like text-to-speech using Web APIs. It was cool at the same time was so tired.</p>
<h1 id="december">December</h1>
<p>Yes its year end and everything is bit slow. I got opportunity to attend All hands at Austin. I met amazing Mozillians and had lot of learning. Went to awesome dinner and Star wars <img alt="😉" class="wp-smiley" src="https://s0.wp.com/wp-content/mu-plugins/wpcom-smileys/twemoji/2/72x72/1f609.png" style="height: 1em;" /><br />
It was great to plan for 2018 related to WebExtension. I am very exciting for upcoming days.</p>
<h2 id="talks">Talks</h2>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://reps.mozilla.org/e/mozilla-session-at-ilugc/">Mozilla Session at ILUGC</a> for Feb meetup</li>
<li><a href="https://reps.mozilla.org/e/saturday-chillout-at-srm-univeristy/">Saturday Chillout</a> at SRM university</li>
<li><a href="https://reps.mozilla.org/e/dhirajzilla-webextension-session/">Dhirajzilla WebExtension Session</a> at Salem</li>
<li><a href="https://iamvp7.github.io/tag/woc2017/">Weeks of Contribution</a> Series of talk about WebExtension.</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="workshops--hackathon">Workshops &amp; hackathon</h2>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://reps.mozilla.org/e/mozactivate-hackathon-at-kcg/">MozActivate Hackathon at KCG</a> at KCG, Chennai</li>
<li><a href="https://reps.mozilla.org/e/mozactivate-webext-at-sns-college-of-tech/">MozActivate WebExt</a> at SNSCT, Coimbatore</li>
<li><a href="https://reps.mozilla.org/e/srm-university-extension-hackathon/">SRM University Extension Hackathon</a> at SRM Chennai</li>
<li><a href="https://reps.mozilla.org/e/mozillatn-sfd-extension-hackathon/">MozillaTN SFD Extension Hackathon</a> at KCG community space.</li>
<li><a href="https://reps.mozilla.org/e/add-ons-hacksprint/">Add-ons Hacksprint</a> at hyderabad Space</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="experiments">Experiments</h2>
<p>Developed some of the WebExtension which are used during various talks. All the code are available in github repos <a href="https://github.com/iamVP7/MyExtensions">MyExtensions</a> and <a href="https://github.com/iamVP7/MozWOC17">MozWOC17</a></p>
<p>Having started writing a book on WebExtension along with Karthick, hopefully will be finishing by March 2018 and publish the first version for all the contributors.</p>
<p>2017 is ending with great moments, expecting 2018 will be much more awesome and helpful to learn more. Happy new year.</p>]]>
  </description>
  <pubDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2017 01:34:00 +0000</pubDate>
  
</item>

</channel>
</rss>
