<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

<channel>
	<title>Mozilla Reps Planet</title>
	<link>http://planet.mozillareps.org</link>
	<language>en</language>
	<description>Mozilla Reps Planet - http://planet.mozillareps.org</description>
	<atom:link rel="self" href="http://planet.mozillareps.org/rss20.xml" type="application/rss+xml"/>


<item>
	<title>Md Shahbaz Alam - Beta Testing BugHunting</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://alamshahbaz.wordpress.com/?p=1123</guid>
	<link>https://alamshahbaz.wordpress.com/2019/07/16/beta-testing-bughunting/</link>
	<description>Hello Everyone, It’s been almost 9 months since I wrote a blog. There are pending blogs coming soon from Oct 2018, which includes my journey experience and speaking experience from southeast Asia. After a series of WebExtension events in Ranchi, ...</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2019 09:15:53 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

<item>
	<title>Official Reps Blog - Rep of the Month – June 2019</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.mozilla.org/mozillareps/?p=596</guid>
	<link>https://blog.mozilla.org/mozillareps/2019/07/05/rep-of-the-month-june-2019/</link>
	<description>Please join us in congratulating Pranshu Khanna, Rep of the Month for June 2019! Pranshu is from Surat, Gujarat, India. His journey started with a Connected Devices workshop in 2016, since then he’s been a super active contributor and a ...</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2019 11:37:15 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

<item>
	<title>Official Reps Blog - 8 Years of Reps Program, Celebrating Community Successes!</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.mozilla.org/mozillareps/?p=595</guid>
	<link>https://blog.mozilla.org/mozillareps/2019/07/03/8-years-of-reps-program-celebrating-community-successes/</link>
	<description>The Reps program idea was started in 2010 by William Quiviger and Pierros Papadeas, until officially launched and welcoming volunteers onboard as Mozilla Reps in 2011. The Mozilla Reps program aims to empower and support volunteer Mozillians who want to ...</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2019 12:23:21 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

<item>
	<title>Official Reps Blog - New Council members – 2019 Spring elections</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.mozilla.org/mozillareps/?p=590</guid>
	<link>https://blog.mozilla.org/mozillareps/2019/06/04/new-council-members-2019-spring-elections/</link>
	<description>We are very happy to announce that our 5 new Council members are are fully on-boarded and already working moving the Mozilla Reps program forward. In more detail here are the subjects that they will work on: Mayur Patil: Campaigns ...</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2019 16:02:00 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

<item>
	<title>Official Reps Blog - Rep of the Month – April 2019</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.mozilla.org/mozillareps/?p=587</guid>
	<link>https://blog.mozilla.org/mozillareps/2019/05/13/rep-of-the-month-april-2019/</link>
	<description>Please join us in congratulating Lidya Christina, Rep of the Month for April 2019! Lidya Christina is from Jakarta, Indonesia. Her contribution in SUMO event in 2016 lead her into a proud Mozillian, an active contributor of Mozilla Indonesia and ...</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2019 17:07:21 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

<item>
	<title>Viswaprasath KS - WebXR talk at VIT DevSpace</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://vp7techie.wordpress.com/?p=901</guid>
	<link>https://vp7techie.wordpress.com/2019/05/12/webxr-talk-at-vit-devspace/</link>
	<description>VIT, Vellore is one of the most reputed college in Tamilnadu. At the end of this March they organized DevSpace, Computer science department and Computer Society Students branch of college teamed up and organized this event. It is one of ...</description>
	<pubDate>Sun, 12 May 2019 17:52:40 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

<item>
	<title>Bhuvana Meenakshi Koteeswaran - Discovery of another passion!</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://kbmtechie.wordpress.com/?p=331</guid>
	<link>https://kbmtechie.wordpress.com/2019/04/07/discovery-of-another-passion/</link>
	<description>During this year’s traditional festival of Tamil Nadu, I not only celebrated it in a holy way but also I learnt, shared and discovered. Yes, this was the exact time that the Firefox Fights For You video challenge was open ...</description>
	<pubDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2019 18:37:47 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

<item>
	<title>Viswaprasath KS - Add-ons session at LPU</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://vp7techie.wordpress.com/?p=889</guid>
	<link>https://vp7techie.wordpress.com/2019/03/31/lpu2019/</link>
	<description>LPU generally called as Lovely Professional University is well known university in India. Recently the students club organized one of the amazing event #DiveIntoOpenSource It was not a very easy travel to LPU. I to some extent I love travel ...</description>
	<pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2019 15:50:07 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

<item>
	<title>Official Reps Blog - Rep of the Month – February 2019</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.mozilla.org/mozillareps/?p=581</guid>
	<link>https://blog.mozilla.org/mozillareps/2019/03/14/rep-of-the-month-february-2019/</link>
	<description>Please join us in congratulating Edoardo Viola, our Rep of the Month for February 2019! Edoardo is a long-time Mozillian from Italy and has been a Rep for almost two years. He’s a Resource Rep and has been on the ...</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2019 12:32:46 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

<item>
	<title>Official Reps Blog - Rep of the Month – November 2018</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.mozilla.org/mozillareps/?p=578</guid>
	<link>https://blog.mozilla.org/mozillareps/2019/03/06/rep-of-the-month-november-2018/</link>
	<description>Please join us in congratulating Viswaprasath KS, our Rep of the Month for November 2018! Viswaprasath KS, also know as iamvp7, is a long time Mozillian from India who joined the Mozilla Rep program in June 2013. By profession he ...</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2019 11:06:34 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

<item>
	<title>Shivam Singhal - 2018 Year in Review with AMO</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://championshuttler.wordpress.com/?p=417</guid>
	<link>https://championshuttler.wordpress.com/2019/02/14/2018-year-in-review-with-amo/</link>
	<description>Sibelius Monument, Finland Each one of us have some goals to complete, things to learn, and places to visit. With the year getting ended, it is time to lock back and see what all did we do for the last ...</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 13 Feb 2019 17:27:14 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

<item>
	<title>Official Reps Blog - Reps OKRs – First half of the year 2019</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.mozilla.org/mozillareps/?p=576</guid>
	<link>https://blog.mozilla.org/mozillareps/2019/01/29/reps-okrs-first-half-of-the-year-2019/</link>
	<description>Here are the OKRs for the first half of the year: Objective 1: Reps are the bridge between their local communities (Mozilla or other local open source communities) and the Mozilla contribution opportunities Key Result 1.1: 60% of Reps have ...</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2019 18:24:44 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

<item>
	<title>Bhuvana Meenakshi Koteeswaran - 2018 – Red letter days, Mozilla and Me :)</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://kbmtechie.wordpress.com/?p=327</guid>
	<link>https://kbmtechie.wordpress.com/2018/12/31/2018-red-letter-days-mozilla-and-me/</link>
	<description>Date: 31.12.2018 With the New Year fast approaching I just recollected the sweet memories that the past year 2018 has given me. Of course a lot of ups and downs, without which life can’t be interesting. Firstly I express my ...</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2018 18:30:12 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

<item>
	<title>Robert Reyes - ASEAN Mozillian Localizers Meet at Hanoi, Vietnam</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.bobreyes.com/myblog/?p=5591</guid>
	<link>https://www.bobreyes.com/myblog/asean-mozillian-localizers-meet-at-hanoi-vietnam/</link>
	<description>All roads (flights, actually) lead to Hanoi, Vietnam as the Mozilla Localization Team hosted a Meetup/Workshop for Mozillian Localizers from Southeast Asia on the weekend of 17 to 18 November. The delegation from Mozilla Philippines (MozillaPH) is composed of Kemuel ...</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 19 Nov 2018 15:21:49 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

<item>
	<title>Official Reps Blog - New Council Members – Fall 2018 Elections</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.mozilla.org/mozillareps/?p=574</guid>
	<link>https://blog.mozilla.org/mozillareps/2018/11/12/new-council-members-fall-2018-elections/</link>
	<description>We are very happy to announce that our 2 new Council members Monica Bonilla and Yofie Setiawan are fully on-boarded and already working moving the Mozilla Reps program forward. A warm welcome from all of us. We we are very ...</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 12 Nov 2018 18:31:09 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

<item>
	<title>Official Reps Blog - Rep of the Month – October 2018</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.mozilla.org/mozillareps/?p=572</guid>
	<link>https://blog.mozilla.org/mozillareps/2018/11/12/rep-of-the-month-october-2018/</link>
	<description>Please join us in congratulating Tim Maks van den Broek, our Rep of the Month for October 2018! Tim is one of our most active members in the Dutch community. During his 15+ years as a Mozilla Volunteer he has ...</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 12 Nov 2018 12:59:59 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

<item>
	<title>Bhuvana Meenakshi Koteeswaran - An escape to The Square Mile #Mozfest2018</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://kbmtechie.wordpress.com/?p=297</guid>
	<link>https://kbmtechie.wordpress.com/2018/11/03/an-escape-to-the-square-mile-mozfest2018/</link>
	<description>Dates of the event: 26,27 and 28, Oct 2018. Venue: Ravensbourne University, London My first trip overseas came true just because of Mozilla and Mozfest2018. In first place my sincere thanks to Mozilla Foundations and Sarah Allen for helping me ...</description>
	<pubDate>Sat, 03 Nov 2018 08:31:45 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

<item>
	<title>Official Reps Blog - Community Coordinator role</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.mozilla.org/mozillareps/?p=569</guid>
	<link>https://blog.mozilla.org/mozillareps/2018/10/10/community-coordinator-role/</link>
	<description>The Reps program is evolving in order to be aligned with Mozilla’s changes on how we perceive communities. Part of those changes is the Mission Driven Mozillians project, where the Reps are involved. We (the Reps Council) believe that the ...</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 10 Oct 2018 12:56:48 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

<item>
	<title>Md Shahbaz Alam - VR and AR on the Web @ Cognizance 2018</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://alamshahbaz.wordpress.com/?p=1102</guid>
	<link>https://alamshahbaz.wordpress.com/2018/10/04/vr-and-ar-on-the-web-cognizance-2018/</link>
	<description>Mozilla India’s first collaboration with Cognizance 2k18. Spreading the Mozilla mission in Changa. Also spreading awareness for online privacy, MozActivate campaign. Amongst students from all over Gujarat, in the technical fest hosted by CHARUSAT, Changa. This will be the 1st ...</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 04 Oct 2018 17:14:23 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

<item>
	<title>Official Reps Blog - Rep of the Month – September 2018</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.mozilla.org/mozillareps/?p=567</guid>
	<link>https://blog.mozilla.org/mozillareps/2018/10/04/rep-of-the-month-september-2018/</link>
	<description>Please join us in congratulating Umesh Agarwal, our Rep of the Month for September 2018! Umesh is from Kharagpur, India and works as Big Data Splunk Architect &amp;amp; Administrator. He is an Open Source Geek and his other areas of ...</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 04 Oct 2018 15:58:24 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

<item>
	<title>Mehul Patel - DevConfIN 2018</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.rowdymehul.com/?p=1634</guid>
	<link>http://www.rowdymehul.com/events/devconfin-2018/</link>
	<description>DevConf.in 2018 is the second annual Developers’ Conference to be organized by Red Hat in Bengaluru, India. It is meant to provide a platform to the local FOSS community participants to come together and engage in the knowledge sharing through ...</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 14 Sep 2018 22:27:02 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

<item>
	<title>Bhuvana Meenakshi Koteeswaran - A day admist techie geeks #Devconf2018</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://kbmtechie.wordpress.com/?p=173</guid>
	<link>https://kbmtechie.wordpress.com/2018/09/09/a-day-admist-techie-geeks-devconf2018/</link>
	<description>Dates of the event: 04 &amp;amp; 05, August, 2018 Venue : Christ University, Bangalore, India. This is the first conference as a speaker I attended and it turned out to be a great event with huge bunch of people interested ...</description>
	<pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 08:19:07 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

<item>
	<title>Official Reps Blog - Rep of the Month – August 2018</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.mozilla.org/mozillareps/?p=565</guid>
	<link>https://blog.mozilla.org/mozillareps/2018/08/27/rep-of-the-month-august-2018/</link>
	<description>Please join us in congratulating Abhiram Ravikumar, our Rep of the Month for August 2018! Abhiram Ravikumar is an amazing contributor from Bangalore India and a long time Mozillian contributing as a Rep since November 2015. He is the so-called ...</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 27 Aug 2018 13:51:38 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

<item>
	<title>Viswaprasath KS - Devconf India 2018</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://vp7techie.wordpress.com/?p=872</guid>
	<link>https://vp7techie.wordpress.com/2018/08/11/devconf-india-2018/</link>
	<description>DevConf Contributor Conferences are technology conference events for Linux and JBoss Developers, Admins, Linux and other open source project contributors, organized by Red Hat. This is the 2nd time happening at India, it was one of the amazing open source ...</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 10 Aug 2018 20:08:04 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

<item>
	<title>Official Reps Blog - Rep of the Month – July 2018</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.mozilla.org/mozillareps/?p=558</guid>
	<link>https://blog.mozilla.org/mozillareps/2018/08/10/rep-of-the-month-july-2018/</link>
	<description>Please join us in congratulating Lívia Takács, our Rep of the Month for July 2018! Livia is a UI developer and visual designer from Hungary and has been part of the Reps program for a bit more than a year. ...</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 10 Aug 2018 09:18:49 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

<item>
	<title>Official Reps Blog - Onboarding team for 2nd half of 2018</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.mozilla.org/mozillareps/?p=556</guid>
	<link>https://blog.mozilla.org/mozillareps/2018/08/08/onboarding-team-for-2nd-half-of-2018/</link>
	<description>This blogpost was composed by Daniele Scasciafratte As we have entered the second half of the year, the Reps Council has worked on updating the Onboarding Screening Team for 2018-2. The scope of this team is to help on evaluating ...</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 08 Aug 2018 15:11:26 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

<item>
	<title>Official Reps Blog - Reps Council at SF All Hands 2018</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.mozilla.org/mozillareps/?p=552</guid>
	<link>https://blog.mozilla.org/mozillareps/2018/07/20/reps-council-at-sf-all-hands-2018/</link>
	<description>This post was written by Prathamesh Chavan TL;DR The All Hands is a special time of the year where Mozilla employees along with core volunteers gather for a week of many meetings and brainstorming. The All Hands Wiki page has ...</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 20 Jul 2018 12:39:37 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

<item>
	<title>Official Reps Blog - In loving memory of Abbackar DIOMANDE</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.mozilla.org/mozillareps/?p=549</guid>
	<link>https://blog.mozilla.org/mozillareps/2018/07/18/in-loving-memory-of-abbackar-diomande/</link>
	<description>It brings us great sadness to share with you the recent news about one of our dear Rep we will so fondly remember. Abbackar DIOMANDE from Ivory Coast is unfortunately no longer with us. Diomande, was a Mozillian from Bouake, ...</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 18 Jul 2018 12:35:46 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

<item>
	<title>Official Reps Blog - H2 2018 Reps Plan for the Council</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.mozilla.org/mozillareps/?p=544</guid>
	<link>https://blog.mozilla.org/mozillareps/2018/07/16/544/</link>
	<description>This blogpost was authored by Daniele Scasciafratte What we have done In the first half of the year, our focus was to align the program with Mission Driven Mozillians and prepare the mandatory Reps onboarding course to ensure it aligns ...</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 16 Jul 2018 14:34:26 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

<item>
	<title>Viswaprasath KS - Mozofest 2018</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://vp7techie.wordpress.com/?p=863</guid>
	<link>https://vp7techie.wordpress.com/2018/07/08/mozofest-2018/</link>
	<description>Mozofest is an event organized by SRMKzilla club each and every year. This year they had big plans for this event. Usually they used limited number of events this year they had Speaker series, Hackathon and other events which educate ...</description>
	<pubDate>Sun, 08 Jul 2018 12:30:28 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

<item>
	<title>Md Shahbaz Alam - LinuxCon China</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://alamshahbaz.wordpress.com/?p=1081</guid>
	<link>https://alamshahbaz.wordpress.com/2018/07/05/linuxcon-china/</link>
	<description>LinuxCon China was a technical conference for developers, operations experts (architects, sys admins, devops), business, compliance and legal leadership and other professionals to come together in an informal setting to learn from open source experts, have fascinating discussions, collaborate with ...</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 05 Jul 2018 04:43:27 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

<item>
	<title>Nino Vranesic - Hack all the things</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.elnino.si/post/175384669542</guid>
	<link>http://blog.elnino.si/post/175384669542</link>
	<description>The term “hacker” can refer to someone or an activity with either good or bad intentions. The...</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 29 Jun 2018 22:14:18 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

<item>
	<title>Official Reps Blog - Rep of the Month – May 2018</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.mozilla.org/mozillareps/?p=542</guid>
	<link>https://blog.mozilla.org/mozillareps/2018/06/22/rep-of-the-month-may-2018/</link>
	<description>Please join us in congratulating Prathamesh Chavan, our Rep of the Month for May 2018! Prathamesh is from Pune, India and works as a Technical Support Engineer at Red Hat. From his very early days in the Mozilla community, Prathamesh ...</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 22 Jun 2018 08:30:16 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

<item>
	<title>Bhuvana Meenakshi Koteeswaran - Taking WebXR to the most energetic gen</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://kbmtechie.wordpress.com/?p=159</guid>
	<link>https://kbmtechie.wordpress.com/2018/05/29/taking-webxr-to-the-most-energetic-gen/</link>
	<description>Venue: Academic heights public school, Hyderabad Date: 20.05.2018 I in the first place wondered whether a topic like WebXR going to complicate the audience I targeted for the day. My audience included 50+ kids, their parents and their guardians of ...</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 29 May 2018 10:20:01 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

<item>
	<title>Bhuvana Meenakshi Koteeswaran - Organise things right!</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://kbmtechie.wordpress.com/?p=145</guid>
	<link>https://kbmtechie.wordpress.com/2018/05/15/organise-things-right/</link>
	<description>The Global Sprint which was going throughout the world on various projects made Fahima and me to think about the event in our home town too. So I took the initiative to organise all things required for this event. I ...</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 15 May 2018 05:31:24 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

<item>
	<title>Official Reps Blog - Rep of the Month – April 2018</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.mozilla.org/mozillareps/?p=540</guid>
	<link>https://blog.mozilla.org/mozillareps/2018/05/08/rep-of-the-month-april-2018/</link>
	<description>Please join us in congratulating David Ross, our Rep of the Month for April 2018! David is a Mozillian living the UK and active in a lot of different Mozilla projects. In his day job he is building an Open ...</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 08 May 2018 15:09:18 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

<item>
	<title>Viswaprasath KS - COEP FOSS Meetup 2018</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://vp7techie.wordpress.com/2018/04/27/coep-foss-meetup-2018/</guid>
	<link>https://vp7techie.wordpress.com/2018/04/27/coep-foss-meetup-2018/</link>
	<description>This is my second visit to Pune, after my recent GNUify event. GNUNify was mainly focused for Student developers, the target audience were getting started with Open source community. COeP Foss Meetup had well experienced developers and students who are ...</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 27 Apr 2018 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

<item>
	<title>Md Shahbaz Alam - WebVR @ LPU</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://alamshahbaz.wordpress.com/?p=1056</guid>
	<link>https://alamshahbaz.wordpress.com/2018/04/27/webvr-lpu/</link>
	<description>Lovely Professional University is a private university situated in Jalandhar, Punjab, India. It is a well know educational institutions in the country with around 34000 students and over 130 programs. Mrinal and I were invited to LPU for a workshop ...</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 27 Apr 2018 05:59:03 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

<item>
	<title>Official Reps Blog - Rep of the Month – March 2018</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.mozilla.org/mozillareps/?p=537</guid>
	<link>https://blog.mozilla.org/mozillareps/2018/04/10/rep-of-the-month-march-2018/</link>
	<description>Please join us in congratulating Md Shahbaz Alam, our Rep of the Month for March 2018! Shahbaz is a Full Stack Developer and Tech Evangelist by profession. He loves to talk about WebVR and auth0, he single-handedly created a Mozilla ...</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 10 Apr 2018 09:05:18 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

<item>
	<title>Michael Kohler - 10 Years as a Mozilla Volunteer</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">https://michaelkohler.info/2018/04/09/mozilla-10-years-mozillian/</guid>
	<link>https://michaelkohler.info/2018/04/09/mozilla-10-years-mozillian/</link>
	<description>March 10th, 2018 marked my 10 year anniversary as a Mozilla volunteer. I wanted to write this blog post for quite some time now, but as y</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 09 Apr 2018 19:29:11 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

<item>
	<title>Md Shahbaz Alam - Virtual Reality @ Indian Institute of Technology (BHU)</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://alamshahbaz.wordpress.com/?p=1023</guid>
	<link>https://alamshahbaz.wordpress.com/2018/04/09/virtual-reality-indian-institute-of-technology-bhu/</link>
	<description>Again trio has come together for a wonderful event. This time it was IIT-BHU. The event started with the introduction of the speakers, Shahbaz, Umesh and Prathamesh ( trio aka SUP ). Prathamesh started the session explaining the difference between ...</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 09 Apr 2018 18:25:31 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

<item>
	<title>Official Reps Blog - Reps of the Month – February 2018</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.mozilla.org/mozillareps/?p=535</guid>
	<link>https://blog.mozilla.org/mozillareps/2018/04/01/reps-of-the-month-february-2018/</link>
	<description>Please join us in congratulating Ziggy Maes and Anthony Maton, our Reps of the Month for February 2018! Ziggy Ziggy is a long time Mozillian that is involved in organizing our presence at FOSDEM or managing the volunteers at the ...</description>
	<pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2018 14:36:02 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

<item>
	<title>Bhuvana Meenakshi Koteeswaran - A day as a speaker @ SRMkzilla</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://kbmtechie.wordpress.com/?p=132</guid>
	<link>https://kbmtechie.wordpress.com/2018/04/01/a-day-as-a-speaker-srmkzilla/</link>
	<description>Date: 24th March,2018 Venue: SRM University, Chennai The day started with the inauguration by the chief guest, Mr. Raaman. It was an interesting talk on Linux forum and how open source plays the real trend in today’s world. I was ...</description>
	<pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2018 13:04:04 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

<item>
	<title>Md Shahbaz Alam - Virtual Reality @ Hackfest, IIT (ISM) Dhanbad</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://alamshahbaz.wordpress.com/?p=1010</guid>
	<link>https://alamshahbaz.wordpress.com/2018/03/28/virtual-reality-hackfest-iit-ism-dhanbad/</link>
	<description>HackFest is IIT(ISM) Dhanbad’s 36-hour annual hackathon organized by the Computer Science and Engineering Society (CSES) and ACM Student Chapter, IIT(ISM) Dhanbad. The event started with an introduction of speakers. Prathamesh, Umesh, and Shahbaz ( yep it’s me ), since ...</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 28 Mar 2018 15:15:53 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

<item>
	<title>Md Shahbaz Alam - Footprints 2018</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://alamshahbaz.wordpress.com/?p=998</guid>
	<link>https://alamshahbaz.wordpress.com/2018/03/26/footprints-2018/</link>
	<description>WebMR is a new technology which is in its initial stages. WebMR was the thing which has brought a huge participation at Baroda. Everyone was eagerly waiting for us. Event started with a brief introduction of the speakers. Prathamesh Chavan ...</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 26 Mar 2018 17:23:45 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

<item>
	<title>Bhuvana Meenakshi Koteeswaran - My first talk on WebXR</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://kbmtechie.wordpress.com/?p=128</guid>
	<link>https://kbmtechie.wordpress.com/2018/03/18/my-first-talk-on-webxr/</link>
	<description>Date: 17.03.2018 Venue : PES University, Bangalore, India. This was my first presentation on WebXR as my previous talks were mostly focused on WebVR and projects related to it. There were around 150+ enthusiastic participants who actively participated in this ...</description>
	<pubDate>Sun, 18 Mar 2018 17:12:22 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

<item>
	<title>Sanyam Khurana - International Women's Day with WoMoz in Delhi</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">tag:www.sanyamkhurana.com,2018-03-15:blog/womoz-international-womens-day-delhi.html</guid>
	<link>https://www.sanyamkhurana.com/blog/womoz-international-womens-day-delhi.html</link>
	<description>We all know that every year, 8th March is celebrated as International Women&#39;s Day. It is a focal point in the movement for women&#39;s rights. On this occasion, all the Open Source communities in and around Delhi came forward to ...</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 14 Mar 2018 21:21:00 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

<item>
	<title>Tanzeel Khan - Discussion: Aadhaar and Right to Privacy in India @ Delhi NCR</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://khantanzeel.wordpress.com/?p=592</guid>
	<link>https://khantanzeel.wordpress.com/2018/03/09/discussion-aadhaar-and-right-to-privacy-in-india-delhi-ncr/</link>
	<description>To assess the status of Aadhaar Campaign in India and plan future initiatives to safeguard the right to privacy in India, a Talk Session was held at SpringHouse Gurugram on March 9 2018. Senior Global Policy Manager of Mozilla Jochai ...</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 09 Mar 2018 05:23:30 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

<item>
	<title>Robert Reyes - Three (03) Mozilla Talks in a Week!</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.bobreyes.com/myblog/?p=5481</guid>
	<link>https://www.bobreyes.com/myblog/three-03-mozilla-talks-in-a-week/</link>
	<description>I was able to squeeze delivery of three (03) Mozilla talks during the week of 05 to 11 February 2018. To chronicle what has transpired during these three (03) events, I have this blog post… Prof. Belay Montes’ Class at ...</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 07 Mar 2018 07:08:04 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

<item>
	<title>Official Reps Blog - New Review Team Member 2018</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.mozilla.org/mozillareps/?p=533</guid>
	<link>https://blog.mozilla.org/mozillareps/2018/03/06/new-review-team-member-2018/</link>
	<description>Hi amazing Reps! We’re so very happy to announce the new Review Team members who have just been officially on boarded. Welcome Michael, Pushpita, Jason, and Arturo to the team! The Review Team is a specialized group responsible in reviewing ...</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 06 Mar 2018 13:31:07 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

<item>
	<title>Md Shahbaz Alam - Maker Fest 2018</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://alamshahbaz.wordpress.com/?p=982</guid>
	<link>https://alamshahbaz.wordpress.com/2018/03/06/maker-fest-2018/</link>
	<description>Makerfest has been a place to explore and learn from all the makers and collaborators. This is my 2nd consecutive year as Volunteer from Mozilla India. This time I was there to represent Auth0 and talk about its service. I ...</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 06 Mar 2018 07:15:15 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

<item>
	<title>Viswaprasath KS - Prayatna 2018</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://vp7techie.wordpress.com/2018/03/05/prayatna-2018/</guid>
	<link>https://vp7techie.wordpress.com/2018/03/05/prayatna-2018/</link>
	<description>Prayatna is one of the prime Technical fest organised by MIT, Anna University Chennai. It is an yearly where the number of students participating will be very high. This year our community organized One day workshop of WebExtension. This time ...</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 05 Mar 2018 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

<item>
	<title>Viswaprasath KS - KGiSL Mozactivate 2018</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://vp7techie.wordpress.com/2018/03/02/kgisl-mozactivate-2018/</guid>
	<link>https://vp7techie.wordpress.com/2018/03/02/kgisl-mozactivate-2018/</link>
	<description>KGiSL community space is very close to every Mozillian around Tamilnadu, we had our first meetup there. There are lot of events related to Mozilla and open source communities happen at this space. After so long time I got opportunity ...</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 02 Mar 2018 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

<item>
	<title>Sanyam Khurana - MozAMU: Mozilla Addons Development at AMU</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">tag:www.sanyamkhurana.com,2018-03-01:blog/mozilla-addons-dev-amu.html</guid>
	<link>https://www.sanyamkhurana.com/blog/mozilla-addons-dev-amu.html</link>
	<description>It all started with PyCon India. I met a few students of Aligarh Muslim University who were trying to teach about FOSS in their college. A few them were already contributing to Coala. We talked a bit and they were ...</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 11:41:00 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

<item>
	<title>Mehul Patel - Maker Fest 2018</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.rowdymehul.com/?p=1502</guid>
	<link>http://www.rowdymehul.com/mozilla/maker-fest-2018/</link>
	<description>MakerFest has always been very closed to my heart because from here what my journey as a #Mozillian started and as result, this is my 2nd consecutive year as a Lead organizer and 3rd year as a volunteer from Mozilla ...</description>
	<pubDate>Sun, 25 Feb 2018 19:04:19 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

<item>
	<title>Mehul Patel - GSIndia Summit 2017</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.rowdymehul.com/?p=1488</guid>
	<link>http://www.rowdymehul.com/mozilla/gsindia-summit-2017/</link>
	<description>GirlScript India Summit – It is the first ever women oriented technical festival of India hosted by GirlScript Foundation. It is a platform where students get a chance to polish their skills and explore their potential. The Technical fest will ...</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 23 Feb 2018 18:34:23 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

<item>
	<title>Viswaprasath KS - GNUnify 2018</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://vp7techie.wordpress.com/2018/02/19/gnunify-2018/</guid>
	<link>https://vp7techie.wordpress.com/2018/02/19/gnunify-2018/</link>
	<description>GNUnify is one of the amazing event where each and every year Mozilla India community make sure to participate. GNUnify is an annual gathering consisting of Free and Open Source software workshops, talks, seminars and BOFs (Birds of a feather), ...</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2018 07:39:00 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

<item>
	<title>Mehul Patel - Google DevFest Ahmedabad 2017</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.rowdymehul.com/?p=1476</guid>
	<link>http://www.rowdymehul.com/rust/google-devfest-ahmedabad-2017/</link>
	<description>Google Developers Group (GDG) – is open and volunteer geek community who create exciting projects and share experience about Google technologies with a passion and GDG Ahmedabad is one of the most active &amp;amp; passionate community. The aim of GDG ...</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2018 08:29:48 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

<item>
	<title>Nino Vranesic - Embracing the improvement psychology</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.elnino.si/post/170845327967</guid>
	<link>http://blog.elnino.si/post/170845327967</link>
	<description>What would you do if you could do it all the time? Everybody is the happiest when they are doing...</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 13 Feb 2018 21:04:20 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

<item>
	<title>Sanyam Khurana - Web Extensions, Womoz &amp; Privacy</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">tag:www.sanyamkhurana.com,2018-01-23:blog/web-extensions-womoz-privacy.html</guid>
	<link>https://www.sanyamkhurana.com/blog/web-extensions-womoz-privacy.html</link>
	<description>A Saturday well spent teaching students about Open Source, Add-ons and Privacy. We had an activity at Indira Gandhi Delhi Technical University for Women (IGDTUW) for Addons, WoMoz and Privacy. The session started with Trishul giving a talk on getting ...</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 23 Jan 2018 14:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

</channel>
</rss>
