<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

<channel>
  <title>Mozilla Reps Planet</title>
  <link>http://planet.mozillareps.org</link>
  <language>en</language>
  <description>Mozilla Reps Planet - http://planet.mozillareps.org</description>
  <atom:link rel="self" href="http://planet.mozillareps.org/rss20full.xml" type="application/rss+xml"/>


<item>
  <title>Christophe Villeneuve - Meetup et hackathon WebExtensions chez Mozilla Paris</title>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">urn:md5:f89b57e42cee63ea83f2c412bd39b517</guid>
  <link>https://blog.mozfr.org/post/2017/11/meetup-Hackathon-webextensions-Mozilla-Paris</link>
  <description>
    <![CDATA[<p><a href="https://blog.mozfr.org/dotclear/public/MozillaParis/webextensions/salle.jpg"><img alt="Meetup Mozilla Paris" src="https://blog.mozfr.org/dotclear/public/MozillaParis/webextensions/.salle_s.jpg" style="float: right; margin: 0 0 1em 1em;" /></a> Suite au succès du précédent Meetup sur l’<a href="https://blog.mozfr.org/post/2017/10/Introduction-aux-WebExtensions-lundi-prochain-chez-Mozilla-Paris" hreflang="fr" title="Introduction aux WebExtensions lundi prochain chez Mozilla Paris (12 oct. 2017) Communauté Mozilla francophone">introduction aux WebExtensions</a>, nous vous proposons de nous retrouver de nouveau autour des WebExtensions mais sous une nouvelle formule.</p>


<p>Ce rendez-vous se déroulera en 2 temps (ou en 2 jours) les <strong>17 et 18 novembre</strong> prochain à Mozilla Paris.</p>    <h3>1<sup>re</sup> étape : le lancement</h3>


<p>La première étape de ce rendez-vous sera au format Meetup et lancera la deuxième étape.</p>


<p>Ce rendez-vous est destiné à toutes les personnes intéressées par cette mutation dans leur navigateur préféré, mais aussi aux personnes curieuses en matière de compatibilité du code pour le développement web.</p>


<p>Le programme de la soirée se composera :</p>


<p>Tout d’abord, notre Mozillien <strong>Christophe Villeneuve</strong> (<em>Mozilla Rep</em>), contributeur aux WebExtensions, nous  parlera du portage au sens large, dont :</p>
<ul>
<li>le portage des extensions venant de Chrome ;</li>
<li>des différences entre le bureau et le mobile ;</li>
<li>les incompatibilités que vous rencontrerez actuellement.</li>
</ul>


<p>Il sera suivi de <strong>Marc Haussaire</strong>, cofondateur du moteur de recherche <a href="https://www.lilo.org/fr/" hreflang="fr" title="Lilo, le moteur de recherche qui finance des projets sociaux">Lilo</a> qui finance des projets sociaux et environnementaux. Marc nous présentera les différentes fonctionnalités utilisées par Lilo dans les WebExtensions :</p>
<ul>
<li>affichage de fenêtres liées à un bouton dans Firefox ;</li>
<li>gestion des <em>content scripts</em> ;</li>
<li>comment ils ont opéré la migration depuis les extensions <em>legacy</em> (obsolètes).</li>
</ul>


<p>Ensuite, nous préparerons le hackathon du lendemain en partageant liens et astuces, et en récoltant les idées et envies d’extension des présents, même s’ils ne seront pas là pour la seconde journée.</p>


<p>Enfin, pour terminer la soirée, il sera possible d’échanger de manière informelle, en dégustant quelques pizzas, autour des différentes présentations, mais aussi sur Firefox en général.</p>


<p>L’événement est <strong>gratuit, mais sur inscription</strong> sur <a href="https://www.meetup.com/fr-FR/Firefox-France-User-Group/events/243686714/" hreflang="fr" title="Meetup 17 novembre 2017 : Présentation Hackathon WebExtensions">sa page Meetup</a>.</p>


<h3>2ᵉ étape : le jour J</h3>


<p>Le jour J va permettre à tout le monde de contribuer individuellement ou par petits groupes aux extensions jusqu’à la soumission sur le site officiel des <a href="https://addons.mozilla.org/fr/firefox/" hreflang="fr" title="Modules pour Firefox"><em>add-ons</em> de Mozilla</a>.</p>


<p>Ainsi, à partir des idées et des différentes propositions soumises lors de la soirée de lancement, vous pourrez :</p>
<ul>
<li>apprendre et créer une WebExtension ;</li>
<li>porter une extension Google ou Edge vers Firefox.</li>
</ul>


<p>Il est impératif de <strong>vous munir d’un ordinateur</strong> pour pouvoir programmer sa WebExtension.</p>


<p>L’événement est <strong>gratuit, mais sur inscription</strong> sur <a href="https://www.meetup.com/fr-FR/Firefox-France-User-Group/events/243686678/" hreflang="fr" title="Hackathon 18 novembre 2017 : Hackathon WebExtensions">sa page Meetup</a>.</p>


<p><img alt="Puzzle Firefox" src="https://blog.mozfr.org/dotclear/public/mozilla/logo/puzzle.jpg" style="display: table; margin: 0 auto;" /></p>


<h3>Retour sur l’introduction aux WebExtensions</h3>


<p><a href="https://blog.mozfr.org/post/2017/10/Introduction-aux-WebExtensions-lundi-prochain-chez-Mozilla-Paris" hreflang="fr" title="Introduction aux WebExtensions lundi prochain chez Mozilla Paris (12 oct. 2017) Communauté Mozilla francophone">Le mois dernier</a> se déroulait une soirée sous la forme d’une mise en bouche aux WebExtensions. Ce fut l’occasion de découvrir ce chamboulement qui arrive dans vos navigateurs, comme dans Firefox 57 nommé Firefox Quantum, le 14 novembre prochain.</p>


<p><img alt="Christophe Villeneuve - Hellosct1" src="https://blog.mozfr.org/dotclear/public/MozillaParis/webextensions/.hellosct1_s.jpg" style="float: right; margin: 0 0 1em 1em;" /></p>


<p>Tout d’abord, notre Mozillien Christophe Villeneuve a  aidé à mieux appréhender ces nouvelles extensions, les impacts et les possibilités offertes dans le navigateur, dont voici les diapos (<em>slides</em>)  :</p>

 
<div style="margin-bottom: 5px;"> <strong><a href="https://www.slideshare.net/hellosct1/introduction-webextensions-v2" title="Introduction webextensions (v2)">Introduction aux WebExtensions</a> </strong> par <strong><a href="https://www.slideshare.net/hellosct1">Christophe Villeneuve</a></strong> </div>



<p>Pour illustrer ces explications, il a monté une petite animation pour mieux comprendre l’anatomie des WebExtensions. Il l’a appelée <a href="https://addons.mozilla.org/fr/firefox/addon/screen-saver/" hreflang="fr" title="Screen Saver / Economisateur d'écran par hellosct1 – Modules pour Firefox">Screen saver</a>. Vous pouvez en  consulter les sources sur le <a href="https://github.com/hellosct1/screensaver-webextensions" hreflang="fr" title="Dépôt Screen saver en WebExtensions">dépôt GitHub</a>.</p>


<p><img alt="Christophe Fernandes et Athanase Kalantzakis - iGraal" src="https://blog.mozfr.org/dotclear/public/MozillaParis/webextensions/.igraal_s.jpg" style="float: left; margin: 0 1em 1em 0;" /></p>


<p>Juste après, ce furent Christophe Fernandes et Athanase Kalantzakis de <a href="https://fr.igraal.com/" hreflang="fr" title="iGraal cashback">iGraal</a> qui ont montré à travers leur expérience professionnelle l’utilisation des extensions en général et des WebExtensions en particulier.</p>


<div style="margin-bottom: 5px;"><strong><a href="https://www.slideshare.net/christophefernandes/igraal-et-les-webextensions" title="iGraal et les webextensions">iGraal et les WebExtensions</a></strong> par <strong><a href="https://www.slideshare.net/christophefernandes">Christophe Fernandes</a></strong> </div>



<p>Nous ne doutons pas que notre second événement pourra, comme le premier, allier apprentissage et bonne humeur. Nous comptons donc sur vous pour ces 2 journées.</p>


<p>Pour venir…</p>

<p style="margin: 2em 0 1em 2em; line-height: 1.8em;"><a href="https://www.mozilla.org/en-US/contact/spaces/paris/" title="Mozilla Spaces Paris"><img alt="Mozilla Spaces Paris" src="https://blog.mozfr.org/dotclear/public/MozillaParis/20170109/.mozillaspaces_paris_s.png" style="float: right; margin: 0 0 1em 1em;" /></a><strong>Vendredi 17 novembre 2017 à 19 h 00</strong><br />
<a href="https://www.mozilla.org/">Fondation Mozilla</a><br />
<strong>16 bis, boulevard Montmartre</strong>, Paris 9ᵉ (<a href="https://www.openstreetmap.org/node/2883451098#map=18/48.87195/2.34215" hreflang="fr" title="OpenStreetMap">plan libre</a>)<br />
<em>Accès handicapé</em><br />
<br />
<a href="https://blog.mozfr.org/dotclear/public/Firefox_OS/station-gare.png"><img alt="" src="https://blog.mozfr.org/dotclear/public/Firefox_OS/station-gare.png" style="float: left; margin: 0 1em 1em 0;" /></a>Métro : préférez <strong>Grands Boulevards</strong><br />
(sortie <strong>Musée Grévin</strong>)<br />
<br />
<a href="https://github.com/mozfr/besogne/wiki/Se-rendre-%C3%A0-Mozilla-Paris" hreflang="fr" title="Se rendre à Mozilla Paris · mozfr/besogne Wiki">Se rendre à Mozilla Paris</a> sur notre wiki.</p>

<address><br />
<a href="https://twitter.com/hellosct1" hreflang="fr" title="Christophe Villeneuve (@hellosct1) sur Twitter">@hellosct1</a> </address>



<p><em>Précédent événement :</em>  <a href="https://blog.mozfr.org/post/2017/10/alchimie-12-apres-2-annees-d-absence" hreflang="fr" title="Alchimie 12, après 2 années d’absence">Alchimie 12, après 2 années d’absence</a></p>


<p><em>Crédit photo :</em> <a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/mozinet/albums/72157662214314018/with/38106494702/" hreflang="fr" title="Meetup Introduction WebExtensions octobre 2017 – Mozilla Paris">Mozinet</a> sous licence <a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/2.0/deed.fr&amp;quot" hreflang="fr" title="Creative Commons — Attribution - partage dans les mêmes conditions 2.0 Générique — CC BY-SA 2.0">CC By-SA 2.0</a>.</p>]]>
  </description>
  <pubDate>Sat, 04 Nov 2017 01:24:12 +0000</pubDate>
  
</item>

<item>
  <title>Official Reps Blog - Resources Reps, what’s next?</title>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.mozilla.org/mozillareps/?p=515</guid>
  <link>https://blog.mozilla.org/mozillareps/2017/11/01/resources-reps-whats-next/</link>
  <description>
    <![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/christosbacharakis/24555180461" title="IMG_8366.CR2"><img alt="IMG_8366.CR2" height="683" src="https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1537/24555180461_93f876d1b2_b.jpg" width="1024" /></a></p>
<p>In the previous <a href="https://kelimuttu.github.io/rep-resources-training/">blog post</a>, I wrote about the learnings that we got from the initial training session. And last Friday, we just <a href="https://discourse.mozilla.org/t/resources-track-applications-are-now-open/18367/12?u=rizki_kelimutu">announced</a> the new graduates from the final phase of Resources Rep training. The assessment was made during the 3 weeks of the training (whether group or individual exercises) that started on the 2nd of October until 21st of October 2017. You can also see the full list of the Rep Resources graduates in the <a href="https://reps.mozilla.org/people/#/group/resources/">Reps portal</a>. But I would like to quickly take you back on the initial purpose of Resources Reps.</p>
<p><b>What is a Resources Rep?</b></p>
<p>The idea behind the Resources Reps  is to have specialized Reps who are trained to help communities and other fellow Reps to plan strategically how they use the resources that the Reps program offers. This will ensures that resources of the program are used in the most impactful way and according to the<a href="https://discourse.mozilla.org/t/budget-allocation-q1-2/14650"> guidance</a> provided by Mozilla’s strategy and the Council.</p>
<p><b>When did the training happened?</b></p>
<p>The training sessions happened in 3 phases. The first one, which was the trial training, happened during 24th of July – 12th of August 2017. We asked  6 Reps to participate on this trial session to help us improve the training. After the trial training, we then opened the application for the rest of the Reps and decided to carry on with the first phase of the training with the India applicants during 11th of September – 1st of October. Finally, the last phase happened on the 2nd of October – 21st of October.</p>
<p>During the 3 weeks of the training, the candidates were asked to go through the training material and complete the quiz every  week. And in the end of each week (we decided to have the meeting on the weekend), we scheduled a video meeting for an hour in order to have work and discuss on the subject together.</p>
<p><b>What did we learn from the overall training?</b></p>
<p>On the trial training, the participants helped  a lot in terms of improving the content of the training. Thanks to them, now we have the <a href="https://wiki.mozilla.org/ReMo/SOPs/Budget/Receipts_guide">receipt guideline</a> to help the Rep identify which receipts are acceptable and which are not.</p>
<p>On the first phase of the training with Reps from India, we were experimenting with a new video conference tool, which surprisingly performed so much better than the tool that we usually use.</p>
<p>And on the second phase, I learned a lot about accessibility issues. Since we need to accommodate so many time zones, I decided to break the meeting into 2 sessions in each weekend. The first session is for the Asia, Europe, and Africa, and the other session is for the Pacific people who lived in North or South America.</p>
<p>The first meeting was rather challenging since we had people with problems on communication (more specifically a deaf participant and a person that was not able to follow up in English). This came to me as a shock, because that was something I was not prepared for. But fortunately, with some love of the local community, we were able to have an effective meeting. It’s super amazing to see how people were willing to help each other in the training. It was also a reminder for me to think about accessibility in advance for our future activities. For example like providing dial in details for a meeting could be so much beneficial for some people who don’t have access to a PC and can only join via phone. Or checking on the participants before the meeting in case there’s somebody who need special support. Because if we want to excel on diversity and inclusion, then we need to take further action to accommodate everyone.</p>
<p><b>How can I apply to be a Resources Rep?</b></p>
<p>For now we’re in the process of evaluating our current graduates. So in the meantime, we are not accepting more applications. But there’s a possibility we will reopen the application in the future. We’ll let you know for sure.</p>
<p><b>What’s next?</b></p>
<p>New Reps that  don’t have access to the budget and swag, can now ask for help from these <a href="https://wiki.mozilla.org/ReMo/Resources">Resources Rep</a>. We will no longer need to assign the bug to the mentor if the request was made by a Resources Rep. And instead it will go directly to the review team. And ideally, the new Reps should choose Resources Rep who’s close to their region. So, for example if I’m a new Rep from the US, I will ask for help from <a href="https://reps.mozilla.org/u/hashrocket/">Jason</a> who in this case is the Resources Rep who live the closest to me. You can also see the group on the <a href="https://reps.mozilla.org/people/#/group/resources/">reps portal</a>.</p>
<p>We’re also going to reshuffle the Review Team members in the near future. The Review Team is now discussing the recommendation list from the current Resources Rep to be sent to the council for the future candidates of the Review team. We’ll keep you updated for the process.</p>
<p>I also would like to thank the participants of the Resources Rep training. And especially for those who always make the time on their weekend to join the meeting in each week. Congratulations!</p>]]>
  </description>
  <pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2017 16:52:15 +0000</pubDate>
  
</item>

<item>
  <title>Christophe Villeneuve - Firefox et sécurité vendredi à Associalibre à Bruxelles</title>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">urn:md5:a0d8aa5ccd3ae166e3c72d690359dc92</guid>
  <link>https://blog.mozfr.org/post/2017/10/firefox-et-securite-vendredi-associalibre-bruxelles</link>
  <description>
    <![CDATA[<p><a href="https://blog.mozfr.org/dotclear/public/mozfr/evenements/Associalibre/associalibre2015_april1.jpg"><img alt="Public UbuCon Europe" src="https://blog.mozfr.org/dotclear/public/mozfr/evenements/Associalibre/.associalibre2015_april1_s.jpg" style="float: right; margin: 0 0 1em 1em;" /></a> La <a href="http://www.lasemainenumerique.be/" hreflang="fr" title="La semaine numérique du 16 au 27 octobre 2017">semaine numérique</a> est un rendez-vous incontournable en Belgique qui se déroulera du 16 au 27 octobre 2017. À cette occasion, pour la troisième année consécutive, <a href="https://2017.associalibre.be/" hreflang="fr" title="AssociaLibre 2017">Associalibre</a> participera à ce rendez-vous et vous invite les <strong>19 et 20 octobre prochain à l’ISIB à Bruxelles</strong> (Belgique).</p>


<p>Comme pour les éditions précédentes, le programme d’Associalibre sera de qualité avec de nombreuses conférences, des ateliers, la présentation d’outils accessibles et destinés à une utilisation dans le monde associatif et enseignant.</p>    <p>L’événement ouvre ses portes le jeudi 19 octobre avec une conférence-débat inaugurale sur la thématique : <a href="https://2017.associalibre.be/?Conferences-Debat-public" hreflang="fr" title="Conférences - Débat public - AssociaLibre 2017">du respect des données en réseaux sociaux</a>. Tout au long de la journée du 20 octobre seront ensuite proposés des conférences, des ateliers pratiques, des présentations d’outils accessibles, etc.</p>


<p>Bien que focalisés sur les sujets du Libre et des solutions alternatives, les domaines abordés pourront concerner tout le monde, à commencer par tous les utilisateurs d’Internet. Vous pourrez ainsi trouver des conférences ou des ateliers relatifs à la protection de la vie privée, aux hébergements alternatifs, à la suite LibreOffice, à Framasoft, à la cartographie libre OpenStreetMap, à l’autodéfense numérique, etc.</p>


<p><a href="https://blog.mozfr.org/dotclear/public/mozfr/evenements/Associalibre/associalibre2015_april_atelier2.jpg"><img alt="Public UbuCon Europe" src="https://blog.mozfr.org/dotclear/public/mozfr/evenements/Associalibre/.associalibre2015_april_atelier2_m.jpg" style="display: table; margin: 0 auto;" /></a></p>


<h3>Mozilla</h3>


<p>Du côté de Mozilla, notre Mozilien <a href="https://mozillians.org/u/Benoit/" hreflang="fr" title="Mozillien Benoit Leseul">Benoit Leseul</a> interviendra le vendredi 20 octobre pour :</p>
<ul>
<li>10h00 – une conférence sur le thème de <a href="https://2017.associalibre.be/?Firefox-et-ses-aspect-de-securite" hreflang="fr" title="Firefox et ses aspects de sécurité">Firefox et ses aspects de sécurité</a> ;</li>
<li>10h30 – un atelier sur <a href="https://2017.associalibre.be/?Firefox-et-ses-aspect-de-securite#atelier_firefox" hreflang="fr" title="Firefox et ses aspects de sécurité : Atelier - AssociaLibre 2017">Firefox et ses extensions – comment ils protègent votre vie privée numérique</a>.</li>
</ul>


<p>Vous pouvez consulter le <a href="https://2017.associalibre.be/?-Programme-" hreflang="fr" title="Programme complet associalibre 2017">programme complet</a> sur le site de l’événement.</p>


<p>Enfin, pour vous rendre à ce rendez-vous <strong>gratuit et ouvert à tous</strong>, une page d’<a href="https://2017.associalibre.be/?-Infos-pratiques-" hreflang="fr" title="Infos pratiques AssociaLibre 2017">infos pratiques</a> est disponible. Et nous vous y attendons nombreux.</p>


<h3>Programme</h3>

<ul>
<li>19 octobre à partir de 19h30 – <a href="https://2017.associalibre.be/?Conferences-Debat-public" hreflang="fr" title="conférences-debat">Conférence débat</a></li>
<li>20 octobre de 9h00 à 16h00 – <a href="https://2017.associalibre.be/?-Programme-" hreflang="fr" title="Conférences – ateliers">Conférences – ateliers pratiques</a></li>
</ul>


<p><a href="https://blog.mozfr.org/dotdotclear/public/mozfr/evenements/Associalibre/associalibre2017-image4.png"><img alt="Public UbuCon Europe" src="https://blog.mozfr.org/dotclear/public/mozfr/evenements/Associalibre/.associalibre2017-image4_m.png" style="display: table; margin: 0 auto;" /></a></p>


<h3>L’affiche</h3>


<p><a href="https://blog.mozfr.org/dotclear/public/mozfr/evenements/Associalibre/associalibre2017-image2.jpg"><img alt="Public UbuCon Europe" src="https://blog.mozfr.org/dotclear/public/mozfr/evenements/Associalibre/.associalibre2017-image2_m.jpg" style="display: table; margin: 0 auto;" /></a></p>


<h3>S’y rendre</h3>


<p><strong>ISIB – Institut Supérieur Industriel de Bruxelles</strong><br />
Rue Royale, 150<br />
1000 Bruxelles<br />
Belgique</p>


<p><strong>Accès en transport en commun pour la rue Royale 150</strong><br />
SNCB<br />
Gare de Bruxelles – Congrès<br />
STIB<br />
Tram 92 et 93 – Arrêt Congrès<br />
Métro : station Madou, Parc ou Botanique</p>

<address><br />
<a href="https://twitter.com/hellosct1" hreflang="fr" title="Christophe Villeneuve (@hellosct1) sur Twitter">@hellosct1</a> </address>



<p><em>Précédent événement :</em>  <a href="https://blog.mozfr.org/post/2017/10/Introduction-aux-WebExtensions-lundi-prochain-chez-Mozilla-Paris" hreflang="fr" title="Introduction aux WebExtensions lundi prochain chez Mozilla Paris (12 oct. 2017) Communauté Mozilla francophone">Introduction aux WebExtensions lundi prochain chez Mozilla Paris</a></p>


<p><em>Crédit photo :</em>  Album Associalibre 2015. Tous droits réservés.</p>]]>
  </description>
  <pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2017 20:23:40 +0000</pubDate>
  
</item>

<item>
  <title>Christophe Villeneuve - Nouveautés Firefox et patrimoine à Mozilla Paris</title>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">urn:md5:53dbafae8aa3db2f6394179c2ebca374</guid>
  <link>https://blog.mozfr.org/post/2017/10/Nouveautes-Firefox-patrimoine-Mozilla-Paris</link>
  <description>
    <![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/mozinet/23981307468/in/album-72157686796421374/" title="Salle des fêtes – hôtel de Mercy-Argenteau – Mozilla Paris"><img alt="Salle des fêtes – hôtel de Mercy-Argenteau – Mozilla Paris" height="160" src="https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4505/23981307468_92a85debea_m.jpg" style="float: right; margin-left: 0.5em;" width="240" /></a>Comme depuis cinq années maintenant, les bureaux classés aux monuments historiques de Mozilla à Paris étaient ouverts au public pour les Journées européennes du patrimoine (<a href="https://blog.mozfr.org/post/2017/09/Mozilla-vous-attend-journees-europeennes-du-patrimoine-2017-16-17-septembre" hreflang="fr" title="Mozilla vous attend aux Journées du patrimoine les 16 et 17 septembre (1er sept. 2017) Communauté Mozilla francophone">voir notre annonce</a>).</p>


<p>Des Mozilliens étaient présents pour faire la visite aux nombreux curieux et pour répondre à leurs questions en particulier sur Photon, les WebExtensions, Sync et Focus, qui étaient tous en démonstration.</p>    <p><br />
Nous avons réalisé une petite vidéo des bureaux de Mozilla pendant les visites (<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-Rl2Iuy_vGc" hreflang="fr" title="Journées européennes du patrimoine 2017 à Mozilla Paris (mise en ligne le 13 oct. 2017) chaîne YouTube de Mozilla francophone (2 min 53)">sur YouTube</a>) :</p>

<div style="text-align: center;">

</div>



<p>La visite de l’hôtel de Mercy-Argenteau commence par les pièces du fond donnant sur le boulevard et remontant au XVIIIᵉ siècle pour finir par le hall (précédemment antichambre) et la salle des fêtes aux décors de la fin du XIXᵉ siècle. C’est là que les visiteurs pouvaient découvrir les dernières nouveautés du locataire actuel, Mozilla :</p>

<div style="text-align: center;">
<a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/mozinet/37122090484/in/album-72157686796421374/" title="Salle des fêtes – hôtel de Mercy-Argenteau – Mozilla Paris"><img alt="Salle des fêtes – hôtel de Mercy-Argenteau – Mozilla Paris" height="333" src="https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4458/37122090484_d7d05855ac.jpg" width="500" /></a>
<em style="display: block; text-align: center;">Salle des fêtes : visites et ateliers Mozilla</em>
</div>



<p><a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/mozinet/36899233090/in/album-72157686796421374/" title="Salle des fêtes – hôtel de Mercy-Argenteau – Mozilla Paris"><img alt="Salle des fêtes – hôtel de Mercy-Argenteau – Mozilla Paris" height="320" src="https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4331/36899233090_80ea8a2e30_n.jpg" style="float: left; margin-right: 0.5em;" width="168" /></a>À tout seigneur, tout honneur : un atelier Photon permettait de découvrir la nouvelle interface épurée qui sera disponible dans Firefox 57 (<a href="https://blog.mozfr.org/post/2017/10/Allumez-vos-moteurs-Firefox-Quantum-beta-Developer-Edition" hreflang="fr" title="Allumez vos moteurs – Firefox Quantum passe en bêta et en Developer Edition (1er oct. 2017) Communauté Mozilla francophone">déjà disponible en version bêta</a>).</p>


<p>Les WebExtensions qui seront les seules extensions présentes dans la prochaine version 57 de Firefox faisaient l’objet d’un second atelier.</p>


<p><a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/mozinet/37122094974/in/album-72157686796421374/" title="Salle des fêtes – hôtel de Mercy-Argenteau – Mozilla Paris"><img alt="Salle des fêtes – hôtel de Mercy-Argenteau – Mozilla Paris" height="160" src="https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4461/37122094974_d5902f4b89_m.jpg" style="float: right; margin-left: 0.5em;" width="240" /></a>Un troisième atelier était commun à Sync, le composant de synchronisation des données personnelles de Firefox sur les différents systèmes, et à <a href="https://blog.mozfr.org/post/2017/09/Firefox-Focus-pour-Android-onglets" hreflang="fr" title="Firefox Focus pour Android se met aux onglets">Firefox Focus</a>, l’application mobile de Mozilla axée vie privée.</p>

<div style="text-align: center; clear: both; margin-top: 2em;">
<a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/mozinet/37122092174/in/album-72157686796421374/" title="Salle des fêtes – hôtel de Mercy-Argenteau – Mozilla Paris"><img alt="Salle des fêtes – hôtel de Mercy-Argenteau – Mozilla Paris" height="333" src="https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4504/37122092174_6f96426aca.jpg" width="500" /></a>
<em style="display: block;">Nos bénévoles aux petits soins pour leurs visiteurs de tous âges</em>
<br />
<br /><a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/mozinet/37832381621/in/album-72157686796421374/" title="Le hall ou précédemment l'antichambre – hôtel de Mercy-Argenteau – Mozilla Paris"><img alt="Le hall ou précédemment l'antichambre – hôtel de Mercy-Argenteau – Mozilla Paris" height="333" src="https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4467/37832381621_aaba9eb56f.jpg" width="500" /></a>
<em style="display: block;">Le hall ou précédemment l’antichambre</em>
</div>



<p>Nous espérons bien vous voir aux prochaines Journées du patrimoine les 15 et 16 septembre 2018. Vous visiterez ces superbes décors classés et nous aurons des nouveautés à vous montrer, n’en doutez pas.</p>

<div style="text-align: center;">
<a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/mozinet/37832392691/in/album-72157686796421374/" title="Salons – hôtel de Mercy-Argenteau – Mozilla Paris"><img alt="Salons – hôtel de Mercy-Argenteau – Mozilla Paris" height="500" src="https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4484/37832392691_94ff48c55f.jpg" width="333" /></a>
<em style="display: block;">Les bureaux de Mozilla donnant sur le boulevard (XVIIᵉ)</em>
</div>



<p>Retrouvez davantage de photos prises ce week-end dans ces albums :</p>

<div style="text-align: center;">
<a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/mozinet/albums/72157686796421374" title="Mozilla Paris – Journées du patrimoine 2017"><img alt="Mozilla Paris – Journées du patrimoine 2017" src="https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4353/37165823521_25569c264b_z.jpg" /></a>
<br />
<a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/26276571@N03/albums/72157687221335074" title="Journées du Patrimoine 2017"><img alt="Journées du Patrimoine 2017" height="360" src="https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4475/37330311956_8b594d3c6c_z.jpg" width="640" /></a>

</div>

<address><br />
<a href="https://twitter.com/hellosct1" hreflang="fr" title="Christophe Villeneuve (@hellosct1) sur Twitter">@hellosct1</a> et <a href="https://twitter.com/Mozinet" hreflang="fr" title="Mozinet (@Mozinet) sur Twitter">@Mozinet</a>
</address>



<p><em>Précédent événement :</em> <a href="https://blog.mozfr.org/post/2017/10/Rien-a-cacher-vraiment-nothing-to-hide" hreflang="fr" title="Rien à cacher, vraiment ? (20 oct. 2017) Communauté Mozilla francophone">Rien à cacher, vraiment ?</a></p>


<p><em>Crédit photos :</em> de l’article, Mozinet sous licence <a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/2.0/deed.fr" hreflang="fr" title="Creative Commons — Attribution - pas d’utilisation commerciale - partage dans les mêmes conditions 2.0 générique — CC BY-NC-SA 2.0">CC By-NC-SA 2.0</a>.</p>]]>
  </description>
  <pubDate>Sat, 21 Oct 2017 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  
</item>

<item>
  <title>Michal Stanke - The story of me@mozilla</title>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://michal.stanke.cz/2017/10/20/the-story-of-me-at-mozilla</guid>
  <link>http://michal.stanke.cz/2017/10/20/the-story-of-me-at-mozilla.html</link>
  <description>
    <![CDATA[<p>After our successful presence on the <a href="https://www.linuxdays.cz/2017/">LinuxDays</a> conference in Prague, I have been asked by a <a href="https://www.linuxexpres.cz/">Linux Expres</a> for an interview, how I get to the Mozilla community, what I do there, etc. <del>The article is not public yet</del> The article went out <a href="https://www.linuxexpres.cz/rozhovor/michal-stanke-ceska-komunita-by-mohla-prosazovat-mobilni">today</a>, but I have realized I never told this story to the Mozilla community itself. So take some popcorn and make yourself comfortable…</p>

<p>Back in times when I thought PowerPoint presentations are the masterpiece of computer science and their quality score is determined by the number of animations per slide, my Internet Explorer got sick. After an attempt to change the homepage in hope it will stop showing me ads everywhere, I have decided I need a new browser. I knew some people online and asked them for a recommendation, and their answers were Opera and Firefox. I never saw any of them in action before, so I dived into the dark unknown waters of the internet to download them for testing. My first impression from Opera was it’s too complex and complicated to change the homepage and import bookmarks, while Firefox did that all for me when I clicked all the <em>Next &gt;</em> buttons. The winner was clear.</p>

<p>That was <strong>Firefox 2.0</strong>, way different from Internet Explorer. When exploring the user documentation to help me a bit, I found an information, that 3.0 is imminent. Wow, a browser that is being developed and will have a new <em>version</em>. Super cool for someone using the old IE! But the documentation did not helped me much actually, which drove me right into the registration form of the <strong>Czech community forum</strong>, and here my community story begins.</p>

<p>After some time, I realized that I know answers for other questions on the forum, so I started answering. About the same time I have decided to start using all Mozilla-based applications I can make use of, namely Thunderbird and Instantbird (which I <strong>started localizing</strong> soon). Later the Mozilla.cz team offered me to translate some <strong>articles on SUMO</strong> and websites like AMO, but for me the Czech community forum was still the top until 2014, when Pavel Cvrček (JasnaPaka) offered me to <strong>translate Thunderbird</strong> on my own. That was huge responsibility for me, but also recognition. I thought that’s the most you can achieve, I felt like a real boss.</p>

<p>The next year, 2015, was like a big spinning wheel, outlined by the <strong>Mozilla.cz restart</strong> initiative led by Pavel to rebuild the Mozilla.cz website content (and design) and utilize as much of Mozilla infrastructure as we can. The motto was “Mozilla is doing many things, and they do them right”, it’s not necessary to update own versions of user documentation anymore. The second half of the year was very turbulent. Pavel decided to forward me the responsibility for <strong>Mozilla.cz content</strong> and <strong>Firefox localization</strong>, leaving the community projects due to the lack of time. At the end of the year, the changes in the community probably became so visible, that I have been invited to <strong>Mozlando</strong>, to meet my first non-Czech Mozillians in person.</p>

<p>The last two years I will sum in a sentence or two. I try to act like a community peer for every l10n and support related project in Mozilla, I became a Rep, and after our localization community grew over 4 people, I am unable to name all the milestones we have outlined and achieved. The last two years are not really a story of me@mozilla, but a story of <strong>czech-community@mozilla</strong>.</p>

<p>Now you may think that my involvement with the global Mozilla community is pretty short. And you are right. I am around the global stuff since 2014/15, still having longer experience with support forums answers than anything else. But for me that illustrates how powerful and dynamic the Mozilla community is.</p>]]>
  </description>
  <pubDate>Fri, 20 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  
</item>

<item>
  <title>Xavier Martorell - My Story with Mozilla</title>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">https://yunit0.tumblr.com/post/166545352987</guid>
  <link>https://yunit0.tumblr.com/post/166545352987</link>
  <description>
    <![CDATA[<p>I was in high school,
sitting in the Computers room, taking part of a boring and monotonous class
about Office IT. Because of that, I decided to open Firefox and start surfing
the web for some entertainment to make the time passed faster. So, I clicked in
the Firefox logo, Firefox popped-up and as soon as it opened, I realized about of
a yellow square at the bottom of Firefox asking me to took part of Mozilla and
become a volunteer. </p>



<p>In that moment, I
was dubitative because I didn’t really know what to do or if it was worth it
but I recalled a conversation I had with my best friend at that time about
Mozilla and its principles and decided to give it a try… I pressed the yellow
squared button and it redirected me into a webpage that showed me all the activities
I could join  (Labs, Localization,
Coding, Marketing, QA…).   After a few minutes, I decided that I wanted
to help with QA, testing some products as Firefox Beta, Firefox Nightly or the now
ceased Firefox Aurora because I wanted to make Firefox a better browser with
less bugs and more stability. </p>



<p>Once I clicked
it, it opened my email prompting me to write an E-Mail to the responsible of QA
Area in Mozilla Hispano (who I would know later as Gabriela) stating that I
wanted to contribute in that area and the reasons for it.  I wrote the email and she quickly answered it giving
me some tasks to do in Teambox (A site we used in order to organize tasks and
activities) as well as giving me some mentorship so I could start helping as
fast as possible. </p>

<p> Time passed really
quick and I went from being a newcomer to be part as a member of Mozilla without
with no more mentorship. Anyway, I kept in touch with Gabriela because she was my
friend and still the responsible of the area. As time passed by, I saw a drop
in the participation of the QA area so I proposed Gabriela a new scheme for it.
She really liked the idea and she decided to offer me the possibility of being
co-responsible of the area so I could help her with all the task involved which
I clearly accepted.  

</p><p> A year passed
without a lot of changes, I routinely participated in the friday testdays about
Firefox Beta, we also organized an amazing Spanish testday which was
well-received and well-appreciated for the Hispanic contributors of Mozilla and
I tried to help in other areas like Marketing or Localization.

</p><p> One day, I saw a
notification about a QA/Localization hackathon that would take part in Paris somewhere
near November 2015. The idea of going to Paris to the Mozilla Office really
fascinated me and I applied as fast as I could, wishing to be selected for it
so I could have the opportunity to meet other people as passionate as I for
Mozilla. Somehow, my wishes became true and I got the chance to travel to Paris
and meet some contributors there like Facyber (My great friend Marko) or
Marcia, a nice woman from Mozilla which I only had the pleasure to talk by iRC
and the one who taught us all she could about FirefoxOS in the short time of
two days. It was a really great experience.

</p><p>Sadly, one day,
Mozilla decided to cut off Firefox OS, and that decision took with it some ups
and downs which made some contributors leave the community because they didn’t
see a clear orientation or a clear focus and all the communities of Mozilla around
the world saw a big break on its activities. In that moment, I was really busy
studying for the exams of the university and other stuff so I became really inactive
for a few months and I did not really see what was coming. </p>



<p>Once I returned,
I realized how everything was stopped and I felt really guilty for it. For that
reason, some contributors and I decided that it was time to relaunch the
community and we got down to work for it. At first, we took some surveys and we
decided some goals for the community but this approach didn’t clearly work out,
so some months later, we decided to take it back and we proposed some interesting
new projects to work on and as of today, it seems it has worked because we got
new projects and new contributors working on them. </p>



<p>To conclude, I
have to add that after relaunching the community, I got really motivated so I
decided that it was time to step up and apply to become a Mozilla Rep as other
people recommended me.</p>]]>
  </description>
  <pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2017 20:11:36 +0000</pubDate>
  
</item>

<item>
  <title>Md Shahbaz Alam - MozAarambh Jharkhand RAI University</title>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alamshahbaz.wordpress.com/?p=861</guid>
  <link>https://alamshahbaz.wordpress.com/2017/10/17/mozaarambh-jharkhand-rai-university/</link>
  <description>
    <![CDATA[<p>I started my journey in Mozilla as a contributor to Mozilla Community Rajasthan and met many enthusiasts who inspired me to do  every possible contributions i could do to Mozilla and Open source in general. I am from Jharkhand , after returning from Rajasthan, I met a mozillian from Jharkhand community, <a href="https://mozillians.org/en-US/u/amitsin6h/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Amit Singh</a> , he is very passionate about learning new things and very much like the idea of working in open.</p>
<p>I got to know many problems of the people wanted to contribute. Major problem is the availability of support from Mozilla and Mozilla Reps in general. There are many Reps from this region , but unfortunatly they are working outside this state. They are very helpful in arranging things, but… But they want their presence, they want to hear them in person and want to know their success story, how they came to mozilla and why….. There are many more questions asked by few contributors who wanted to continue the same. I listed their questions and figured out many possible things we could do together to improve the contributions from this region.</p>
<p>I moved to Ranchi officially , it was the time when i was very busy with my work. A phone call rang, it was Amit , wanted to know if i can organize an event in Jharkhand Rai University. I said yes, definitely . He introduced me to Prof. Shudhanshu, after meeting him we fixed the date, 6th Oct. 2017. Made a poster , promoted in Jharkahnd Rai University.</p>
<p><img alt="MozAarambh Poster" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-905" src="https://alamshahbaz.files.wordpress.com/2017/10/mozaarambh-poster.jpg?w=840" /></p>
<p>Event day, we reached the venue on time, we received a warm welcome. Prof. Shudhanshu introduced us infornt of students. I see a hall, full pacekd with students almost 200+ . I introduced myself  and why I choose to contribute to Mozilla and Open source. Students were listening this as if they were sitting in a lecture room. It was the tme to bring out few swags , in a minute everyone was answering questions, asking interesting questions. <strong>Swag has some power!!!!!</strong></p>

<a href="https://alamshahbaz.wordpress.com/2017/10/17/mozaarambh-jharkhand-rai-university/photo6282760985194375150/"><img alt="" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail" height="113" src="https://alamshahbaz.files.wordpress.com/2017/10/photo6282760985194375150.jpg?w=150&amp;h=113" width="150" /></a>
<a href="https://alamshahbaz.wordpress.com/2017/10/17/mozaarambh-jharkhand-rai-university/photo62827609851943751521/"><img alt="" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail" height="113" src="https://alamshahbaz.files.wordpress.com/2017/10/photo62827609851943751521.jpg?w=150&amp;h=113" width="150" /></a>

<p>I started with introduction of Mozilla, Firefox and Open Source. To my surprise everyone knows about these things. Then I got to know that they had one introduction event of mozilla but after that never heard back from that mozillian. Then I introduced them about the mozilla’s products and projects, what actually matters. People were very excited to know about WebVR, Rust and WebCompat .</p>

<a href="https://alamshahbaz.wordpress.com/2017/10/17/mozaarambh-jharkhand-rai-university/photo6282760985194375158/"><img alt="" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail" height="113" src="https://alamshahbaz.files.wordpress.com/2017/10/photo6282760985194375158.jpg?w=150&amp;h=113" width="150" /></a>
<a href="https://alamshahbaz.wordpress.com/2017/10/17/mozaarambh-jharkhand-rai-university/photo6282760985194375148/"><img alt="" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail" height="113" src="https://alamshahbaz.files.wordpress.com/2017/10/photo6282760985194375148.jpg?w=150&amp;h=113" width="150" /></a>

<p>I forgot to introduce the speakers, I had Amit and <a href="https://mozillians.org/en-US/u/Malam1212/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Mahtab</a> with me who was sharing the stage. Amit gave session on WebCompat and even showed a demo on how to file a report. Mahtab gave session on L10n and how a non-coder students still contribute to open source.</p>

<a href="https://alamshahbaz.wordpress.com/2017/10/17/mozaarambh-jharkhand-rai-university/photo62827609851943751461/"><img alt="" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail" height="113" src="https://alamshahbaz.files.wordpress.com/2017/10/photo62827609851943751461.jpg?w=150&amp;h=113" width="150" /></a>
<a href="https://alamshahbaz.wordpress.com/2017/10/17/mozaarambh-jharkhand-rai-university/photo6282760985194375157/"><img alt="" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail" height="113" src="https://alamshahbaz.files.wordpress.com/2017/10/photo6282760985194375157.jpg?w=150&amp;h=113" width="150" /></a>

<p>Event concluded with a group picture. A mozilla style of conclusion!!</p>
<p><img alt="photo6282760985194375143" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-904" src="https://alamshahbaz.files.wordpress.com/2017/10/photo6282760985194375143.jpg?w=840" /></p>
<p>Actual thing happend after the event , there were 80 students who wanted to know the possibilities and ways to involve with Mozilla and it’s projects. We get back to the hall ,selected few students who have shown their interest in making a club. I introduced Mozilla Campus Club to them. We formed a team and created Telegram groups so that we stay in loop.</p>

<a href="https://alamshahbaz.wordpress.com/2017/10/17/mozaarambh-jharkhand-rai-university/photo6282760985194375154/"><img alt="" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail" height="150" src="https://alamshahbaz.files.wordpress.com/2017/10/photo6282760985194375154.jpg?w=113&amp;h=150" width="113" /></a>
<a href="https://alamshahbaz.wordpress.com/2017/10/17/mozaarambh-jharkhand-rai-university/photo62827609851943751533/"><img alt="" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail" height="150" src="https://alamshahbaz.files.wordpress.com/2017/10/photo62827609851943751533.jpg?w=113&amp;h=150" width="113" /></a>
<a href="https://alamshahbaz.wordpress.com/2017/10/17/mozaarambh-jharkhand-rai-university/photo6282760985194375156/"><img alt="" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail" height="113" src="https://alamshahbaz.files.wordpress.com/2017/10/photo6282760985194375156.jpg?w=150&amp;h=113" width="150" /></a>
<a href="https://alamshahbaz.wordpress.com/2017/10/17/mozaarambh-jharkhand-rai-university/photo6282760985194375145/"><img alt="" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail" height="112" src="https://alamshahbaz.files.wordpress.com/2017/10/photo6282760985194375145.jpg?w=150&amp;h=112" width="150" /></a>

<p>Mozilla Jharkhand has a <a href="https://www.facebook.com/groups/mozilla.jharkhand" rel="noopener" target="_blank">facebook group</a> and after the event people joined this group in hige number, from 170 we reached to 246 in a single day. Not only they joined in this group, they have introduced themself to this group, which i never seen in other community as this scale. This shows they are very active and only need a correct Mentor to guide them.</p>
<p>I will love to do the role of Mentor to them. And next day we were rocking on local newspaper. Planning a series of events in this college to educate them and make a good contributor.</p>
<p><img alt="22254677_1860036047345475_1303368950574395804_o" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-915" src="https://alamshahbaz.files.wordpress.com/2017/10/22254677_1860036047345475_1303368950574395804_o.jpg?w=840" /></p>
<p>“Doing good is a part of our code.” – Mozilla</p>
<p>“Learn , Teach n be Innovative” – Shahbaz</p>
<p>Event Link : <a href="https://reps.mozilla.org/e/mozaarambh-rai-university/" rel="nofollow">https://reps.mozilla.org/e/mozaarambh-rai-university/</a></p>
<p> </p><br />  <a href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/alamshahbaz.wordpress.com/861/" rel="nofollow"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/alamshahbaz.wordpress.com/861/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" height="1" src="https://pixel.wp.com/b.gif?host=alamshahbaz.wordpress.com&amp;blog=73514675&amp;post=861&amp;subd=alamshahbaz&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" />]]>
  </description>
  <pubDate>Tue, 17 Oct 2017 15:52:05 +0000</pubDate>
  
</item>

<item>
  <title>Christophe Villeneuve - Introduction aux WebExtensions lundi prochain chez Mozilla Paris</title>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">urn:md5:4262c6c53890e5fc080de2c669b5e819</guid>
  <link>https://blog.mozfr.org/post/2017/10/Introduction-aux-WebExtensions-lundi-prochain-chez-Mozilla-Paris</link>
  <description>
    <![CDATA[<p><a href="https://blog.mozfr.org/dotclear/public/mozfr/evenements/meetup/salle-mozilla-paris.png"><img alt="Salle Meetup Mozilla Parist" src="https://blog.mozfr.org/dotclear/public/mozfr/evenements/meetup/.salle-mozilla-paris_s.png" style="float: right; margin: 0 0 1em 1em;" /></a> Le prochain Firefox – Firefox Quantum – verra de nombreuses et radicales nouveautés arriver jusqu’au grand public. Un de ces changements sera que Firefox n’acceptera plus que les WebExtensions.</p>

<p style="margin-left: 1em; padding-left: 0.5em;">(Re)lire : <a href="https://blog.mozfr.org/post/2017/10/Allumez-vos-moteurs-Firefox-Quantum-beta-Developer-Edition" hreflang="fr" title="Allumez vos moteurs – Firefox Quantum passe en bêta et en Developer Edition (1er oct. 2017) annonce de Nick Nguyen traduite par la communauté Mozilla francophone">Allumez vos moteurs – Firefox Quantum passe en bêta et en Developer Edition</a> et <a href="https://blog.mozfr.org/post/2017/09/Firefox-57-chacun-peut-contribuer-a-son-succes" hreflang="fr" title="Firefox 57 : chacun peut contribuer à son succès (9 sept. 2017) Communauté Mozilla francophone">Firefox 57 : chacun peut contribuer à son succès</a></p>    <p><br />
Les WebExtensions, initiées par Google pour Chrome et adoptées par Microsoft pour Edge, sont la solution qui va permettre de développer aisément des extensions multinavigateurs.</p>


<p>Le rendez-vous d’aujourd’hui est destiné à toutes les personnes intéressées par cette mutation dans leur navigateur préféré, mais aussi aux personnes curieuses en matière de développements web.</p>


<p>Le programme de la soirée se composera :</p>


<p>Tout d’abord, notre Mozillien Christophe Villeneuve (<em>Mozilla Rep</em>), contributeur aux WebExtensions, parlera :</p>

<blockquote>
<p>Une présentation de Christophe Villeneuve pour mieux appréhender ce nouveau type d’extensions, les impacts et les possibilités offertes dans le navigateur, ainsi que les endroits disponibles dans le navigateur pour ajouter vos fonctionnalités, le tout cadencé d’exemples.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Ensuite, les développeurs Christophe Fernandes et Athanase Kalantzakis apporteront leurs expériences utilisateur dans le milieu professionnel en présentant l’application concrètes des API WebExtensions et la problématique du développement <em>cross browser</em> :</p>

<blockquote>
<p>Une présentation de Christophe Fernandes et Athanase Kalantzakis proposeront un regard dans le milieu de l’entreprise avec les points suivants :</p>
<ul>
<li>iGraal et son extension ;</li>
<li>présentation d’API intéressantes utilisées au sein de leur extension ;</li>
<li>la problématique du <em>cross browser</em> avec les WebExtensions : notamment via l’utilisation du <em>polyfill webextension</em>.</li>
</ul>
</blockquote>


<p>Enfin, pour terminer la soirée, il sera possible d’échanger de manière informelle autour de ces deux sujets, mais aussi sur Firefox.</p>


<p>L’événement est <strong>gratuit, mais sur inscription</strong> sur <a href="https://www.meetup.com/fr-FR/Firefox-France-User-Group/events/243324869/" hreflang="fr" title="Meetup Octobre 2017 : Introductions aux WebExtensions">sa page Meetup</a>.</p>

<p style="margin: 2em 0 1em 2em; line-height: 1.8em;">
<a href="https://www.mozilla.org/en-US/contact/spaces/paris/" title="Mozilla Spaces Paris"><img alt="Mozilla Spaces Paris" src="https://blog.mozfr.org/dotclear/public/MozillaParis/20170109/.mozillaspaces_paris_s.png" style="float: right; margin: 0 0 1em 1em;" /></a><strong>Lundi 16 octobre 2017 à 19 h 00</strong><br />
<a href="https://www.mozilla.org/">Fondation Mozilla</a><br />
<strong>16 bis, boulevard Montmartre</strong>, Paris 9ᵉ (<a href="https://www.openstreetmap.org/node/2883451098#map=18/48.87195/2.34215" hreflang="fr" title="OpenStreetMap">plan libre</a>)<br />
<em>Accès handicapé</em><br /><br />
<a href="https://blog.mozfr.org/dotclear/public/Firefox_OS/station-gare.png"><img alt="" src="https://blog.mozfr.org/dotclear/public/Firefox_OS/station-gare.png" style="float: left; margin: 0 1em 1em 0;" /></a>Métro : préférez <strong>Grands Boulevards</strong><br />
(sortie <strong>Musée Grévin</strong>)<br /><br />
<a href="https://github.com/mozfr/besogne/wiki/Se-rendre-%C3%A0-Mozilla-Paris" hreflang="fr" title="Se rendre à Mozilla Paris · mozfr/besogne Wiki">Se rendre à Mozilla Paris</a> sur notre wiki.</p>

<address><br />
<a href="https://twitter.com/hellosct1" hreflang="fr" title="Christophe Villeneuve (@hellosct1) sur Twitter">@hellosct1</a>
</address>

<p><em>Précédent événement :</em> <a href="https://blog.mozfr.org/post/2017/10/firefox-quantum-57-sprint-a-vous-de-jouer" hreflang="fr" title="Firefox Quantum 57 Sprint, à vous de jouer ! (5 oct. 2017) Communauté Mozilla francophone">Firefox Quantum 57 Sprint, à vous de jouer !</a></p>

<p><em>Crédit photo :</em> <a href="https://france.debian.net/posts/2014/Meetup_Paris_06_2014/" hreflang="fr" title="Meetup Debian juin 2014 – Mozilla Paris">Meetup Debian juin 2014</a>.</p>]]>
  </description>
  <pubDate>Fri, 13 Oct 2017 05:47:58 +0000</pubDate>
  
</item>

<item>
  <title>Christophe Villeneuve - Firefox Quantum 57 Sprint, à vous de jouer !</title>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">urn:md5:3f83c3f6c3a84a20b40fb422b3a3ffd7</guid>
  <link>https://blog.mozfr.org/post/2017/10/firefox-quantum-57-sprint-a-vous-de-jouer</link>
  <description>
    <![CDATA[<p><a href="https://blog.mozfr.org/dotclear/public/mozfr/evenements/firefox-quantum-57.jpg"><img alt="Écran de début de la présentation du sprint Firefox Quantum 57" src="https://blog.mozfr.org/dotclear/public/mozfr/evenements/firefox-quantum-57.jpg" style="float: right; margin: 0 0 1em 1em; width: 250px;" /></a> Après le <a href="https://blog.mozfr.org/post/2017/09/sprintons-pour-firefox-quantum-57-4-octobre-paris" hreflang="fr" title="Sprintons pour Firefox Quantum 57 le 4 octobre à Paris (27 sept. 2017) Communauté Mozilla francophone">sprint</a> pour <strong>Firefox Quantum 57</strong> couru en personne chez <strong>Mozilla Paris</strong>, nous vous passons le relais pour continuer le sprint de <strong>chez vous</strong> et vous pouvez courir <strong>jusqu’au 8 octobre</strong> prochain.</p>

<p>Pour cela, nous mettons à votre disposition la vidéo de présentation et les diapos (<em>slides</em>).</p>    <div style="text-align: center; clear: right;">
<div style="margin-bottom: 5px;"><strong><a href="https://www.slideshare.net/hellosct1/firefox-quatum57" title="Firefox Quantum 57">Firefox Quantum 57</a></strong> par <strong><a href="https://www.slideshare.net/hellosct1">Christophe Villeneuve</a></strong></div>
</div>

<div style="text-align: center; margin-top: 2em;"><em style="display: block;">Présentation par Pascal Chevrel (Mozilla) et Christophe Villeneuve (Mozilla Rep)<br />
du Firefox Quantum Sprint de Paris (22 min 28) sur <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=OSaS1iB3DPc" hreflang="fr" title="Firefox Quantum Sprint à Mozilla Paris (ajoutée le 4 oct. 2017) chaîne YouTube de Mozilla francophone">sur YouTube</a></em></div>

<p>Si vous rencontrez des problèmes ou avez besoin d’échanger avec nous, vous pouvez nous solliciter sur notre canal <a href="https://github.com/mozfr/besogne/wiki/IRC" hreflang="fr" title="IRC · mozfr/besogne Wiki">IRC</a> : <a href="irc://irc.mozilla.org/mozfr" hreflang="fr" title="Canal de travail de la communauté Mozilla francophone – IRC mozilla.org">#mozfr</a>. N’hésitez pas. Il n’y a pas de question bête et vous y serez bien accueilli·e.</p>

<p><br />
<em>Votre participation peut vraiment faire la différence.</em></p>

<address><br />
<a href="https://twitter.com/hellosct1" hreflang="fr" title="Christophe Villeneuve (@hellosct1) sur Twitter">@hellosct1</a> et <a href="https://twitter.com/Mozinet" hreflang="fr" title="Mozinet (@Mozinet) sur Twitter">@Mozinet</a></address>

<p><em>Précédent événement :</em> <a href="https://blog.mozfr.org/post/2017/10/vie-privee-comme-avantage-competitif-Gry-Hasselbalch-18-octobre-Mozilla-Paris" hreflang="fr" title="La vie privée comme avantage compétitif – Gry Hasselbalch – 18 octobre à Mozilla Paris (3 oct. 2017) Communauté Mozilla francophone">La vie privée comme avantage compétitif – Gry Hasselbalch – 18 octobre à Mozilla Paris</a></p>

<p><em>Crédit photo :</em> <a href="https://www.flickr.com/gp/mozinet/rzN621">Mozinet</a> sous licence <a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/2.0/deed.fr" hreflang="fr" title="Creative Commons — Attribution - pas d’utilisation commerciale - partage dans les mêmes conditions 2.0 générique — CC BY-NC-SA 2.0">CC By-NC-SA 2.0</a>.</p>]]>
  </description>
  <pubDate>Sat, 07 Oct 2017 14:15:22 +0000</pubDate>
  
</item>

<item>
  <title>Christophe Villeneuve - Sprintons pour Firefox Quantum 57 le 4 octobre à Paris</title>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">urn:md5:b340fdf29c86c13b64cc6a49cc6d3fc5</guid>
  <link>https://blog.mozfr.org/post/2017/09/sprintons-pour-firefox-quantum-57-4-octobre-paris</link>
  <description>
    <![CDATA[<p><a href="https://blog.mozfr.org/dotclear/public/firefox/57/succes/RobotPoster2.jpg"><img alt="Poster Robot" src="https://blog.mozfr.org/dotclear/public/firefox/57/succes/.RobotPoster2_s.jpg" style="float: right; margin: 0 0 1em 1em;" /></a> Dans notre précédent article, nous vous proposions de découvrir <a href="https://blog.mozfr.org/post/2017/09/Firefox-57-chacun-peut-contribuer-a-son-succes" hreflang="fr" title="Firefox 57 : chacun peut contribuer à son succès (9 sept. 2017) Zidi branieck “Gandalf” traduit par la communauté Mozilla francophone">Firefox 57 pour que chacun puisse contribuer à son succès</a>. Aujourd’hui, nous vous proposons de passer à une nouvelle étape en participant à la campagne mondiale qui se déroulera du <strong>2 au 8 octobre 2017</strong> pour tester, depuis chez vous, vos sites préférés avec Firefox 57.</p>


<p>Pour garantir son succès, il est nécessaire de tester cette version 57 (nom de code <strong>Quantum</strong>) en regard des versions précédentes du navigateur Firefox. Vu la diversité des sites de par le monde et leurs moyens d’accès, Mozilla ne pourrait pas tester toutes les possibilités. C’est là que <strong>votre participation peut vraiment faire la différence</strong>.</p>    <p>À cette occasion, nous vous proposons de nous retrouver lors d’une soirée dans les locaux de Mozilla à Paris le <strong>mercredi 4 octobre dès 19 h 00</strong>, uniquement équipé de votre ordinateur portable. Après l’installation des différentes versions de Firefox (bêta 57, Nightly 58), nous vous expliquerons la procédure à effectuer pour réaliser ces fameux tests le plus efficacement possible.</p>


<blockquote><p>Le 14 novembre prochain, une version majeure de Firefox sera diffusée auprès du grand public. Surnommée Firefox Quantum, la version 57 de Firefox, outre une interface entièrement rénovée, sera motorisée par un moteur de rendu véloce et très modernisé sur lequel Mozilla travaille depuis plus d’un an. Afin de s’assurer que cette nouvelle version de Firefox et que les changements importants apportés à son moteur ne posent aucun problème pour l’affichage du Web, nous vous proposons de nous retrouver le soir du 4 octobre dans les bureaux parisiens de Mozilla et de nous aider à  tester  la compatibilité de ce Firefox de nouvelle génération avec la majorité du Web francophone. <a href="https://www.meetup.com/fr-FR/Firefox-France-User-Group/events/243368715/" hreflang="fr" title="Découvrir le texte de présentation de Firefox 57 sprint">Lire la suite sur Meetup</a>.</p></blockquote>


<p>L’événement est gratuit, mais sur inscription sur la page <a href="https://www.meetup.com/fr-FR/Firefox-France-User-Group/events/243368715/" hreflang="fr" title="Firefox 57 Sprint - Firefox France User Group (Paris) – Meetup">Meetup <em>Firefox 57 Sprint</em></a>.</p>


<p>Nous vous expliquerons bientôt comment participer de chez vous si vous ne pouvez nous rejoindre à Paris.</p>

<p style="margin: 2em 0 1em 2em; line-height: 1.8em;">
<a href="https://www.mozilla.org/en-US/contact/spaces/paris/" title="Mozilla Spaces Paris"><img alt="Mozilla Spaces Paris" src="https://blog.mozfr.org/dotclear/public/MozillaParis/20170109/.mozillaspaces_paris_s.png" style="float: right; margin: 0 0 1em 1em;" /></a><strong>Mercredi 4 octobre 2017 à 19 h 00</strong><br />
<a href="https://www.mozilla.org/"><strong>Fondation Mozilla</strong></a><br />
<strong>16 bis, boulevard Montmartre</strong>, Paris 9ᵉ (<a href="https://www.openstreetmap.org/node/2883451098#map=18/48.87195/2.34215" hreflang="fr" title="OpenStreetMap">plan libre</a>)<br />
<em>Accès handicapé</em><br /><br />
<a href="https://blog.mozfr.org/dotclear/public/Firefox_OS/station-gare.png"><img alt="" src="https://blog.mozfr.org/dotclear/public/Firefox_OS/station-gare.png" style="float: left; margin: 0 1em 1em 0;" /></a>Métro : préférez <strong>Grands Boulevards</strong><br />
(sortie <strong>Musée Grévin</strong>)<br /><br />
<a href="https://github.com/mozfr/besogne/wiki/Se-rendre-%C3%A0-Mozilla-Paris" hreflang="fr" title="Se rendre à Mozilla Paris · mozfr/besogne Wiki">Se rendre à Mozilla Paris</a> sur le wiki.<br />
</p>

<address><br />
<a href="https://twitter.com/hellosct1" hreflang="fr" title="Christophe Villeneuve (@hellosct1) sur Twitter">@hellosct1</a> 
</address>



<p><em>Crédit illustrations :</em> Mozilla.</p>]]>
  </description>
  <pubDate>Thu, 05 Oct 2017 11:56:12 +0000</pubDate>
  
</item>

<item>
  <title>Official Reps Blog - Rep of the Month – September 2017</title>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.mozilla.org/mozillareps/?p=512</guid>
  <link>https://blog.mozilla.org/mozillareps/2017/10/03/rep-of-the-month-september-2017/</link>
  <description>
    <![CDATA[<div class="cooked">
<p>Please join us in congratulating <a href="https://reps.mozilla.org/u/Kush19/" rel="nofollow noopener">Kushagra Varade</a>, our Rep of the Month for September 2017!</p>
<p>Kushagra is a web developer from Bhopal, India and has joined the Reps program in the first Webinar we ever organized back in April.</p>
<div class="lightbox-wrapper">
<p><a class="lightbox" href="https://discourse-paas-production-content.s3.amazonaws.com/original/3X/4/f/4fd543ae24c339ccf8cbcaf71966948c66826e2c.jpeg" rel="nofollow noopener" title="6019d9717d9ff5bb161d3c477207fba0.jpeg"><img alt="6019d9717d9ff5bb161d3c477207fba0" height="500" src="https://discourse-paas-production-content.s3.amazonaws.com/optimized/3X/4/f/4fd543ae24c339ccf8cbcaf71966948c66826e2c_1_500x500.jpeg" width="500" /></a></p>
<div class="meta"><span class="informations"> </span></div>
</div>
<p>Since joining the Reps program, he has attended several events in his region. Most of these events focused on WebVR such as the <a href="https://reps.mozilla.org/e/geek-night-hyderabad-virtual-reality-for-the-open-web/" rel="nofollow noopener">Geek Night in Hyderabad</a>. He organized a <a href="https://reps.mozilla.org/e/mozactivate-cg/" rel="nofollow noopener">WebVR event</a> in July. Right after joining Reps he attended a <a href="https://reps.mozilla.org/e/moz-coffee-mozilla-mp-bhopal/" rel="nofollow noopener">MozCoffee</a> to discuss onboarding strategies and MozActivate.</p>
<p>Thank you Kushagra, keep rocking the open Web! <img alt=":tada:" class="emoji" src="https://cdn-production.discourse.mozilla-community.org/images/emoji/twitter/tada.png?v=5" title=":tada:" /> <img alt=":tada:" class="emoji" src="https://cdn-production.discourse.mozilla-community.org/images/emoji/twitter/tada.png?v=5" title=":tada:" /></p>
<p><a href="https://discourse.mozilla.org/t/rep-of-the-month-september-2017/19865">Join us on Discourse to congratulate him!</a></p>
</div>]]>
  </description>
  <pubDate>Tue, 03 Oct 2017 09:14:11 +0000</pubDate>
  
</item>

<item>
  <title>Viswaprasath KS - Weeks of Contribution- WebExtension Session7</title>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://iamVP7.in//MozWOC-Session7/</guid>
  <link>http://iamVP7.in//MozWOC-Session7/</link>
  <description>
    <![CDATA[<p><strong>Date</strong> : 29th August 2017</p>]]>
  </description>
  <pubDate>Mon, 02 Oct 2017 00:54:00 +0000</pubDate>
  
</item>

<item>
  <title>Viswaprasath KS - Weeks of Contribution- WebExtension Session6</title>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://iamVP7.in//MozWOC-Session6/</guid>
  <link>http://iamVP7.in//MozWOC-Session6/</link>
  <description>
    <![CDATA[<p><strong>Date</strong> : 22nd August 2017</p>]]>
  </description>
  <pubDate>Mon, 02 Oct 2017 00:34:00 +0000</pubDate>
  
</item>

<item>
  <title>Viswaprasath KS - Weeks of Contribution- WebExtension Session5</title>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://iamVP7.in//MozWOC-Session5/</guid>
  <link>http://iamVP7.in//MozWOC-Session5/</link>
  <description>
    <![CDATA[<p><strong>Date</strong> : 4th August 2017</p>]]>
  </description>
  <pubDate>Mon, 02 Oct 2017 00:04:00 +0000</pubDate>
  
</item>

<item>
  <title>Viswaprasath KS - Weeks of Contribution- WebExtension Session4</title>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://iamVP7.in//MozWOC-Session4/</guid>
  <link>http://iamVP7.in//MozWOC-Session4/</link>
  <description>
    <![CDATA[<p><strong>Date</strong> : 2nd August 2017</p>]]>
  </description>
  <pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2017 23:34:00 +0000</pubDate>
  
</item>

<item>
  <title>Viswaprasath KS - MozillaTN SFDHack WebExtension Workshop</title>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://iamVP7.in//SFDHack-MozActivate-WebExt-workshop/</guid>
  <link>http://iamVP7.in//SFDHack-MozActivate-WebExt-workshop/</link>
  <description>
    <![CDATA[<p>We wanted to make a strong community in Chennai. We got this wonderful place KCG E-cell. Lot of planning went around this event, and we planned event month before.</p>]]>
  </description>
  <pubDate>Fri, 29 Sep 2017 01:34:00 +0000</pubDate>
  
</item>

<item>
  <title>Christophe Villeneuve - Alternatiba, le week-end prochain à Paris</title>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">urn:md5:914b7f056972fed4a95dfe48ebf1bf0b</guid>
  <link>https://blog.mozfr.org/post/2017/09/alternatiba-le-week-end-prochain-a-paris</link>
  <description>
    <![CDATA[<p><a href="https://blog.mozfr.org/dotclear/public/Firefox_OS/mamie_fox/rencontre-sept15-photo4.jpg"><img alt="Public UbuCon Europe" src="https://blog.mozfr.org/dotclear/public/Firefox_OS/mamie_fox/.rencontre-sept15-photo4_s.jpg" style="float: right; margin: 0 0 1em 1em;" /></a>
Après deux années de patience, <a href="https://alternatiba.eu/paris/" hreflang="fr" title="Alernatiba  2017">Alternatiba Paris</a> fait son grand retour avec comme mot d’ordre <strong>Ensemble, nous sommes une force immense !</strong> Il s’agit de l’important événement citoyen où les solutions alternatives sont abordées.</p>


<p>Nous étions présents en 2015 à la <a href="https://firefoxos.mozfr.org/post/2015/10/Mamie-Fox-%3A-mes-belles-rencontres-de-septembre">dernière édition</a> et nous serons aussi là cette année les <strong>30 septembre et 1<sup>er</sup> octobre</strong> prochains, <strong>place Stalingrad</strong>, quai de Seine.</p>    <p><img alt="bandeau Alternatiba 2017" src="https://blog.mozfr.org/dotclear/public/mozfr/evenements/alternatiba/.CP_bandeau_m.jpg" style="display: table; margin: 0 auto;" /></p>


<p>Cette édition 2017 reste au cœur du grand défi climatique et des défis des alternatives.</p>


<p><a href="https://blog.mozfr.org/dotclear/public/mozfr/evenements/alternatiba/Plan_Village_Alternatiba.jpg"><img alt="Public UbuCon Europe" src="https://blog.mozfr.org/dotclear/public/mozfr/evenements/alternatiba/.Plan_Village_Alternatiba_m.jpg" style="display: table; margin: 0 auto;" /></a></p>


<p>À cette occasion vous pourrez retrouver : une scène ouverte, place Stalingrad, des conférences et débats, des projections de films, un espace numérique et de nombreux espaces alternatifs appelés quartiers.</p>


<p>Ce sera l’occasion de (re)découvrir les solutions pour mieux se déplacer, manger, se chauffer, etc. avec les thèmes suivants :</p>
<ul>
<li>vivre ensemble</li>
<li>consommer responsable</li>
<li>s’informer</li>
<li>se divertir</li>
<li>se déplacer</li>
<li>se loger…</li>
</ul>


<p>… à découvrir dans le <a href="https://blog.mozfr.org/post/2017/09/alternatiba.eu/paris/2017-actions/le-village-2017/demandez-le-programme/" hreflang="fr" title="Alternatiba 2017 :  programme des villages">programme complet</a>.</p>


<p><img alt="Foule Alternatiba 2017" src="https://blog.mozfr.org/dotclear/public/mozfr/evenements/alternatiba/.foule_s.jpg" style="display: table; margin: 0 auto;" /></p>


<p>De notre côté, vous pourrez nous retrouver au sein du <strong>village du numérique</strong>, pour parler de solutions libres comme le navigateur Firefox ou de messagerie comme Thunderbird. Nous serons aux côtés des autres associations du Libre : April, Parinux, Framasoft, Ubuntu, etc.</p>


<p>Du côté des conférences, nous serons présents à une table ronde le 1<sup>er</sup> octobre pour parler de  <strong><a href="http://alternatiba.eu/paris/2017-actions/le-village-2017/demandez-le-programme/" hreflang="fr" title="Obsolescence programmée">l’obsolescence programmée, des alternatives numériques</a></strong> (Les Canaux) de 10 h 00 à 12 h 00 aux côtés de l’April, Parinux et M2.</p>


<h3>Informations utiles</h3>


<p><strong>Village numérique</strong></p>


<p>Quartier « S’informer et se divertir »<br />
à hauteur de la péniche Antipode<br />
face au 55 quai de la Seine, Paris 19ᵉ [<a href="https://www.openstreetmap.org/#map=19/48.88672/2.37496" hreflang="fr" title="Plan OpenStreetMap Alternatiba 2017">plan libre</a>]</p>


<p>Métro : Riquet – sortie rue de Flandre (ligne 7) ou Jaurès (lignes 2, 5 et 7)</p>


<p>Horaires d’ouverture :</p>
<ul>
<li>samedi de 13 h à 18 h</li>
<li>dimanche de 10 h à 18 h</li>
</ul>


<p><br />
<em>Alors, nous comptons sur vous pour venir à cet événement et par la même occasion nous faire un petit coucou.</em></p>

<address><br />
<a href="https://twitter.com/hellosct1" hreflang="fr" title="Christophe Villeneuve (@hellosct1) sur Twitter">@hellosct1</a>
</address>




<p><em>Crédit photos :</em></p>


<p><a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/26276571@N03/21431498103/in/album-72157659236601248/" hreflang="fr" title="Christophe Villeneuve sur Flickr">Alternativa 2015, Christophe Villeneuve</a>. Tous droits réservés.</p>


<p><a href="http://alternatives.blog.lemonde.fr/2014/10/10/alternatiba-le-mouvement-citoyen-qui-fait-le-plein-a-tout-va/fr">LeMonde</a>. Tous droits réservés.</p>


<p><em>Notre précédent événement :</em>  <a href="https://blog.mozfr.org/post/2017/09/mozilla-a-la-ubucon-paris-de-cette-semaine" hreflang="fr" title="Mozilla à la UbuCon Paris de cette semaine">Mozilla à la UbuCon Paris de cette semaine</a></p>]]>
  </description>
  <pubDate>Thu, 28 Sep 2017 13:10:12 +0000</pubDate>
  
</item>

<item>
  <title>Mehul Patel - Dive Into Rust at ORDINATEUR’17</title>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.rowdymehul.com/?p=1416</guid>
  <link>http://www.rowdymehul.com/dive-into-rust-at-ordinateur17/</link>
  <description>
    <![CDATA[<p><span class="author-a-n8m2z75zz85z1z88zz69zi0fz76zz87z1c">The event is focused on introducing and teaching the state of art system programming language <a href="https://www.rust-lang.org/en-US/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Rust</a> to local programmers and Mozillians in Gujarat.  This is the first time <strong>Mozilla</strong> will participate at <strong>ORDINATEUR’17</strong>! The summit will involve students and tech enthusiasts from the university. I gave a talk on <a href="https://www.rust-lang.org/en-US/">Rust programming</a> which is one of emerging technologies and one of the major focus of Mozilla.<br />
</span></p>
<p><strong>About ORDINATEUR’17 :</strong></p>
<p>ORDINATEUR’17 is a one of a kind flagship event organized by IEEE GCET Computer Society Student Chapter under the them “<strong><em>Tech Trend &amp; Innovate</em></strong>”</p>
<p><a href="https://i1.wp.com/www.rowdymehul.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/poster.jpg"><img alt="" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1420" src="https://i1.wp.com/www.rowdymehul.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/poster.jpg?resize=720%2C267" /></a>Before, I shared my experience with this talk, so let me tell you one thing that this was my one of the best intellectual programming debate talk. Yes, it is! <img alt="😀" class="wp-smiley" src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/2.3/72x72/1f600.png" style="height: 1em;" /><span id="more-1416"></span></p>
<p>I have started with Introduction to Mozilla and “Who am I”. Adding to that, I have also shared about Mozilla projects and <a href="https://www.rust-lang.org/en-US/">Rust </a>is one of them. So now, Lets Dive Into Rust!</p>
<p><a href="https://i0.wp.com/www.rowdymehul.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/IMG_8975.jpg"><img alt="" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1421" src="https://i0.wp.com/www.rowdymehul.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/IMG_8975.jpg?resize=720%2C480" /></a><br />
According to me, <em>Rust is a good choice when you’d choose C++. You can also say, “Rust is a systems programming language that pursuing the trifecta: safe, concurrent, and fast.” I would say, Rust is an ownership-oriented programming language.</em></p>
<p><em><strong>Why should I use Rust? </strong></em>I am always expecting this question whenever I talk about Rust and here as well one language enthusiast asked me the same questions.</p>
<p><strong>Firstly, I have shared the reason that I’ve looked into Rust at first and then I have explained and discussed each point with participants.  </strong></p>
<p><a href="https://i0.wp.com/www.rowdymehul.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/photo_2017-09-24_04-10-17.jpg"><img alt="" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1419" src="https://i0.wp.com/www.rowdymehul.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/photo_2017-09-24_04-10-17.jpg?resize=720%2C720" /></a></p>
<ul>
<li>Rust is new enough that you can write useful stuff that would have already existed in other languages</li>
<li>It is low-level enough that you take account of most resources.</li>
<li>It’s more like C++ and Go, less like Node and Ruby</li>
<li>cargo is awesome. Managing crates just works as intended, which makes a whole lot of troubles you may have in other languages just vanish with a satisfying <em>poof</em>.</li>
</ul>
<p>Please read the full story <a href="http://www.rowdymehul.com/why-should-i-use-rust/" rel="noopener">here</a>, this may explain you, <em><strong>why you should use </strong></em>Rust?</p>
<p>Then, we move ahead did some practicals where I have shown them small demos from our <a href="https://github.com/MozillaIndia/RustIndia/tree/master/short_demo" rel="noopener">Rust Kits</a></p>
<p><a href="https://i2.wp.com/www.rowdymehul.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/IMG_8938.jpg"><img alt="" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1422" src="https://i2.wp.com/www.rowdymehul.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/IMG_8938.jpg?resize=720%2C480" /></a>It was always fun to play with Rust and glad that participants also enjoyed while rusty their hand.</p>
<div class="wp-caption aligncenter" id="attachment_1423" style="width: 5194px;"><a href="https://i0.wp.com/www.rowdymehul.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/IMG_8978.jpg"><img alt="" class="wp-image-1423 size-full" src="https://i0.wp.com/www.rowdymehul.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/IMG_8978.jpg?resize=720%2C480" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text"><strong>                                             Thanks, ORDINATEUR’17 Team for this memento.</strong></p></div>
<p><strong>Reps </strong>link: <a href="https://reps.mozilla.org/e/mozconnect-with-ordinateur-17/" rel="noopener">https://reps.mozilla.org/e/mozconnect-with-ordinateur-17/</a></p>
<p><strong>Presentation </strong>link: <a href="https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1SatJ6G_Um9cRbV7PjqRrjwf68Ku7kSYG9vGJI_Zy40M/edit?usp=sharing" rel="noopener">https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1SatJ6G_Um9cRbV7PjqRrjwf68Ku7kSYG9vGJI_Zy40M/edit?usp=sharing</a></p>
<p><strong>Google Drive (Photos) </strong>link: <a href="https://drive.google.com/drive/folders/0B9Vs6T2Sp2LAWV9KLWhPYktPOVU" rel="noopener">https://drive.google.com/drive/folders/0B9Vs6T2Sp2LAWV9KLWhPYktPOVU </a></p>
<h1>What Next?</h1>
<ul>
<li>I am looking for more such collaboration with such organizations to spread the Mozilla mission &amp; Rust.</li>
<li>Next series of full-day intense workshop on Rust at G H Patel College of Engineering &amp; Technology with IEEE GCET Computer Society and nearby university campuses.</li>
</ul>
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong><em>Hope you enjoyed my blog! <img alt="🙂" class="wp-smiley" src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/2.3/72x72/1f642.png" style="height: 1em;" /></em></strong></p>]]>
  </description>
  <pubDate>Sat, 23 Sep 2017 23:37:52 +0000</pubDate>
  
</item>

<item>
  <title>Mehul Patel - Why Open Source ?</title>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.rowdymehul.com/?p=1406</guid>
  <link>http://www.rowdymehul.com/why-open-source/</link>
  <description>
    <![CDATA[<p>Firstly, let me extend the thanks to <a href="http://elab.yuvalay.org/" rel="noopener">Yuvalay Electronics Lab</a> for inviting me as Speaker to give a talk on Open Source. Moreover, kudos to you to arrange a talk on Open source first time ever in <span class="_Xbe">Vadodara</span> city.</p>
<p><strong>About Yuvalay Electronics Lab</strong></p>
<p>Yuvalay Electronics Lab offers a platform and eco-system to the students, hobbyists, and professionals to understand and apply the theoretical knowledge of the subjects in the field of Electronics. It helps to convert the interest into the passion by providing a conducive environment to learn-explore-innovate under the guidance of experts. <a href="http://elab.yuvalay.org/" rel="noopener">More</a></p>
<p>This is the first time ever I have not presented any presentation, this time it’s gonna be a pure talk where people can ask me anything about open source. I have started my talk with, what I am thinking or believing about open source.</p>
<p><a href="https://i2.wp.com/www.rowdymehul.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/photo_2017-09-24_03-31-39.jpg"><img alt="" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1408" src="https://i2.wp.com/www.rowdymehul.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/photo_2017-09-24_03-31-39.jpg?resize=720%2C720" /></a>For me, <em>contributing to open source can be a rewarding way to learn, teach, and gain experience. No matter which skills you have, everything can be made useful. In this talk, I have shared the following points which can help you to get started with </em>an<em> open source contribution.</em><span id="more-1406"></span></p>
<ol>
<li><em>Why contribute to open source?</em></li>
<li><em>What it means to contribute</em></li>
<li><em>Boost yourself to a new project; best example: Github</em></li>
<li><em>How to find a project to contribute to? : some sources Github, Your First PR, and so on.</em></li>
<li><em>How to submit a contribution?</em></li>
<li><em>What happens once you contributed?</em></li>
</ol>
<p>I am always asking these questions to my self and trying to find out the answer, and guess what while finding the answer to these questions my contribution to open source automatically done.</p>
<p>A common misconception about contributing to open source is that you need to contribute code. For me, contributions don’t have to be tech related as open source projects also need people who have non-tech skills, like documentation, localization, marketing, testing and much more.</p>
<p>For instance, <b><i>What can I do for Mozilla?</i></b> is a resource that helps pair people with the organization’s technical and non-technical needs.</p>
<p><b><i>Why do people contribute to open source? </i></b></p>
<p>To, improve existing skills<br />
To, meet people who are having similar interests<br />
To, find mentors and teach others<br />
To, build public artifacts that help to build your profile</p>
<p>Here are  few of my personal favorites Open Source Platforms;</p>
<ul>
<li>Linux &lt;3</li>
<li>WordPress</li>
<li>Python &amp; Rust</li>
<li>VLC Media Player &lt;3</li>
<li>Web Browsers:
<ul>
<li>Firefox &lt;3</li>
<li>Chromium (the basis for Chrome)</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>GIMP</li>
</ul>
<p><i>I bet on you, within these kinds of projects exist more undetected bugs, probable improvements, and documentation deficiency. Therefore, even if you don’t want to learn how to code inside, still you can find ways to take part in the open source world.</i></p>
<p>There was a very healthy discussion between me and all the participants where they asking back to back questions and I am thus thoroughly enjoying to answer those questions.</p>
<p><a href="https://i2.wp.com/www.rowdymehul.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/photo_2017-09-24_03-28-47.jpg"><img alt="" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1409" src="https://i2.wp.com/www.rowdymehul.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/photo_2017-09-24_03-28-47.jpg?resize=720%2C720" /></a>Our goal via this talk is to make people understand that open source contribution have no explicit literal like hard-earned cash value. But, the implicit value, i.e. the opportunity to contribute to open source widely outweighs any literal cash value you might gain by giving your time over to a project. e.g. Guess how much money I got paid for contributing to Linux package? $0. Yep, it was $0.</p>
<p>Our aim is to people believe that if they don’t file bugs and make steps to reproduce them, or on ways to reproduce expected and unexpected behaviors, so coders/techs have no way of knowing how software gets used and what they should do get resolved.</p>
<p>At last, we also had round discussion of what participants thinking about open source and what their passion about open source.Everyone has shared their views and all an all it was great to hear their views on it.</p>
<p><a href="https://i0.wp.com/www.rowdymehul.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/photo_2017-09-24_03-42-46.jpg"><img alt="" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1411" src="https://i0.wp.com/www.rowdymehul.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/photo_2017-09-24_03-42-46.jpg?resize=720%2C720" /></a>Even if you like to write code, other types of contributions are a great way to get involved with a project and meet other community members. Building those relationships will give you opportunities to work on other parts of the project. This is the way community builds with better engagement.</p>
<p><a href="https://i0.wp.com/www.rowdymehul.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/IMG-9744.jpg"><img alt="" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1410" src="https://i0.wp.com/www.rowdymehul.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/IMG-9744.jpg?resize=720%2C540" /></a><br />
Thank you, everyone, who joined our talk! <img alt="🙂" class="wp-smiley" src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/2.3/72x72/1f642.png" style="height: 1em;" /> Hope you enjoyed reading my blog.  <img alt="🙂" class="wp-smiley" src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/2.3/72x72/1f642.png" style="height: 1em;" /></p>]]>
  </description>
  <pubDate>Sat, 23 Sep 2017 22:25:32 +0000</pubDate>
  
</item>

<item>
  <title>Viswaprasath KS - MozillaTN SNSCT WebExtension Workshop</title>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://iamVP7.in//SNSCT-MozActivate-WebExt-workshop/</guid>
  <link>http://iamVP7.in//SNSCT-MozActivate-WebExt-workshop/</link>
  <description>
    <![CDATA[<p>Coimbatore is one of the amazing city in Tamilnadu, and its so special for MozillaTN community as we have more amazing student contributors. SNSCT college at Coimbatore is so special and is best known for QA activities.</p>]]>
  </description>
  <pubDate>Tue, 19 Sep 2017 01:34:00 +0000</pubDate>
  
</item>

<item>
  <title>Geraldo Barros - Internet Health @Software Freedom Day 2017 São Carlos</title>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">https://geraldobarros.me/?p=894</guid>
  <link>https://geraldobarros.me/internet-health-software-freedom-day-2017-sao-carlos/</link>
  <description>
    <![CDATA[<p>Yesterday I was in one of the editions of <a href="https://sancalug.github.io/sfd-2017-site/">Software Freedom Day 2017 in the city of São Carlos</a> to talk about the Internet Health. <em>Here we have a little draft of what we talked!</em><span id="more-894"></span></p>
<p>The Software Freedom Day (SFD) is an annual worldwide celebration of Free Software. #SFD is a public education effort with the aim of increasing awareness of Free Software and its virtues, and encouraging its use. At São Carlos city (Brazil) edition, I pushed a conversation about #<a href="https://internethealthreport.org/v01/">InternetHealthy</a>! By engaging a community of key thinkers on defining Internet health, we want to generate better understanding of what the world can do to make the Internet healthier.</p>
<p><strong>Conversation</strong></p>
<p>Our conversation is guided directly on concept of the Internet Health, the importance of measuring the health of the Internet, then we talk about the history of the <a href="https://internethealthreport.org/v01/">Internet Health report created by Mozilla</a> and the importance of the initiative, we show some of the relevant data in the report about the 5 key topics of Internet health, we take the topics and data to be discussed in depth, and ultimately we guide people to <a href="https://internethealthreport.org/feedback/">give feedback about the report directly on the official website</a>.</p>
<p><a href="https://mega.nz/#!054jnKoZ!1ITun5_rT0QUctVOXNyvrO7xdz-jqNHqdWOoQXNCEm4">Download slide decks</a></p>
<p><strong>Let’s take a note of what we discussed</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>The <strong>concept</strong> of the Internet Health is generally not known, but it is related to the way governments are attacking the Internet through censorship and network control policies.</li>
<li><strong>Decentralization</strong> is one of the most discussed topics, on what way can break the monopoly of big companies like Google and Microsoft.</li>
<li><strong>Web Literacy</strong> is the key to solve most of the issues reported in the report, in particular issues of decentralization and privacy and security.</li>
<li><strong>Digital Inclusion</strong> is important, but it is important to reach the other half of the world along with web literacy.</li>
</ul>
<p> </p>
<blockquote class="instagram-media">
<div style="padding: 8px;">
<div style="line-height: 0; margin-top: 40px; padding: 50.0% 0; text-align: center; width: 100%;"></div>
<p style="margin: 8px 0 0 0; padding: 0 4px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/BZHUiiBA_-A/" rel="noopener" style="color: #000; font-family: Arial,sans-serif; font-size: 14px; font-style: normal; font-weight: normal; line-height: 17px; text-decoration: none;" target="_blank">Software Freedom Day (SFD) is an annual worldwide celebration of Free Software. #SFD is a public education effort with the aim of increasing awareness of Free Software and its virtues, and encouraging its use. At São Carlos city (Brazil) edition, Geraldo Barros (@geraldo_barros) our community member is pushing a conversation about #InternetHealthy! By engaging a community of key thinkers on defining Internet health, we want to generate better understanding of what the world can do to make the Internet healthier. See more: https://internethealthreport.org Software Freedom Day 2017 São Carlos: https://sancalug.github.io/sfd-2017-site #CC0</a></p>
<p style="color: #c9c8cd; font-family: Arial,sans-serif; font-size: 14px; line-height: 17px; margin-bottom: 0; margin-top: 8px; overflow: hidden; padding: 8px 0 7px; text-align: center; white-space: nowrap;">A post shared by Mozilla (@mozillagram) on <time datetime="2017-09-16T19:55:16+00:00" style="font-family: Arial,sans-serif; font-size: 14px; line-height: 17px;">Sep 16, 2017 at 12:55pm PDT</time></p>
</div>
</blockquote>
<p></p>
<p><strong>Thank you all SFD for the opportunity to us talk about Internet Health so important to FOSS software!</strong></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://geraldobarros.me/internet-health-software-freedom-day-2017-sao-carlos/" rel="nofollow">Internet Health @Software Freedom Day 2017 São Carlos</a> appeared first on <a href="https://geraldobarros.me" rel="nofollow">Geraldo Barros</a>.</p>]]>
  </description>
  <pubDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2017 18:36:40 +0000</pubDate>
  
</item>

<item>
  <title>Christophe Villeneuve - Mozilla vous attend aux Journées du patrimoine les 16 et 17 septembre</title>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">urn:md5:2f0a34fce4406a436c58ba6dd4a681a0</guid>
  <link>https://blog.mozfr.org/post/2017/09/Mozilla-vous-attend-journees-europeennes-du-patrimoine-2017-16-17-septembre</link>
  <description>
    <![CDATA[<p><a href="https://blog.mozfr.org/dotclear/public/mozfr/.jep-5_s.jpg"><img alt="Bureau Mozilla Pa" src="https://blog.mozfr.org/dotclear/public/mozfr/.jep-5_s.jpg" style="float: right; margin: 0 0 1em 1em;" /></a>  Les <a href="https://fr.wikipedia.org/wiki/Journ%C3%A9es_europ%C3%A9ennes_du_patrimoine" hreflang="fr" title="Journées européennes du patrimoine – Wikipédia">Journées européennes du patrimoine</a> 2017 se dérouleront le 16 et 17 septembre. Le thème de cette année en France est : <q>Jeunesse et Patrimoine</q>, avec de nombreux lieux ouverts gratuitement ou à tarifs réduits.</p>    <br /><br />



<p><em>Les bureaux de Mozilla Paris (18 s) sur <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=X9t3Y4MVzpI" hreflang="fr" title="Les bureaux de Mozilla Paris sur la chaîne YouTube de Mozilla fr">YouTube</a></em></p>


<p>Depuis 2013, les bureaux parisiens de Mozilla sont installés dans un monument historique classé qui ouvrira ses portes les 2 jours pour vous recevoir pendant ces <a href="http://journeesdupatrimoine.culturecommunication.gouv.fr/" hreflang="fr" title="Les Journées européennes du Patrimoine 2017">Journées du patrimoine 2017</a>.</p>


<p><img alt="Hotel de Mercy-Argenteau" src="https://blog.mozfr.org/dotclear/public/mozfr/.jep-1_s.jpg" style="float: left; margin: 0 1em 1em 0;" /></p>


<p>Mozilla Paris est installé dans le <strong>9ᵉ arrondissement</strong> de la capitale au cœur de <a href="https://fr.wikipedia.org/wiki/H%C3%B4tel_de_Mercy-Argenteau" hreflang="fr" title="Hôtel de Mercy Argenteau – Wikipédia">l’hôtel de Mercy-Argenteau</a>, au <strong>16 bis, boulevard Montmartre</strong>. Bâti en 1778 par l’architecte <a href="https://fr.wikipedia.org/wiki/Firmin_Perlin" hreflang="fr" title="Firmin Perlin – Wikipédia">Firmin Perlin</a> dans un style Louis XVI, cet hôtel devint rapidement la propriété du comte de Mercy-Argenteau, ambassadeur d’Autriche à Paris de 1783 à 1790 et qui avait été précepteur de la future reine Marie-Antoinette.</p>


<p><img alt="La cuisine de Mozilla Paris" src="https://blog.mozfr.org/dotclear/public/mozfr/.jep-11_m.jpg" style="display: table; margin: 0 auto;" /></p>


<p>Des bénévoles de la fondation qui développe le célèbre navigateur web <a href="https://www.mozilla.org/fr/firefox/" hreflang="fr" title="Téléchargez Firefox – Navigateur web gratuit – Mozilla">Firefox</a> seront là tout le week-end pour vous faire découvrir les enjeux du Web d’aujourd’hui : vie privée, logiciel libres, standardisation… il sera aussi possible de découvrir et tester les futures évolutions de Firefox dont la nouvelle interface qui arrivera deux mois après.</p>


<p><strong>Fondation Mozilla</strong><br />
<strong>16 bis, boulevard Montmartre</strong> – 9ᵉ arrondissement de Paris<br />
Ouverture : samedi de 10 h à 18 h <br />
et dimanche de 10 h à 17 h <br />
Gratuit<br />
Accès handicapé</p>


<p><a href="https://github.com/mozfr/besogne/wiki/Se-rendre-%C3%A0-Mozilla-Paris" hreflang="fr" title="Se rendre à Mozilla Paris · mozfr/besogne Wiki">Se rendre à Mozilla Paris</a></p>


<p>Restez branché sur nos réseaux sociaux (<a href="https://www.facebook.com/Mozilla-francophone-663278170492219/" hreflang="fr" title="Mozilla francophone sur Facebook">Facebook</a>, <a href="https://twitter.com/mozilla_fr" hreflang="fr" title="Mozilla FR (@mozilla_fr) sur Twitter">Twitter</a> et <a href="https://mamot.fr/@mozilla" hreflang="fr" title="Mozilla francophone – instance de La Quadrature du Net – Mastodon - Media fédéré">Mastodon</a>) pour les dernières nouvelles.</p>


<p><strong>Liens utiles : </strong><br /></p>
<ul>
<li>Site officiel des <a href="http://journeesdupatrimoine.culturecommunication.gouv.fr/" hreflang="fr" title="Journées européennes du Patrimoine 2017">Journées européennes du Patrimoine 2017</a></li>
<li><a href="https://journeesdupatrimoine.culturecommunication.gouv.fr/Programme" hreflang="fr" title="Programme des Journées européennes du patrimoine 2017">Programme 2017</a></li>
<li><a href="https://journeesdupatrimoine.culturecommunication.gouv.fr/Programme#/pinpoints/16824587" hreflang="fr" title="Programme – Journées européennes du patrimoine 2017">L’hôtel de Mercy-Argenteau sur la carte officielle des Journées du Patrimoine</a></li>
</ul>


<p><img alt="Bannière JEP2017" src="https://blog.mozfr.org/dotclear/public/mozfr/evenements/jep/.jep2017-banniere_m.jpg" style="display: table; margin: 0 auto;" title="Bannière JEP2017, sept. 2017" /></p>

<p>Pour préparer votre visite :</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.neufhistoire.fr/articles.php?lng=fr&amp;pg=68&amp;tconfig=0" hreflang="fr" title="www.neufhistoire.fr Le site de la Société 9ème Histoire - Hôtel de Mercy-Argenteau">Hôtel de Mercy-Argenteau par 9<sup>e</sup> Histoire</a></li>
<li><a href="http://o.nouvelobs.com/high-tech/20130606.OBS2231/visite-guidee-des-nouveaux-locaux-de-mozilla-a-paris.html" hreflang="fr" title="Visite guidée des nouveaux locaux de Mozilla à Paris - 7 juin 2013 - Nouvel Obs">Visite guidée des nouveaux locaux de Mozilla à Paris</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.batiactu.com/edito/-33187.php" hreflang="fr" title="L'hôtel de Mercy-Argenteau s'offre une nouvelle vie (diaporama)">L’hôtel de Mercy-Argenteau s’offre une nouvelle vie</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.hotels-paris-rive-gauche.com/blog/2013/09/26/nous-visitons-la-fondation-mozilla-a-paris/" hreflang="fr" title="Nous visitons la Fondation Mozilla à Paris - Hotels Paris Rive Gauche Blog">Nous visitons la Fondation Mozilla à Paris</a>
</li></ul>


<address><br />
<a href="https://twitter.com/hellosct1" hreflang="fr" title="Christophe Villeneuve (@hellosct1) sur Twitter">@hellosct1</a> et <a href="https://twitter.com/Mozinet" hreflang="fr" title="Mozinet (@Mozinet) sur Twitter">@Mozinet</a>
</address>



<p><em>Notre précédent événement :</em> <a href="https://blog.mozfr.org/post/2017/08/rmll-2017-notre-presence" hreflang="fr" title="RMLL 2017, notre présence">RMLL 2017, notre présence</a></p>]]>
  </description>
  <pubDate>Fri, 15 Sep 2017 19:27:35 +0000</pubDate>
  
</item>

<item>
  <title>Ajay Kumar Jogawath - Mozilla Campus Club Inauguration @ BITS,Warangal</title>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://ajaykumarjogawath.wordpress.com/?p=499</guid>
  <link>https://ajaykumarjogawath.wordpress.com/2017/09/11/mozilla-campus-club-inauguration-bitswarangal/</link>
  <description>
    <![CDATA[<p>Hello everyone,</p>
<p>It has been a long time, I have been writing here. This blog post will be about sharing my personal experience during the Mozilla Campus Club Inauguration at Balaji Institute of Technology and Science, Warangal, Telangana, India.</p>
<p>I have started contributing to Mozilla way back in 2012 and I am really elated that I have come a long way. All it started when a student from BITS contacted me on Facebook asking about the activities and opportunities that a student can be benefited. I told him about the Mozilla Campus Club Program to him and he got excited about it.</p>
<p>In the next few days, I explained him about Mozilla, its mission, vision, Campus Club Program, activities and how he can be a part of a global community. And then things went fast, we decided to inaugurate a Mozilla Campus Club in their college.</p>
<p>So, it was decided that we will be inaugurating a Mozilla Club on September 1st, 2017.</p>
<p>[1] Club Launch of Mozilla Campus Club BITS</p>
<div class="embed-twitter">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="ro">Mozilla Campus Club Inauguration at Balaji Institute of Technological Sciences,India. <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/mozilla?src=hash">#mozilla</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/mozillareps">@mozillareps</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/mozstudents">@mozstudents</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/MozillaIN">@MozillaIN</a> &lt;1/4&gt; <a href="https://t.co/WCrBp4jMYB">pic.twitter.com/WCrBp4jMYB</a></p>
<p>— Ajay Kumar Jogawath (@akjogawath) <a href="https://twitter.com/akjogawath/status/906838903184924673">September 10, 2017</a></p></blockquote>
<p></p></div>
<p>[2] Addressed the audience on Mozilla, Communities and Opportunities</p>
<div class="embed-twitter">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Addressing the audience about <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/MozillaCommunities?src=hash">#MozillaCommunities</a> &amp; <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/MozillaCampusClubs?src=hash">#MozillaCampusClubs</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/mozstudents">@mozstudents</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/mozillareps">@mozillareps</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/sandeep81910240">@sandeep81910240</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/balapandu222">@balapandu222</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/Sree365">@Sree365</a> <a href="https://t.co/gWXuir0Oa4">pic.twitter.com/gWXuir0Oa4</a></p>
<p>— Ajay Kumar Jogawath (@akjogawath) <a href="https://twitter.com/akjogawath/status/906839855463895040">September 10, 2017</a></p></blockquote>
<p></p></div>
<p> </p>
<p>[3] The amazing crowd at Balaji Institute of Technology and Science.</p>
<div class="embed-twitter">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Amazing Crowd at BITS Warangal <a href="https://twitter.com/sandeep81910240">@sandeep81910240</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/balapandu222">@balapandu222</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/Sree365">@Sree365</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/mozillareps">@mozillareps</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/mozlove?src=hash">#mozlove</a> (3/4) <a href="https://t.co/uq5rfas2ob">pic.twitter.com/uq5rfas2ob</a></p>
<p>— Ajay Kumar Jogawath (@akjogawath) <a href="https://twitter.com/akjogawath/status/906840421111918592">September 10, 2017</a></p></blockquote>
<p></p></div>
<p>[4] Press Coverage of the event.</p>
<div class="embed-twitter">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Media Coverage of the Mozilla Event organized in BITS, Warangal <a href="https://twitter.com/mozstudents">@mozstudents</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/mozillareps">@mozillareps</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/sandeep81910240">@sandeep81910240</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/balapandu222">@balapandu222</a> (4/4) <a href="https://t.co/LWROKLrFRy">pic.twitter.com/LWROKLrFRy</a></p>
<p>— Ajay Kumar Jogawath (@akjogawath) <a href="https://twitter.com/akjogawath/status/906842208715919360">September 10, 2017</a></p></blockquote>
<p></p></div>
<div class="embed-twitter">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">The Compulsory Group photo after the event. <a href="https://twitter.com/mozilla">@mozilla</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/MozillaIN">@MozillaIN</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/mozillareps">@mozillareps</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/FirefoxNightly">@FirefoxNightly</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/rustlang">@rustlang</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/sandeep81910240">@sandeep81910240</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/balapandu222">@balapandu222</a> <a href="https://t.co/SBeYqKoEly">pic.twitter.com/SBeYqKoEly</a></p>
<p>— Ajay Kumar Jogawath (@akjogawath) <a href="https://twitter.com/akjogawath/status/907121747270541313">September 11, 2017</a></p></blockquote>
<p></p></div>
<p>Overall, it was an amazing experience talking to students. I have talked on Mozilla, products, Mozilla Campus Club Program, Activate Mozilla Campaign, Rust, WebVR and Firefox Nightly Campaign. Looking forward to organizing more events in future.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>Best Regards,</p>
<p>Ajay Kumar Jogawath</p>
<p>Mozilla Representative</p>
<p> </p><br />  <a href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/ajaykumarjogawath.wordpress.com/499/" rel="nofollow"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/ajaykumarjogawath.wordpress.com/499/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" height="1" src="https://pixel.wp.com/b.gif?host=ajaykumarjogawath.wordpress.com&amp;blog=43809535&amp;post=499&amp;subd=ajaykumarjogawath&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" />]]>
  </description>
  <pubDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2017 06:07:02 +0000</pubDate>
  
</item>

<item>
  <title>Michal Stanke - Mozilla Latest Version - my first project dedicated to Mozilla</title>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://michal.stanke.cz/2017/09/07/mozilla-latest-version-my-first-project-dedicated-to-mozilla</guid>
  <link>http://michal.stanke.cz/2017/09/07/mozilla-latest-version-my-first-project-dedicated-to-mozilla.html</link>
  <description>
    <![CDATA[<p><a href="https://github.com/MozillaCZ/mozilla-latest-version">Mozilla Latest Version</a> (shortly <em>Mozlv</em>) was my first project I have written entirely because of Mozilla. It’s a WordPress plugin to get the latest version number of Firefox/Thunderbird/SeaMonkey and the corresponding links for download or release notes. Currently it loads data from ship-it (<a href="https://product-details.mozilla.org/">product-details.mozilla.org</a>), but it existed even before ship-it started to export this data to public. And at this moment, I am giving <em>Mozlv</em> some love again. ;)</p>

<p>It all started at the beginning of 2015, few months after Pavel Cvrček (JasnaPaka) outlined and kicked off the so called “Mozilla.cz restart”. We have reviewed all the content on the Mozilla.cz website (OK, it was mainly done by Pavel), reduced it and redirected outdated pages to SUMO articles and other appropriate sites, that were update regularly. We have also replaced the old <a href="https://www.mozilla.cz/zpravicky/plnime-slib-a-tak-je-tu-novy-web-mozilla-cz/">Mozilla Europe like looking theme</a> for customized One Mozilla design. But despite making the whole website look new and shiny, we were still left with one big problem under the hood. The problem was in new Firefox versions being release every ~6 weeks. Each time a new version of Firefox or Thunderbird had been released, we needed to put it into WordPress. Of course, we had some plugin to update all the download links and version numbers across all pages, but we needed to watch the new releases on our own and paste them into the fields in administration.</p>

<p>Luckily we have realized soon there are several JSON files on mozilla.org and svn.mozilla.org containing exactly the information we needed. March 2015 was the month when <em>Mozlv</em> was born. It took me actually many hours, because PHP was my greatest enemy back then. :D After I have finished the plugin, there were no earth-shaking changes there. Yes, Firefox for Android and iOS were added, yes, ship-it replaced files placed on the svn server, but there were no bigger features, not even needed. Most of my commits were about fixing breakages.</p>

<p>About a week ago, you may have noticed, that I have added few commits and released version 2.0. “Oh, new major version! There must be plenty of new stuff there, right?” No, there is not, but I have been pretty lazy in bumping the versions in the past, deploying individual commits to Mozilla.cz. Making 2.0 sounds appropriate to me when there is a version actually working after so long. And this time <em>Mozlv</em> will hopefully serve another “community restart” - Mozilla.sk. In Czech Republic we see Slovakia like our brothers. I am helping for some time to <a href="https://bugzilla.mozilla.org/show_bug.cgi?id=639192">revise the content</a> and soon we want to pick a new Mozilla theme too. But there will be one more thing… you are right… updates of Firefox download links. The difference from Mozilla.cz is, that on Mozilla.sk we want to not just switch to <em>Mozlv</em>, but also display an archive of previous Firefox releases. That’s something not implemented in the plugin and I hope to find some time to do it this autumn. And as a bonus, I have discovered there is an AMO JSON API, that would allow us to display information about features extensions from AMO too!</p>

<p><em>Mozlv</em> is my first project and after more than two years, I am surprised the code is still used somewhere, even more it seems to get extended by two quite big features soon and be deployed to a new website. If you run a community website on WordPress and deal with updating Firefox versions manually, try Mozilla Latest Version. The code is available on <a href="https://github.com/MozillaCZ/mozilla-latest-version/">GitHub</a> and if you encounter any issues with deployment, feel free to get in touch.</p>]]>
  </description>
  <pubDate>Thu, 07 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  
</item>

<item>
  <title>Ram Dayal Vaishnav - Highlights from Netherlands HackerCamp – SHA2017!</title>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://gurumukhi.wordpress.com/?p=882</guid>
  <link>https://gurumukhi.wordpress.com/2017/09/05/highlights-from-netherlands-hackercamp-sha/</link>
  <description>
    <![CDATA[SHA, aka Still Hacking Anyways, is part of international non profit outdoor hacker camp series organized once in 4 years in The Netherlands. This year it was organized in Zeewolde on August 4th to 8th and I was honored to be one of speakers at SHA for my WebVR talk. Read my blogpost ‘SHA Hacker … <a href="https://gurumukhi.wordpress.com/2017/09/05/highlights-from-netherlands-hackercamp-sha/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">→</span></a><img alt="" border="0" height="1" src="https://pixel.wp.com/b.gif?host=gurumukhi.wordpress.com&amp;blog=41498319&amp;post=882&amp;subd=gurumukhi&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" />]]>
  </description>
  <pubDate>Mon, 04 Sep 2017 20:32:51 +0000</pubDate>
  
</item>

<item>
  <title>Mehul Patel - MozConnect with IEEE R10 Sectional Leadership Summit</title>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.rowdymehul.com/?p=1374</guid>
  <link>http://www.rowdymehul.com/mozconnect-with-ieee-r10-sectional-leadership-summit/</link>
  <description>
    <![CDATA[<p>While wrapping up with <a href="http://www.rowdymehul.com/rain-of-rust-how-we-did-it/">RainOfRust</a> campaigns I was working on reports and gathering feedbacks from the community about our recent initiative and we got an overwhelmed responses from the all around. The participation with IEEE R10 Sectional Leadership Summit was one of the feedback of our recent work for the community.</p>
<p>Here IEEE Gujarat Section and IEEE GCET Student Branch invited me to join at IEEE R10 Sectional Leadership Summit which was organized on 3rd &amp; 4th August at G H Patel College of Engineering &amp; Technology, Vallabh Vidyanagar, Gujarat.</p>
<p>I was very excited and I accepted their invitation as this was the 1st time Mozilla’s presence at IEEE summit.</p>
<p><a href="https://i1.wp.com/www.rowdymehul.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/IMG_2666.jpg"><img alt="" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1381" src="https://i1.wp.com/www.rowdymehul.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/IMG_2666.jpg?resize=720%2C480" /></a><span id="more-1374"></span></p>
<p><strong>About the summit:</strong></p>
<p>The Leadership Summit aims to convene student members of the IEEE to enable them to discuss the growth and development of IEEE student activities in societies, not only within the Section but also in Region 10 (Asia- Pacific) as a whole.</p>
<p>The theme of the summit <strong>was Innovation and Empowerment.</strong></p>
<p>The students will be from all levels of UG and PG programs will be benefitting from the summit. The given theme will encourage and motivate the students on how can they have a way to innovation. There will be discussions and parallel sessions, conducted by Industrialists and professionals, which will focus on the recent trends and upcoming technologies.</p>
<p>This event has definitely uplifted the Section as a whole and created a benchmark for other events taking place across India as well</p>
<p>This was my first visit to this City and university so I was really excited to talk with participants and experts who came to attend this summit.</p>
<p>My session was second last and here I started addressing the audience by sharing about Mozilla and its mission before I moved on to my actual talk i.e. <strong>Open Innovation</strong>.</p>
<p><a href="https://i2.wp.com/www.rowdymehul.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/open.jpg"><img alt="" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1376" src="https://i2.wp.com/www.rowdymehul.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/open.jpg?resize=640%2C427" /></a>Here we have discussed <em><strong>How open is it for everyone?</strong></em> Many students shared their thoughts during the talk and it was great to hear their thoughts.</p>
<blockquote><p><strong>“Open”</strong> means that anyone can publish or invent online without asking for permission, and that the technologies used to run the Web are transparent and understandable.</p></blockquote>
<p>Then after I have talked about the Open Innovation Toolkit, <em>The Open Innovation Toolkit is a community sourced set of best practices and principles to help you incorporate human-centered design into your product development process. Whether you have a new idea or a working prototype to test, the Open Innovation Toolkit can help.</em></p>
<p><a href="https://i1.wp.com/www.rowdymehul.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/IMG_4186.jpg"><img alt="" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1378" src="https://i1.wp.com/www.rowdymehul.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/IMG_4186.jpg?resize=720%2C480" /></a></p>
<p><em>Mozilla Innovation team have designed best 3 methods,</em></p>
<ol>
<li>Gather Insights</li>
<li>Ideate</li>
<li>Prototype&amp; Test</li>
</ol>
<p>More details, <a href="https://toolkit.mozilla.org/methods/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">click here</a>.</p>
<p>Due to limited time, I go ahead with <strong>“Ideate</strong>” method to discuss more by running 2 activities among participants.</p>
<p><strong>1st Activity :</strong></p>
<h2><b>5 “Whys”</b></h2>
<blockquote><p>Purpose of this activity to get to the root cause of the problem with the goal of thinking differently and as a result you will analyse the root cause which is great at making sure you are solving the right problem at first.</p></blockquote>
<p><a href="https://i2.wp.com/www.rowdymehul.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/photo_2017-08-22_22-26-21.jpg"><img alt="" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1380" src="https://i2.wp.com/www.rowdymehul.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/photo_2017-08-22_22-26-21.jpg?resize=720%2C720" /></a></p>
<p><strong>2nd Activity :</strong></p>
<h2><strong>Mind map</strong></h2>
<p><em>A Mind Map is a powerful graphic technique which provides a universal key to unlock the potential of the brain.</em></p>
<blockquote><p>This activity helps when you are facing complex problem. They are organic in their structure and allows us to, via a visual representation, explain how a system or concept is complement each other.</p></blockquote>
<p>Just to understand better we have run this activity with all the participants present there, I have already informed organizing team to put some bank papers and pen to participants kit.</p>
<p>I have explained to them how this works and what they need to follow to be part of this activity: so here are the steps :</p>
<ol>
<li>Start in the center of your page with the subject you want to mind map around. For example “Security”</li>
</ol>
<p>2. Break down the main concept into the areas it relates to. Like “Cyber Security”, “tracking”, gadgets”, “tools”, “threats” “precautions” etc.</p>
<p>3. Further, continue branching those streams out and thinking about what is related until your entire paper is filled out.</p>
<p>4. The end result should be having complete overview of the branches of ideas or concepts that came from your starting point.</p>
<p>At the end of this activity, some students shared an overview of the branches of their ideas and that was an amazing experience.</p>
<p><a href="https://i0.wp.com/www.rowdymehul.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/IMG_4254.jpg"><img alt="" class="wp-image-1379 size-full" src="https://i0.wp.com/www.rowdymehul.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/IMG_4254.jpg?resize=720%2C480" /></a></p>
<h4 style="text-align: center;">Thanks<strong><em>, IEEE Team </em></strong><em>for this</em> memento<strong><em>.</em></strong></h4>
<p><strong>Reps </strong>link: <a href="https://reps.mozilla.org/e/mozconnect-with-ieee-r10-sectional-leadership-summit/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">https://reps.mozilla.org/e/mozconnect-with-ieee-r10-sectional-leadership-summit/</a></p>
<p><strong>Presentation </strong>link: <a href="https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1VH9dwWivvv3VtluOySk1hK7G9f6gC-Z93n3xeAwx_fs/edit?usp=sharing" rel="noopener" target="_blank">https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1VH9dwWivvv3VtluOySk1hK7G9f6gC-Z93n3xeAwx_fs/edit?usp=sharing</a></p>
<p><strong>Google Drive (Photos) </strong>link: <a href="https://drive.google.com/drive/folders/0B3XrTbfRbskSaW1wemlPRlhsV1U?usp=sharing" rel="noopener" target="_blank">https://drive.google.com/drive/folders/0B3XrTbfRbskSaW1wemlPRlhsV1U?usp=sharing</a></p>
<h1>What Next?</h1>
<ul>
<li>I am looking for more such collaboration with such organizations to spread the Mozilla mission.</li>
<li>Helping them to start <a href="https://campus.mozilla.community/">Campus Club</a> in their university.</li>
<li>Next series of Rust talk at G H Patel College of Engineering &amp; Technology with IEEE GCET Computer Society</li>
</ul>
<p style="text-align: center;"><em>Hope you enjoyed my blog! <img alt="🙂" class="wp-smiley" src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/2.3/72x72/1f642.png" style="height: 1em;" /></em></p>]]>
  </description>
  <pubDate>Tue, 22 Aug 2017 17:18:40 +0000</pubDate>
  
</item>

<item>
  <title>Abhiram Ravikumar - It’s raining Rust at Red Hat</title>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://abhiramrk.com/?p=322</guid>
  <link>http://abhiramrk.com/its-raining-rust-at-red-hat/</link>
  <description>
    <![CDATA[<p>I know it’s been a while since I’ve put out a post and mostly because I’m trying to learn amazing things and get my hands dirty, trying to build solutions that actually make sense.</p>
<p>One such pet-project has been Rust, probably the <a href="https://redmonk.com/sogrady/2017/06/08/language-rankings-6-17/">fastest</a> growing systems level programming language today. Hitherto, I’ve always looked at Rust from the outside, never got my hands dirty, mostly because I was under the assumption that it had nothing to do with web development. Turns out, I was completely wrong!</p>
<p>This year’s <a href="https://discourse.mozilla.org/t/rainofrust-campaign-trailer/15852">Rain of Rust</a> campaign gave me an opportunity to revisit the programming language and the reason why it’s been garnering interests at astronomical pace. For a nascent programming language which is in the 1.19th version of its release, it’s challenging the big guns – C and C++. Yes, you heard <a href="https://www.quora.com/Which-language-has-the-brightest-future-in-replacement-of-C-between-D-Go-and-Rust-And-Why">it </a>right.</p>
<h3>On to the campaign</h3>
<p>The campaign, although initiated and led by volunteers from the Mozilla India community at first was later adopted by the larger Mozilla community with contributions from all over the world like these events in <a href="https://reps.mozilla.org/e/rust-activate/">Mexico </a>and <a href="https://reps.mozilla.org/e/dive-into-rust-senai-santa-cecilia/">Brazil</a>. The main goal of the event was to increase outreach about the language and train developers to contribute in the rust ecosystem.</p>
<h3>At Bangalore</h3>
<p>As one of the crucial aspects of the campaign was to organize on-the-ground events and so, with the gracious support of our host Sumantro at Red Hat, we managed to pull of a small event consisting of rust enthusiasts and Mozilla Tech Speakers.</p>
<p>We had our very own Vigneshwer leading the introduction to rust and hands-on session. This was well taken by the participants who had just installed rust and exploring what they could do with the language.</p>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">We have <a href="https://twitter.com/dvigneshwer">@dvigneshwer</a> today kick starting <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/RainOfRust?src=hash">#RainOfRust</a>  at BLR. <a href="https://twitter.com/rustlang">@rustlang</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/mozTechSpeakers">@mozTechSpeakers</a> <img alt="🌟" class="wp-smiley" src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/2.3/72x72/1f31f.png" style="height: 1em;" /> other talks lined up.. <a href="https://t.co/EGvXB63sS3">pic.twitter.com/EGvXB63sS3</a></p>
<p>— Abhiram Ravikumar (@abhi12ravi) <a href="https://twitter.com/abhi12ravi/status/878555743338676225">June 24, 2017</a></p></blockquote>
<p></p>
<p>With witty remarks, use cases and insights of the language, Vigneshwer kept the participants interested. During the hands-on he introduced the <a href="https://github.com/MozillaIndia/RustIndia/tree/master/RainOfRust#rust-kits">kits </a>built by the Rust India community and explained how participants could use them to learn the language. On the whole, it was a well-rounded session and helped the participants understand why rust is important and how they could contribute.</p>
<p>We then had a talk by Ravi from <a href="https://www.atherenergy.com/">Ather energy</a> which has used rust components to send  location data packets from its two-wheeler vehicles to the cloud in a secure and reliable fashion. His talk was inspirational as the participants were able to visualize how rust could be used in a production scenario.</p>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Second talk of the day by Ravi from <a href="https://twitter.com/atherenergy">@atherenergy</a> using <a href="https://twitter.com/rustlang">@rustlang</a> in production environments! <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/RainOfRust?src=hash">#RainOfRust</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/mozTechSpeakers">@mozTechSpeakers</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/MozillaIN">@MozillaIN</a> <img alt="🌟" class="wp-smiley" src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/2.3/72x72/1f31f.png" style="height: 1em;" /> <a href="https://t.co/hNZcVSlmhV">pic.twitter.com/hNZcVSlmhV</a></p>
<p>— Abhiram Ravikumar (@abhi12ravi) <a href="https://twitter.com/abhi12ravi/status/878572229981683714">June 24, 2017</a></p></blockquote>
<p></p>
<p>For the last talk of the day, we had our own ReMo and host Sumantro show a demo on <a href="https://rocket.rs/">Rocket</a>, a simple web framework for rust developers. This was in particular interest to me as a web developer, hitherto I was under the impression that rust could only be used for parallel computing and system level programming scenarios.  Now that I know rust has a fast and safe web framework, watch out JavaScript! Here’s Sumantro’s <a href="http://sumantrom.blogspot.in/2017/04/rocket-on-fedora.html">post </a>on how to set it up on Fedora.</p>
<div class="fb-social-plugin fb-post"></div>
<p> </p>
<h3>Last word</h3>
<p>On the whole it was personally fulfilling that we pulled off a workshop in ~1 week of planning and what was comforting was that the feedback we received through the new ReMo <a href="https://github.com/mozilla/activate.mozilla.community/issues/210">feedback form</a> was a 6+ on a scale of 0-7. Yay!</p>
<p>Finishing off with a mighty group photo. A round of shout-outs to Bhumika and Ra Fey for helping us out with the posters and social media calls to action! You guys are wonderful. ^_^</p>
<p> </p>
<div class="wp-caption aligncenter" id="attachment_336" style="width: 656px;"><a href="http://abhiramrk.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/grouppic.jpg"><img alt="Rust Workshop | June 2017 | Bangalore" class="wp-image-336 size-large" height="507" src="http://abhiramrk.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/grouppic-1024x804.jpg" width="646" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Rust Workshop | June 2017 | Bangalore</p></div>
<p> </p>
<p>Fin.</p>
<a class="likepost json-call 1-322-posts" href="http://abhiramrk.com/feed/?fn=like&amp;following=1-322-posts">Like</a><p><a class="a2a_button_facebook" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/facebook?linkurl=http%3A%2F%2Fabhiramrk.com%2Fits-raining-rust-at-red-hat%2F&amp;linkname=It%E2%80%99s%20raining%20Rust%20at%20Red%20Hat" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank" title="Facebook"></a><a class="a2a_button_twitter" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/twitter?linkurl=http%3A%2F%2Fabhiramrk.com%2Fits-raining-rust-at-red-hat%2F&amp;linkname=It%E2%80%99s%20raining%20Rust%20at%20Red%20Hat" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank" title="Twitter"></a><a class="a2a_button_google_plus" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/google_plus?linkurl=http%3A%2F%2Fabhiramrk.com%2Fits-raining-rust-at-red-hat%2F&amp;linkname=It%E2%80%99s%20raining%20Rust%20at%20Red%20Hat" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank" title="Google+"></a><a class="a2a_button_whatsapp" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/whatsapp?linkurl=http%3A%2F%2Fabhiramrk.com%2Fits-raining-rust-at-red-hat%2F&amp;linkname=It%E2%80%99s%20raining%20Rust%20at%20Red%20Hat" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank" title="WhatsApp"></a><a class="a2a_button_diaspora" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/diaspora?linkurl=http%3A%2F%2Fabhiramrk.com%2Fits-raining-rust-at-red-hat%2F&amp;linkname=It%E2%80%99s%20raining%20Rust%20at%20Red%20Hat" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank" title="Diaspora"></a><a class="a2a_button_wordpress" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/wordpress?linkurl=http%3A%2F%2Fabhiramrk.com%2Fits-raining-rust-at-red-hat%2F&amp;linkname=It%E2%80%99s%20raining%20Rust%20at%20Red%20Hat" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank" title="WordPress"></a><a class="a2a_button_tumblr" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/tumblr?linkurl=http%3A%2F%2Fabhiramrk.com%2Fits-raining-rust-at-red-hat%2F&amp;linkname=It%E2%80%99s%20raining%20Rust%20at%20Red%20Hat" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank" title="Tumblr"></a><a class="a2a_button_blogger_post" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/blogger_post?linkurl=http%3A%2F%2Fabhiramrk.com%2Fits-raining-rust-at-red-hat%2F&amp;linkname=It%E2%80%99s%20raining%20Rust%20at%20Red%20Hat" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank" title="Blogger Post"></a><a class="a2a_button_hacker_news" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/hacker_news?linkurl=http%3A%2F%2Fabhiramrk.com%2Fits-raining-rust-at-red-hat%2F&amp;linkname=It%E2%80%99s%20raining%20Rust%20at%20Red%20Hat" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank" title="Hacker News"></a><a class="a2a_dd addtoany_share_save" href="https://www.addtoany.com/share#url=http%3A%2F%2Fabhiramrk.com%2Fits-raining-rust-at-red-hat%2F&amp;title=It%E2%80%99s%20raining%20Rust%20at%20Red%20Hat"></a></p>]]>
  </description>
  <pubDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2017 14:21:43 +0000</pubDate>
  
</item>

<item>
  <title>Geraldo Barros - Setting up the success of Dive Into Rust workshops at São Paulo</title>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">https://geraldobarros.me/?p=847</guid>
  <link>https://geraldobarros.me/setting-up-the-success-of-dive-into-rust-workshops-at-sao-paulo/</link>
  <description>
    <![CDATA[<p>The first <a href="https://activate.mozilla.community/rust-hack/">Dive Into Rust</a> workshop at São Paulo, the connection of Mozilla communities with Rust brazilian community, the people who were with us, our learnings, workshop flow, resources, follow up and the next steps.<span id="more-847"></span></p>
<p><a href="https://reps.mozilla.org/e/dive-into-rust-senai-santa-cecilia/">Last Saturday was our first Rust workshop in São Paulo</a>, an initiative that is part of the <a href="https://activate.mozilla.community/rust-hack/">Mozilla Activate campaign to introduce Rust to programmers</a> and advance a more secure web with the programming language of the future.</p>
<h4>Recruiting speakers</h4>
<p>The beginning of our journey was to find programmers who love to teach Rust and have readiness to lead training with our Brazilian community. We found Rust programmers after an <a href="https://users.rust-lang.org/t/rust-at-sao-paulo-bra-lets-spread-the-rust-as-the-future-of-systems-programming/11167">open call in the Rust forum!</a> It was the first connection to the Mozilla and Rust community.</p>
<p>And as much as you can understand Rust and perform simple tasks, meeting someone who programs and has experience is essential to a highly impactful and inspiring workshop for new <em>rustceans</em>!</p>
<h4>Workshop</h4>
<p>The Mozilla Activate campaign has a workshop flow suggestion for our activities but we dare to go further, we did a combo flow with the suggestion of <a href="https://activate.mozilla.community/rust-hack/">Dive Into Rust</a> + <a href="https://github.com/MozillaIndia/RustIndia/tree/master/RainOfRust">India’s Rain Of Rust</a> + <a href="https://github.com/mozillabrasil/dive-into-rust">activities created by ourselves</a>.</p>
<p>The result is a workshop that <strong>goes beyond testing Rust</strong>, but has practical and realistic activities for a <strong>developer’s everyday life</strong>.</p>
<h5>Workshop Flow</h5>
<ol class="listtype-number listindent1 list-number1" start="1">
<li><span class=" author-d-iz88z86z86za0dz67zz78zz78zz74zz68zjz80zz71z9iz90za3pm1z122zjz87z6wjnz83zrg4rz68zz75zrz87zz85zz81zvz90z3fz71zmz78zb">Welcome, agenda and offline icebreakers. </span><span class="highlight author-d-iz88z86z86za0dz67zz78zz78zz74zz68zjz80zz71z9iz90za3pm1z122zjz87z6wjnz83zrg4rz68zz75zrz87zz85zz81zvz90z3fz71zmz78zb"><b>10m</b></span></li>
<li><span class="attrlink url author-d-iz88z86z86za0dz67zz78zz78zz74zz68zjz80zz71z9iz90za3pm1z122zjz87z6wjnz83zrg4rz68zz75zrz87zz85zz81zvz90z3fz71zmz78zb"><a class="attrlink" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=8EPsnf_ZYU0" rel="noreferrer nofollow noopener" target="_blank"><u>Rust and the Future of Systems Programming</u></a></span><span class=" author-d-iz88z86z86za0dz67zz78zz78zz74zz68zjz80zz71z9iz90za3pm1z122zjz87z6wjnz83zrg4rz68zz75zrz87zz85zz81zvz90z3fz71zmz78zb">’s movie. </span><span class="highlight author-d-iz88z86z86za0dz67zz78zz78zz74zz68zjz80zz71z9iz90za3pm1z122zjz87z6wjnz83zrg4rz68zz75zrz87zz85zz81zvz90z3fz71zmz78zb"><b>6m</b></span></li>
<li><span class=" author-d-iz88z86z86za0dz67zz78zz78zz74zz68zjz80zz71z9iz90za3pm1z122zjz87z6wjnz83zrg4rz68zz75zrz87zz85zz81zvz90z3fz71zmz78zb">Introducing Rust: What is it? Benefits? Use in the real world. </span><span class="highlight author-d-iz88z86z86za0dz67zz78zz78zz74zz68zjz80zz71z9iz90za3pm1z122zjz87z6wjnz83zrg4rz68zz75zrz87zz85zz81zvz90z3fz71zmz78zb"><b>15m</b></span></li>
<li><span class=" author-d-iz88z86z86za0dz67zz78zz78zz74zz68zjz80zz71z9iz90za3pm1z122zjz87z6wjnz83zrg4rz68zz75zrz87zz85zz81zvz90z3fz71zmz78zb">Introducing language using the </span><span class="attrlink url author-d-iz88z86z86za0dz67zz78zz78zz74zz68zjz80zz71z9iz90za3pm1z122zjz87z6wjnz83zrg4rz68zz75zrz87zz85zz81zvz90z3fz71zmz78zb"><a class="attrlink" href="https://doc.rust-lang.org/book/second-edition/" rel="noreferrer nofollow noopener" target="_blank"><u>Rust Book V2</u></a></span><span class=" author-d-iz88z86z86za0dz67zz78zz78zz74zz68zjz80zz71z9iz90za3pm1z122zjz87z6wjnz83zrg4rz68zz75zrz87zz85zz81zvz90z3fz71zmz78zb">. </span><span class="highlight author-d-iz88z86z86za0dz67zz78zz78zz74zz68zjz80zz71z9iz90za3pm1z122zjz87z6wjnz83zrg4rz68zz75zrz87zz85zz81zvz90z3fz71zmz78zb"><b>15m</b></span></li>
<li><span class=" author-d-iz88z86z86za0dz67zz78zz78zz74zz68zjz80zz71z9iz90za3pm1z122zjz87z6wjnz83zrg4rz68zz75zrz87zz85zz81zvz90z3fz71zmz78zb">Introducing </span><span class="attrlink url author-d-iz88z86z86za0dz67zz78zz78zz74zz68zjz80zz71z9iz90za3pm1z122zjz87z6wjnz83zrg4rz68zz75zrz87zz85zz81zvz90z3fz71zmz78zb"><a class="attrlink" href="https://www.rustup.rs/" rel="noreferrer nofollow noopener" target="_blank"><u>rustup</u></a></span><span class=" author-d-iz88z86z86za0dz67zz78zz78zz74zz68zjz80zz71z9iz90za3pm1z122zjz87z6wjnz83zrg4rz68zz75zrz87zz85zz81zvz90z3fz71zmz78zb">, </span><span class="attrlink url author-d-iz88z86z86za0dz67zz78zz78zz74zz68zjz80zz71z9iz90za3pm1z122zjz87z6wjnz83zrg4rz68zz75zrz87zz85zz81zvz90z3fz71zmz78zb"><a class="attrlink" href="https://doc.rust-lang.org/book/second-edition/ch14-00-more-about-cargo.html" rel="noreferrer nofollow noopener" target="_blank"><u>Cargo</u></a></span><span class=" author-d-iz88z86z86za0dz67zz78zz78zz74zz68zjz80zz71z9iz90za3pm1z122zjz87z6wjnz83zrg4rz68zz75zrz87zz85zz81zvz90z3fz71zmz78zb">, crates.io, rustdoc, playground and quickly activities to test the Rust install and become familiar with Rust. </span><span class="highlight author-d-iz88z86z86za0dz67zz78zz78zz74zz68zjz80zz71z9iz90za3pm1z122zjz87z6wjnz83zrg4rz68zz75zrz87zz85zz81zvz90z3fz71zmz78zb"><b>15m</b></span></li>
<li><span class=" author-d-iz88z86z86za0dz67zz78zz78zz74zz68zjz80zz71z9iz90za3pm1z122zjz87z6wjnz83zrg4rz68zz75zrz87zz85zz81zvz90z3fz71zmz78zb">Exercises with the </span><span class="attrlink url author-d-iz88z86z86za0dz67zz78zz78zz74zz68zjz80zz71z9iz90za3pm1z122zjz87z6wjnz83zrg4rz68zz75zrz87zz85zz81zvz90z3fz71zmz78zb"><a class="attrlink" href="https://exercism.io/languages/rust/about" rel="noreferrer nofollow noopener" target="_blank"><u>Exercism</u></a></span><span class=" author-d-iz88z86z86za0dz67zz78zz78zz74zz68zjz80zz71z9iz90za3pm1z122zjz87z6wjnz83zrg4rz68zz75zrz87zz85zz81zvz90z3fz71zmz78zb">, an exercise together and in a group. </span><span class="highlight author-d-iz88z86z86za0dz67zz78zz78zz74zz68zjz80zz71z9iz90za3pm1z122zjz87z6wjnz83zrg4rz68zz75zrz87zz85zz81zvz90z3fz71zmz78zb"><b>30m</b></span></li>
<li><span class=" author-d-iz88z86z86za0dz67zz78zz78zz74zz68zjz80zz71z9iz90za3pm1z122zjz87z6wjnz83zrg4rz68zz75zrz87zz85zz81zvz90z3fz71zmz78zb">Introducing to the Ownership and exercise: move semantics of </span><span class="attrlink url author-d-iz88z86z86za0dz67zz78zz78zz74zz68zjz80zz71z9iz90za3pm1z122zjz87z6wjnz83zrg4rz68zz75zrz87zz85zz81zvz90z3fz71zmz78zb"><a class="attrlink" href="https://github.com/carols10cents/rustlings" rel="noreferrer nofollow noopener" target="_blank"><u>Rustlings</u></a></span><span class=" author-d-iz88z86z86za0dz67zz78zz78zz74zz68zjz80zz71z9iz90za3pm1z122zjz87z6wjnz83zrg4rz68zz75zrz87zz85zz81zvz90z3fz71zmz78zb">. </span><span class="highlight author-d-iz88z86z86za0dz67zz78zz78zz74zz68zjz80zz71z9iz90za3pm1z122zjz87z6wjnz83zrg4rz68zz75zrz87zz85zz81zvz90z3fz71zmz78zb"><b>30m</b></span></li>
<li><span class="attrlink url author-d-iz88z86z86za0dz67zz78zz78zz74zz68zjz80zz71z9iz90za3pm1z122zjz87z6wjnz83zrg4rz68zz75zrz87zz85zz81zvz90z3fz71zmz78zb"><a class="attrlink" href="https://is.gd/usZmBy" rel="noreferrer nofollow noopener" target="_blank">Structs</a></span><span class=" author-d-iz88z86z86za0dz67zz78zz78zz74zz68zjz80zz71z9iz90za3pm1z122zjz87z6wjnz83zrg4rz68zz75zrz87zz85zz81zvz90z3fz71zmz78zb"> and </span><span class="attrlink url author-d-iz88z86z86za0dz67zz78zz78zz74zz68zjz80zz71z9iz90za3pm1z122zjz87z6wjnz83zrg4rz68zz75zrz87zz85zz81zvz90z3fz71zmz78zb"><a class="attrlink" href="https://is.gd/141bRV" rel="noreferrer nofollow noopener" target="_blank">enums</a></span><span class=" author-d-iz88z86z86za0dz67zz78zz78zz74zz68zjz80zz71z9iz90za3pm1z122zjz87z6wjnz83zrg4rz68zz75zrz87zz85zz81zvz90z3fz71zmz78zb"> exercises. </span><span class="highlight author-d-iz88z86z86za0dz67zz78zz78zz74zz68zjz80zz71z9iz90za3pm1z122zjz87z6wjnz83zrg4rz68zz75zrz87zz85zz81zvz90z3fz71zmz78zb"><b>30m</b></span></li>
<li><span class=" author-d-iz88z86z86za0dz67zz78zz78zz74zz68zjz80zz71z9iz90za3pm1z122zjz87z6wjnz83zrg4rz68zz75zrz87zz85zz81zvz90z3fz71zmz78zb">Exercise about parallelism: </span><span class="attrlink url author-d-iz88z86z86za0dz67zz78zz78zz74zz68zjz80zz71z9iz90za3pm1z122zjz87z6wjnz83zrg4rz68zz75zrz87zz85zz81zvz90z3fz71zmz78zb"><a class="attrlink" href="https://github.com/leodasvacas/hashcash/blob/master/src/main.rs" rel="noreferrer nofollow noopener" target="_blank">A parallel bitcoin miner</a></span><span class=" author-d-iz88z86z86za0dz67zz78zz78zz74zz68zjz80zz71z9iz90za3pm1z122zjz87z6wjnz83zrg4rz68zz75zrz87zz85zz81zvz90z3fz71zmz78zb">. </span><span class="highlight author-d-iz88z86z86za0dz67zz78zz78zz74zz68zjz80zz71z9iz90za3pm1z122zjz87z6wjnz83zrg4rz68zz75zrz87zz85zz81zvz90z3fz71zmz78zb"><b>30m</b></span></li>
<li><span class=" author-d-iz88z86z86za0dz67zz78zz78zz74zz68zjz80zz71z9iz90za3pm1z122zjz87z6wjnz83zrg4rz68zz75zrz87zz85zz81zvz90z3fz71zmz78zb">Free Rust Hackathon</span> <span class=" author-d-iz88z86z86za0dz67zz78zz78zz74zz68zjz80zz71z9iz90za3pm1z122zjz87z6wjnz83zrg4rz68zz75zrz87zz85zz81zvz90z3fz71zmz78zb h-mdash">—</span><span class=" author-d-iz88z86z86za0dz67zz78zz78zz74zz68zjz80zz71z9iz90za3pm1z122zjz87z6wjnz83zrg4rz68zz75zrz87zz85zz81zvz90z3fz71zmz78zb">  attendees will choose and develop a project with Rust. </span><span class="highlight author-d-iz88z86z86za0dz67zz78zz78zz74zz68zjz80zz71z9iz90za3pm1z122zjz87z6wjnz83zrg4rz68zz75zrz87zz85zz81zvz90z3fz71zmz78zb"><b>100m</b></span>
<ol class="listtype-number listindent2 list-number2" start="1">
<li><span class=" author-d-iz88z86z86za0dz67zz78zz78zz74zz68zjz80zz71z9iz90za3pm1z122zjz87z6wjnz83zrg4rz68zz75zrz87zz85zz81zvz90z3fz71zmz78zb">Continue Exercising Exercism</span></li>
<li><span class=" author-d-iz88z86z86za0dz67zz78zz78zz74zz68zjz80zz71z9iz90za3pm1z122zjz87z6wjnz83zrg4rz68zz75zrz87zz85zz81zvz90z3fz71zmz78zb">Client and chat server for terminal</span></li>
<li><span class=" author-d-iz88z86z86za0dz67zz78zz78zz74zz68zjz80zz71z9iz90za3pm1z122zjz87z6wjnz83zrg4rz68zz75zrz87zz85zz81zvz90z3fz71zmz78zb">Web client</span> <span class=" author-d-iz88z86z86za0dz67zz78zz78zz74zz68zjz80zz71z9iz90za3pm1z122zjz87z6wjnz83zrg4rz68zz75zrz87zz85zz81zvz90z3fz71zmz78zb h-lparen">(</span><span class=" author-d-iz88z86z86za0dz67zz78zz78zz74zz68zjz80zz71z9iz90za3pm1z122zjz87z6wjnz83zrg4rz68zz75zrz87zz85zz81zvz90z3fz71zmz78zb">API access or scraping)</span></li>
<li><span class=" author-d-iz88z86z86za0dz67zz78zz78zz74zz68zjz80zz71z9iz90za3pm1z122zjz87z6wjnz83zrg4rz68zz75zrz87zz85zz81zvz90z3fz71zmz78zb">Web server with JSON API</span></li>
<li><span class=" author-d-iz88z86z86za0dz67zz78zz78zz74zz68zjz80zz71z9iz90za3pm1z122zjz87z6wjnz83zrg4rz68zz75zrz87zz85zz81zvz90z3fz71zmz78zb">Access a database</span></li>
<li><span class=" author-d-iz88z86z86za0dz67zz78zz78zz74zz68zjz80zz71z9iz90za3pm1z122zjz87z6wjnz83zrg4rz68zz75zrz87zz85zz81zvz90z3fz71zmz78zb">Make a graphical interface</span></li>
<li><span class=" author-d-iz88z86z86za0dz67zz78zz78zz74zz68zjz80zz71z9iz90za3pm1z122zjz87z6wjnz83zrg4rz68zz75zrz87zz85zz81zvz90z3fz71zmz78zb">Use a Rust library through your favorite language</span> <span class=" author-d-iz88z86z86za0dz67zz78zz78zz74zz68zjz80zz71z9iz90za3pm1z122zjz87z6wjnz83zrg4rz68zz75zrz87zz85zz81zvz90z3fz71zmz78zb h-lparen">(</span><span class="attrlink url author-d-iz88z86z86za0dz67zz78zz78zz74zz68zjz80zz71z9iz90za3pm1z122zjz87z6wjnz83zrg4rz68zz75zrz87zz85zz81zvz90z3fz71zmz78zb"><a class="attrlink" href="https://dvigneshwer.github.io/posts/2016/04/Rust-Python/" rel="noreferrer nofollow noopener" target="_blank"><u>Python</u></a></span><span class=" author-d-iz88z86z86za0dz67zz78zz78zz74zz68zjz80zz71z9iz90za3pm1z122zjz87z6wjnz83zrg4rz68zz75zrz87zz85zz81zvz90z3fz71zmz78zb">)</span></li>
<li><span class=" author-d-iz88z86z86za0dz67zz78zz78zz74zz68zjz80zz71z9iz90za3pm1z122zjz87z6wjnz83zrg4rz68zz75zrz87zz85zz81zvz90z3fz71zmz78zb">Rust-python binding</span>
<ol class="listtype-number listindent3 list-number3" start="1">
<li><span class=" author-d-iz88z86z86za0dz67zz78zz78zz74zz68zjz80zz71z9iz90za3pm1z122zjz87z6wjnz83zrg4rz68zz75zrz87zz85zz81zvz90z3fz71zmz78zb">Creating a python module in Rust which focusses on delivering high performance</span></li>
<li><span class="attrlink url author-d-iz88z86z86za0dz67zz78zz78zz74zz68zjz80zz71z9iz90za3pm1z122zjz87z6wjnz83zrg4rz68zz75zrz87zz85zz81zvz90z3fz71zmz78zb"><a class="attrlink" href="https://github.com/MozillaIndia/RustIndia/blob/master/RainOfRust/rust_python_fib" rel="noreferrer nofollow noopener" target="_blank">Code</a></span></li>
<li><span class="attrlink url author-d-iz88z86z86za0dz67zz78zz78zz74zz68zjz80zz71z9iz90za3pm1z122zjz87z6wjnz83zrg4rz68zz75zrz87zz85zz81zvz90z3fz71zmz78zb"><a class="attrlink" href="https://dvigneshwer.github.io/posts/2016/04/Rust-Python/" rel="noreferrer nofollow noopener" target="_blank">Read the documentation here</a></span></li>
</ol>
</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li><span class=" author-d-iz88z86z86za0dz67zz78zz78zz74zz68zjz80zz71z9iz90za3pm1z122zjz87z6wjnz83zrg4rz68zz75zrz87zz85zz81zvz90z3fz71zmz78zb">Open feedback e feedback for Mozilla using </span><span class="attrlink url author-d-iz88z86z86za0dz67zz78zz78zz74zz68zjz80zz71z9iz90za3pm1z122zjz87z6wjnz83zrg4rz68zz75zrz87zz85zz81zvz90z3fz71zmz78zb url"><a class="attrlink" href="https://mzl.la/howwasit" rel="noreferrer nofollow noopener" target="_blank"><u>https://mzl.la/howwasit</u></a></span><span class=" author-d-iz88z86z86za0dz67zz78zz78zz74zz68zjz80zz71z9iz90za3pm1z122zjz87z6wjnz83zrg4rz68zz75zrz87zz85zz81zvz90z3fz71zmz78zb">. </span><span class="highlight author-d-iz88z86z86za0dz67zz78zz78zz74zz68zjz80zz71z9iz90za3pm1z122zjz87z6wjnz83zrg4rz68zz75zrz87zz85zz81zvz90z3fz71zmz78zb"><b>5m</b></span></li>
</ol>
<h5>Photos</h5>
<p><img alt="" class="aligncenter" height="1536" src="https://pbs.twimg.com/media/DHC7BuaXkAEXtTz.jpg:large" width="2048" /></p>
<h5><img alt="" class="aligncenter wp-image-869 size-full" height="1152" src="https://geraldobarros.me/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/DG9zEMrXsAMmh5n.jpglarge.jpeg" width="2048" /> <img alt="" class="aligncenter wp-image-868 size-full" height="2160" src="https://geraldobarros.me/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/DSC_0033.jpg" width="3840" /> <img alt="" class="aligncenter wp-image-867 size-full" height="2160" src="https://geraldobarros.me/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/DSC_0032.jpg" width="3840" /> <img alt="" class="aligncenter wp-image-865 size-full" height="2160" src="https://geraldobarros.me/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/DSC_0030.jpg" width="3840" /><img alt="" class="aligncenter wp-image-862 size-full" height="3936" src="https://geraldobarros.me/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/DSC_0024.jpg" width="5248" /> <img alt="" class="aligncenter wp-image-864 size-full" height="2160" src="https://geraldobarros.me/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/DSC_0027-1.jpg" width="3840" /> <img alt="" class="aligncenter wp-image-861 size-full" height="3936" src="https://geraldobarros.me/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/DSC_0021-1.jpg" width="5248" /></h5>
<h4>Learnings</h4>
<h5>Who wants to learn Rust?</h5>
<ul>
<li>People who already coding are interested in learning Rust;</li>
<li>People who coding and work in big companies who are looking for great solutions to improve their applications;</li>
<li>People in the interior of the state of São Paulo are extremely interested</li>
</ul>
<h5>What is the ideal format?</h5>
<ul>
<li>A diverse, hands-on workshop focused on day-to-day activities ensures that developers understand Rust’s way of programming and operating;</li>
<li>Activities that work with other languages like Python are a plus and shows the power of Rust language;</li>
</ul>
<h5>Marketing?</h5>
<ul>
<li>Facebook is a powerful network to promote the workshop, <strong>in only 2 hours our tickets sold out</strong>;</li>
<li>Workshops with 20-25 people is ideal for highly impactful activities using Rust;</li>
<li>We need to organize more workshops because we have a <strong>waiting list of around 60 people</strong> and <strong>more people want to learn Rust every day</strong>.</li>
</ul>
<h4>Follow up</h4>
<p>The participants connected to the Brazilian community of Rust in the Telegram, which is extremely active, and guided to join the official channels of communication and resources.</p>
<h4>Next steps</h4>
<ul>
<li><strong>We are ready and eagerly awaiting the next workshop</strong> that will happen in Belo Horizonte, state of Minas Gerais, the land of cheese bread! <strong><a href="https://www.eventbrite.com.br/e/mergulhando-em-rust-o-futuro-da-programacao-de-sistemas-2-registration-36876136517">Apply now to this workshop</a></strong>!</li>
<li>We are going to be present in Brazilian podcasts to talk about Rust and <a href="https://hacks.mozilla.org/2016/07/shipping-rust-in-firefox/">ambitious Mozilla plans with Rust and Firefox</a>;</li>
<li>We will approach the <a href="https://t.me/rustlangbr">Rust brazilian community</a> to support with resources, guidance and planning;</li>
<li>We will reach out to the <a href="https://twitter.com/rustlang">Rust Community Team</a> on how the Rust community and our activities can support the overall goals of the community.</li>
</ul>
<h4>Thank You</h4>
<p><em>A big #MozLove to</em></p>
<ul>
<li>Cybelle, our aweeesome workshop organizer!</li>
<li>Leonardo from Unicamp, our aweeeesome and expert Rust Speaker!</li>
<li>Matheus, Alda and team player &amp; SENAI for big support with place and infra!</li>
<li><strong>Also for all attendees and newcomers at Rust brazilian community!</strong></li>
</ul>
<div class="wp-video" style="width: 700px;">
<video class="wp-video-shortcode" controls="controls" height="360" id="video-847-1" loop="1" width="700"><source src="https://geraldobarros.me/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/giphy.mp4?_=1" type="video/mp4" /><a href="https://geraldobarros.me/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/giphy.mp4">https://geraldobarros.me/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/giphy.mp4</a></video></div>
<p>The post <a href="https://geraldobarros.me/setting-up-the-success-of-dive-into-rust-workshops-at-sao-paulo/" rel="nofollow">Setting up the success of Dive Into Rust workshops at São Paulo</a> appeared first on <a href="https://geraldobarros.me" rel="nofollow">Geraldo Barros</a>.</p>]]>
  </description>
  <pubDate>Tue, 15 Aug 2017 18:14:08 +0000</pubDate>
  
</item>

<item>
  <title>Official Reps Blog - Reps Program Objectives – Q3 2017</title>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.mozilla.org/mozillareps/?p=510</guid>
  <link>https://blog.mozilla.org/mozillareps/2017/08/15/reps-program-objectives-q3-2017/</link>
  <description>
    <![CDATA[<p>As with every quarter, we define Objectives and Key Results for the Reps Program. We are happy to announce the Objectives for the current quarter.</p>
<p><strong>Objective 1</strong>: <strong>The Reps program continues to grow its process maturity</strong><br />
KR1: 20 Reps have been trained with the Resource training<br />
KR2: 100% of the budget requests of new Reps are filed by Resource Track Reps<br />
KR3: 30 Reps complete the coaching training<br />
KR4: The amount of mentor-less Reps is reduced by 50%<br />
KR5: Increase number of authors for Reps tweets to 10 people</p>
<p><strong>Objective 2: The Reps program is the backbone for any mobilizing needs</strong><br />
KR1: We documented what mobilizing Reps are focusing on<br />
KR2: An implementation roadmap for mobilizers’ recommendations is in place.<br />
KR3: Identified 1 key measures that is defining how our Mobilizers add value to the coding and Non-Coding/Enthusiast communities</p>
<p><strong>Objective 3: The Activate Portal is improved for Mobilizer Reps and Functional Areas</strong><br />
KR1: The Rust activity is updated<br />
KR2: The WebExtensions activity update has been tested in 3 pilot events in 3 different countries<br />
KR3: 60 unique Reps have run a MozActivate event<br />
KR4: The website is updated to the new branding</p>
<p>We will work closely with the Community Development Team to achieve our goals. You can follow the progress of these tasks in the <a href="https://waffle.io/mozilla/Reps">Reps Issue Tracker</a>. We also have a <a href="http://mozilla.github.io/Reps/okr-dashboard/">dashboard</a> to track the status of each objective.</p>
<p>Which of the above objectives are you most interested in? What key result would you like to hear more about? What do you find intriguing? Which thoughts cross your mind upon reading this? Where would you like to help out? Let’s keep the conversation going! <a href="https://discourse.mozilla.org/t/reps-program-q3-okrs-2017/17859">Join the discussion on Discourse.</a></p>]]>
  </description>
  <pubDate>Tue, 15 Aug 2017 08:16:02 +0000</pubDate>
  
</item>

<item>
  <title>Robert Reyes - First Time at COSCUP Taiwan</title>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.bobreyes.com/myblog/?p=5421</guid>
  <link>http://www.bobreyes.com/myblog/first-time-coscup-taiwan/</link>
  <description>
    <![CDATA[<p>I had the opportunity to represent Mozilla (and my country) in COSCUP 2017 over the weekend. COSCUP is an annual conference held by Taiwanese Open source community participants since 2006. It’s a major force of Free software movement advocacy in Taiwan. The event is often held with talks, sponsor and communities booths, and Birds of […]</p>
<p>The post <a href="http://www.bobreyes.com/myblog/first-time-coscup-taiwan/" rel="nofollow">First Time at COSCUP Taiwan</a> appeared first on <a href="http://www.bobreyes.com/myblog" rel="nofollow">Bob Reyes Dot Com</a>.</p>]]>
  </description>
  <pubDate>Mon, 07 Aug 2017 02:35:27 +0000</pubDate>
  
</item>

<item>
  <title>Christophe Villeneuve - Création de MoCo – 3 août 2005 – Coup d'œil dans le rétro</title>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">urn:md5:c79ffd466956db399b5dbc71deee7e90</guid>
  <link>https://blog.mozfr.org/post/2017/08/Creation-MoCo-3-aout-2005</link>
  <description>
    <![CDATA[<p><strong>Firefox n’est pas né de nulle part. Il est le fruit d’une riche histoire. Découvrons-en un événement marquant.</strong></p>

<p><a href="https://blog.mozfr.org/dotclear/public/mozilla/retro/Mozilla_Leadership_boards.png" title="Mozilla Leadership : boards (août 2017)"><img alt="Mozilla Leadership : boards (août 2017)" src="https://blog.mozfr.org/dotclear/public/mozilla/retro/.Mozilla_Leadership_boards_m.png" style="float: right; margin: 0 0 1em 1em; width: 300px;" /></a>Le 3 août 2005, la <a href="https://blog.mozfr.org/post/2017/07/Creation-Mozilla-Foundation-15-juillet-2003" hreflang="fr" title="Création de la Mozilla Foundation – 15 juillet 2003 – Coup d'œil dans le rétro (15 juil. 2017) Communauté Mozilla francophone"><i lang="en">Mozilla Foundation</i></a>, l’organisation d’intérêt général sans but lucratif de développement de logiciels et chargée du pilotage du projet Mozilla, <a href="http://www-archive.mozilla.org/reorganization/" hreflang="en" title="Mozilla Foundation Reorganization">a fondé</a> une<strong> filiale à 100 %, la <i lang="en">Mozilla Corporation</i></strong>. Couramment abrégée en MoCo, l’entreprise est une <strong>filiale soumise à l’impôt</strong>, servant les mêmes objectifs sans but lucratif et d’intérêt public que l’organisation mère, la fondation Mozilla. La <i lang="en">Mozilla Corporation</i> est depuis lors responsable du développement, du marketing et de la distribution des produits Mozilla.</p>

<p>À cette époque, les contrats de partage des revenus issus des recherches dans Firefox rapportaient de plus en plus d’argent à mesure que les parts de marché de Firefox augmentaient. En créant une division commerciale, les activités générant des revenus de la nouvelle entité peuvent fournir des fonds pour soutenir le développement, les tests et la production de divers technologies <i lang="en">open source</i> issues du projet Mozilla. La gestion des activités génératrices de revenus associées avec ces produits permet aussi à <strong>la fondation de rester une organisation exonérée d’impôts</strong>. MoCo n’est pas une société commerciale comme les autres. Elle ne distribue pas de dividendes à divers actionnaires, ni ne propose de <i lang="en">stock-options</i> ou d’intéressement à ses employés.</p>

<p>Le rôle principal de la fondation est de superviser, diriger et promouvoir le projet <i lang="en">open source</i> Mozilla. La fondation n’est pas chargée du développement du code de Mozilla, mais laisse cette responsabilité à d’autres organisations et à des individus participant au projet Mozilla dont <i lang="en">Mozilla Corporation</i>. Firefox est développé, distribué et promu par des employés de la MoCo avec les bénévoles participant au projet dans ces domaines.</p>    <p>La <a href="https://www.mozilla.org/fr/foundation/" hreflang="fr" title="La Mozilla Foundation"><i lang="en">Mozilla Foundation</i></a> a pour but de promouvoir l’ouverture, l’innovation et la participation sur l’internet. Elle promeut les valeurs de <a href="https://www.mozilla.org/fr/mission/" hreflang="fr" title="Nous œuvrons à améliorer Internet – Mozilla">l’internet ouvert</a> pour le monde entier. MoFo fait progresser sa mission grâce à d’autres projets logiciels que <a href="https://www.mozilla.org/fr/firefox/" hreflang="fr" title="Plus vif et plus sûr, le meilleur navigateur d’aujourd’hui – Firefox">les Firefox</a> et par <a href="https://www.mozilla.org/en-US/grants/" hreflang="en" title="Grants – Mozilla">des subventions</a> à des organisations dans les milieux de l’éducation et de la création web, des technologies <i lang="en">open source</i>, de la souveraineté des utilisateurs, et de la culture libre et communautaire, ainsi que par des engagements et des efforts éducatifs tels que <a href="https://learning.mozilla.org/" hreflang="en" title="Mozilla Learning"><i lang="en">Learning</i></a> dans l’éducation ou <a href="http://openbadges.org/" hreflang="en"><i lang="en">Open Badges</i></a>. La fondation reçoit et collecte <a href="https://donate.mozilla.org/fr/" hreflang="fr" title="donate.mozilla.org – Faites un don à Mozilla">des dons</a> pour ses propres activités.</p>


<p>Partie de 36 employés en 2005, <a href="https://www.mozilla.org/en-US/foundation/moco/" hreflang="fr" title="About the Mozilla Corporation"><i lang="en">Mozilla Corporation</i></a> <strong>emploie 1 200 personnes</strong> actuellement, alors que la fondation Mozilla n’a toujours qu’une poignée d’employés (3 en 2005).</p>


<p><strong>La gouvernance chez Mozilla, établie par la fondation, est complexe.</strong> En plus de répondre à leur hiérarchie chez MoCo ou MoFo des employés peuvent, aux côtés de bénévoles ou d’employés d’autres entreprises parties prenantes, faire partie de <a href="https://www.mozilla.org/en-US/about/governance/roles/" hreflang="en" title="Roles and Leadership – Mozilla">l’organisation de mozilla.org</a> : <i lang="en">staff</i>, <i lang="en">drivers</i>, <i lang="en">modules owners</i>, etc. La page <a href="https://www.mozilla.org/en-US/about/leadership/" hreflang="en" title="Mozilla Leadership – Mozilla">leadership</a> de Mozilla comporte les équipes de direction avec pour la MoCo <strong>Mitchell Baker</strong> (dirigeante historique du projet) comme présidente exécutive et <strong>Chris Beard</strong> comme CEO (directeur général) et pour la MoFo <strong>Mark Surman</strong> président et directeur exécutif. Avant les conseils d’administration des deux Mo, la page liste le conseil des <i lang="en">Reps</i> de Mozilla qui est composé de Mozilliens volontaires qui font office de représentants officiels de Mozilla dans leur région ou pour leur communauté locale. Le conseil fournit une vision générale pour le programme <a href="https://blog.mozfr.org/post/2017/06/mozilla-reps-le-mois-mots-zilla" hreflang="fr" title="Mozilla Reps – le mois Mots-zilla (23 juin 2017) Communauté Mozilla francophone"><i lang="en">Mozilla Reps</i></a> et supervise les opérations quotidiennes au niveau mondial.</p>


<p>L’équipe de cadres seniors de MoCo appelée <a href="https://www.mozilla.org/en-US/foundation/mocosc/" hreflang="en" title="About the Mozilla Corporation Steering Committee"><i lang="en">Steering Committee</i></a> (comité de pilotage) est responsable du leadership, de la coordination des divers groupes travaillant ensemble pour produire les produits Mozilla. Le comité se tient au courant des conditions du marché, trace le chemin de Mozilla dans cet environnement et fixe la direction général des offres des produits de consommation de Mozilla. Le comité effectue aussi des tâches comme les embauches, la planification et l’allocation des ressources. Il le fait d’une manière qui s’aligne avec l’identité de Mozilla en tant qu’organisation à but non lucratif, <i lang="en">open source</i> et basée sur la communauté. Le comité cherche à absorber, distiller et refléter les valeurs de la communauté Mozilla dans l’exercice de ses responsabilités.</p>


<p style="margin-left: 1em; padding-left: 0.5em;">(Re)lire : <a href="https://blog.mozfr.org/post/2017/06/MoFo-mois-Mots-zilla" hreflang="fr" title="MoFo – le mois Mots-zilla (2 juin 2017) Communauté Mozilla francophone">MoFo – le mois Mots-zilla</a></p>

<address><br />
<a href="https://twitter.com/Mozinet" hreflang="fr" title="Mozinet (@Mozinet) sur Twitter">Mozinet</a>
</address>

<p><em>Lien vers le précédent coup d’œil dans le rétro :</em> <a href="https://blog.mozfr.org/post/2017/07/Creation-Mozilla-Foundation-15-juillet-2003" hreflang="fr" title="Création de la Mozilla Foundation – 15 juillet 2003 – Coup d'œil dans le rétro (15 juil. 2017) Communauté Mozilla francophone">Création de la <i lang="en">Mozilla Foundation</i> – 15 juillet 2003</a></p>
<p>Article issu d’une <a href="https://firefoxos.mozfr.org/post/2015/08/MoCo-a-10-ans-%E2%80%93-Coup-d-oeil-dans-le-retro" hreflang="fr" title="MoCo a 10 ans – Coup d'œil dans le rétro - FxOS">première version</a> publiée pour feu Firefox OS.</p>]]>
  </description>
  <pubDate>Fri, 04 Aug 2017 15:01:04 +0000</pubDate>
  
</item>

<item>
  <title>Viswaprasath KS - Weeks of Contribution- WebExtension Session3</title>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://iamVP7.in//MozWOC-Session3/</guid>
  <link>http://iamVP7.in//MozWOC-Session3/</link>
  <description>
    <![CDATA[<p><strong>Date</strong> : 28th July 2017</p>]]>
  </description>
  <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jul 2017 23:34:00 +0000</pubDate>
  
</item>

<item>
  <title>Viswaprasath KS - Weeks of Contribution- WebExtension Session1</title>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://iamVP7.in//MozWOC-Session1/</guid>
  <link>http://iamVP7.in//MozWOC-Session1/</link>
  <description>
    <![CDATA[<p><strong>Date</strong> : 24th July 2017</p>]]>
  </description>
  <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jul 2017 23:34:00 +0000</pubDate>
  
</item>

<item>
  <title>Official Reps Blog - Rep of the Month – July 2017</title>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.mozilla.org/mozillareps/?p=508</guid>
  <link>https://blog.mozilla.org/mozillareps/2017/07/28/rep-of-the-month-july-2017/</link>
  <description>
    <![CDATA[<div class="cooked">
<p>Please join us in congratulating <a href="https://reps.mozilla.org/u/dvigneshwer/" rel="nofollow noopener">Vigneshwer Dhinakaran</a>, our Rep of the Month for July 2017!</p>
<p>Vigneshwer is a data scientist working on realtime data and a tech enthusiast coming from India.</p>
<p><a href="https://scontent.fath3-2.fna.fbcdn.net/v/t31.0-8/16179241_1830873240462561_4074884736782256847_o.jpg?oh=3b7236a2a732a381422afc70b1bb1ed1&amp;oe=59F6B539" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"> <img height="460" src="https://scontent.fath3-2.fna.fbcdn.net/v/t31.0-8/16179241_1830873240462561_4074884736782256847_o.jpg?oh=3b7236a2a732a381422afc70b1bb1ed1&amp;oe=59F6B539" width="690" /> </a>During the last months, Vigneshwer (or Viki as most of his friends call him) has been heavily involved on helping building the Rust community in India. His efforts, along with other awesome Reps, have resulted to the <a href="https://discourse.mozilla-community.org/t/rain-of-rust-campaign-live/16020">RainofRust Campaign</a>, a campaign with the purpose to spread the Rust language in India and to create early adapters of the language. During the campaign Viki wrote a <a href="https://github.com/MozillaIndia/RustIndia/tree/master/RainOfRust#rust-kits" rel="nofollow noopener">new event flow</a> while he was leading a lot of the offline and online events. But his work doesn’t stop there. Since the campaign has finished, Viki is leading the efforts to help those early adopters to become Rust contributors in order to strengthen the community in India. Moreover, Viki has participated in the <a href="https://blog.mozilla.org/mozillareps/2017/07/10/reps-mobilizer-experiment/" rel="nofollow noopener">mobilizers experiment</a> where he was leading the efforts on understanding how to mobilize the Rust community and unlock the <a href="https://discourse.mozilla-community.org/t/results-of-the-mobilizer-experiment-for-rust-india/16558">challenges they are facing</a>.</p>
<p>Thank you Vigneshwer for being awesome, keep rocking the open Web! <img alt=":tada:" class="emoji" src="https://cdn-production.discourse.mozilla-community.org/images/emoji/twitter/tada.png?v=5" title=":tada:" /> <img alt=":tada:" class="emoji" src="https://cdn-production.discourse.mozilla-community.org/images/emoji/twitter/tada.png?v=5" title=":tada:" /></p>
<p><a href="https://discourse.mozilla-community.org/t/rep-of-the-month-july-2017/17474"><span class="author-a-rc6pvwz72ze8z90znkxz89z3t">Join us in congratulating him on Discourse.</span></a></p>
</div>]]>
  </description>
  <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jul 2017 11:12:34 +0000</pubDate>
  
</item>

<item>
  <title>Official Reps Blog - Council at the All Hands in San Francisco</title>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.mozilla.org/mozillareps/?p=506</guid>
  <link>https://blog.mozilla.org/mozillareps/2017/07/25/council-at-the-all-hands-in-san-francisco/</link>
  <description>
    <![CDATA[<p>The All Hands is a special time of the year where Mozilla employees along with core volunteers gather for a week of many meetings and brainstorming. The <a href="https://wiki.mozilla.org/All_Hands/SanFrancisco">All Hands Wiki page</a> has more information about the general setting. During the All Hands, the Reps Council participated in the Open Innovation meetings as well as had meetings about what we’ve accomplished in Q2 and the future of the program. One of our main topics was on how to get new developers involved as contributors in Mozilla projects.</p>
<h3>Top topics</h3>
<p>For that reason it was crucial to understand and discuss the <a href="https://blog.mozilla.org/mozillareps/2017/07/10/reps-mobilizer-experiment/">mobilizers experiment</a> and their outcomes with Srushtika, Daniele and Vigneshwer, in order to understand what are the issues and needs for Add-ons, Rust and WebVR and how we can create communities around those projects and attract new developers.</p>
<p>The idea “Open by Design” was discussed extensively while we’ve tried to understand how Reps program can contribute to the Strategy project. We also had a meeting with Patrick Finch to discuss a few strategy questions and to start the discussion on how the Reps program can help in the next few months.</p>
<p><img src="https://discourse-paas-production-content.s3.amazonaws.com/original/2X/b/b11e8507a66ac4e684279e744cddd7d2b20a34e8.jpg" /></p>
<h3>Other meetings and sessions</h3>
<p>We had other sessions as well. Also we did a lot of administrative tasks as well:</p>
<ul>
<li>Participated in the Q&amp;A Session with Chris Beard</li>
<li>Gave feedback on the <a href="https://blog.lizardwrangler.com/2017/03/13/the-worldview-of-mozilla/">World View project</a></li>
<li>We reviewed our <a href="https://blog.mozilla.org/mozillareps/2017/04/20/reps-program-objectives-q2-2017/">Q2 OKRs</a> and opened <a href="https://github.com/mozilla/reps/issues">issues</a> where necessary to continue in Q3</li>
<li>Updated the Wiki header of Reps pages with a link to the <a href="http://wiki.mozilla.org/ReMo/Leadership">Leadership page</a></li>
<li>Moved the Council Chair from Konstantina to Flore</li>
<li>Started to document new criteria for Reps applications</li>
<li>Further documented the mobilizers initiative and discussed common topics that were raised around those</li>
<li>Had a meeting with Module Owner and Peers</li>
</ul>
<p><img src="https://discourse-paas-production-content.s3.amazonaws.com/original/2X/0/0947e32116b9f301f74f59a3a6dd6662727639a6.jpg" /></p>
<h3>MozActivate</h3>
<p><a href="http://activate.mozilla.community/">Activate</a> holds a special place at Reps activities. During the All Hands we held meetings about the website, the content of the activities and the future of the project. From the Council side Alex Lakatos with Michael Kohler are involved in the website building, while Konstantina Papadea and Ankit Gadgil are working with a focus on the content.</p>
<p>While in San Francisco we <a href="https://activate.mozilla.community/nightly/">launched a new activity about Nightly</a> which now is available on the website. Firefox Nightly is one of the most important projects happening right now in the Mozilla world and it’s crucial for us. We need to get new Firefox Nightly users.</p>
<p>We also joined discussions with the Rust and the Add-ons teams in order to better understand how the Reps Program can help to build their community or improve the promotion of those technologies.</p>
<p>On the feedback form front we are working on the dashboard to simplify the access to feedback of Activate events.</p>]]>
  </description>
  <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jul 2017 11:05:52 +0000</pubDate>
  
</item>

<item>
  <title>Michael Kohler - WebVR/A-Frame Hackathon in Lausanne</title>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://michaelkohler.info/?p=430</guid>
  <link>https://michaelkohler.info/2017/webvr-aframe-hackathon-in-lausanne</link>
  <description>
    <![CDATA[<p>Last Saturday the <a href="http://mozilla.ch/">Mozilla Switzerland community</a>, together with <a href="https://www.liip.ch/en">Liip</a>, has organized a <a href="https://reps.mozilla.org/e/webvr-a-frame-hackathon/">WebVR/A-Frame Hackathon</a> in Lausanne, Switzerland. As always (also in Zurich), we turned to Liip for support regarding a venue, and as always they were happy to host us in Lausanne. At this point, a big “thank you” to them! Without their support we couldn’t organize events as easy as we can now.</p>
<p><a href="http://aframe.io/">A-Frame</a> is a framework for WebVR, making it easy to create scenes and components that can be viewed in the browser, with Cardboard, the HTC Vive and other VR devices. A-Frame even includes an Inspector that makes it easy to develop VR applications in the browser without having to test it constantly on a real VR device.</p>
<p><a href="http://michaelkohler.info/wp-content/uploads/2017/07/L0086.jpg"><img alt="" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-431" height="900" src="http://michaelkohler.info/wp-content/uploads/2017/07/L0086.jpg" width="1200" /></a></p>
<h3>About the event</h3>
<p>We gathered at 10 o’clock to have some initial talks and a light breakfast. It also took some time to set up the Vive and making sure we can demo <a href="https://aframe.io/a-painter">A-Painter</a> and other VR applications. At around 10:30 we started with a quick intro by Geoffroy and me. We <a href="https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1udTkTO9qn76qwNlW3g5IhOCFpS_2eqv8RGfQOUdOaKk">explained the agenda and some general information about Mozilla</a>. After that, Ben gave an <a href="https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1UzDvBJno6CR-fsuVQzXvBS1RnvHY9Xe8NRYl-yVFWwg/edit#slide=id.g24a51ed3a8_0_16">intro to WebVR</a> and how they are using A-Frame at <a href="https://spaces.archilogic.com/explore">Archilogic</a>. It’s amazing to see how it is being used in the wild for really amazing and helpful projects! Thank you for your time to come to Lausanne and present to us!</p>
<p><a href="https://twitter.com/MozillaCH/status/888679520970186752"><img alt="" class="aligncenter wp-image-432 size-full" height="1152" src="http://michaelkohler.info/wp-content/uploads/2017/07/DFU5S_nWAAAbxFi.jpg_large.jpg" width="2048" /></a></p>
<p>Then we did some demos with our gadgets and started hacking. With the help of Ben it was easy to create our own first projects. What struck me most is that my creativity and design skills came to end quite quickly, but nevertheless I could easily create a good Proof of Concept for a future iteration (through skilled people and Pull Requests). :)</p>
<p><a href="http://michaelkohler.info/wp-content/uploads/2017/07/DFa5E_2XYAAtCwi.jpg_large.jpg"><img alt="" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-433" height="1152" src="http://michaelkohler.info/wp-content/uploads/2017/07/DFa5E_2XYAAtCwi.jpg_large.jpg" width="2048" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://michaelkohler.info/wp-content/uploads/2017/07/L0065.jpg"><img alt="" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-435" height="807" src="http://michaelkohler.info/wp-content/uploads/2017/07/L0065.jpg" width="1200" /></a></p>
<p>Here are some projects that were created/started during this hackathon (click on the images to see it live in your browser):</p>
<p><a href="https://grrd01.github.io/AFrame/"><img alt="" class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-439" height="214" src="http://michaelkohler.info/wp-content/uploads/2017/07/Screen-Shot-2017-07-24-at-22.47.46-300x214.png" width="300" /></a></p>
<p><a href="https://gperriard.github.io/a-frame-object-import/"><img alt="" class="aligncenter wp-image-437 size-medium" height="219" src="http://michaelkohler.info/wp-content/uploads/2017/07/Screen-Shot-2017-07-24-at-22.46.08-300x219.png" width="300" /></a></p>
<p><a href="https://michaelkohler.github.io/webvr-reps/"><img alt="" class="aligncenter wp-image-438 size-medium" height="244" src="http://michaelkohler.info/wp-content/uploads/2017/07/Screen-Shot-2017-07-24-at-22.46.00-300x244.png" width="300" /></a></p>
<h3>Another thank you – our preparation hero</h3>
<p>A big “thank you” goes to <a href="https://twitter.com/gperriard">Geoffroy</a>, who has helped us out with the whole coordination with the venue and did an amazing job promoting the event to his network. We are so happy to have people like Geoffroy who are helping us keep the Open Web public and accessible to all!</p>
<p>Honestly, the only thing I did was the administration parts of creating event pages on the Reps portal and Meetup, coordinate for having a speaker and giving a short intro talk about the agenda (with his help). Everything about the venue, food, gadgets was organized by him. He even went as far as traveling to Zurich to get an HTC Vive so we can show case that as well!</p>
<p><a href="http://michaelkohler.info/wp-content/uploads/2017/07/L0294.jpg"><img alt="" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-434" height="807" src="http://michaelkohler.info/wp-content/uploads/2017/07/L0294.jpg" width="1200" /></a></p>
<h3>Conclusion</h3>
<p>We had a lot of fun, and we hope our attendees did too! The verbal feedback was good, however we couldn’t get a lot of responses through the feedback form, even though I reminded all participants after the event through email to please fill out the feedback form. Additionally we need to do better in terms of diversity!</p>
<p>All photos are used with permission by Liip or their respective owners if linked to a tweet.</p>
<img alt="" height="0" src="http://piwik.michaelkohler.info/piwik.php?idsite=n/a&amp;rec=1&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fmichaelkohler.info%2F2017%2Fwebvr-aframe-hackathon-in-lausanne&amp;action_name=WebVR%2FA-Frame+Hackathon+in+Lausanne&amp;urlref=https%3A%2F%2Fmichaelkohler.info%2Ffeed" style="border: 0; width: 0; height: 0;" width="0" />]]>
  </description>
  <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jul 2017 20:49:55 +0000</pubDate>
  
</item>

<item>
  <title>Mehul Patel - Rain Of Rust – How we did it?</title>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.rowdymehul.com/?p=1343</guid>
  <link>http://www.rowdymehul.com/rain-of-rust-how-we-did-it/</link>
  <description>
    <![CDATA[<p><a href="https://i2.wp.com/www.rowdymehul.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/07/RainOfRust_Color.png"><img alt="" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1354" src="https://i2.wp.com/www.rowdymehul.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/07/RainOfRust_Color.png?resize=720%2C215" /></a></p>
<p>Growing up I was a tech geek, always kept myself updated with the latest ongoing in the language world. It always excited me to explore the tiny bits of these platforms and constantly kept myself updated with brushing my knowledge.</p>
<p>About 9 months ago I met <strong>Manish Goregaokar</strong>, who works in Mozilla as a Rust/Servo Contributor met me at Mozilla India meetup which was organized by Mozilla India team and I was one of the core team member organizing that event. He introduced me this programming language and gradually I became very fond of it, finding it very interesting and exciting to explore this language.</p>
<p>Eventually after spending some time, analyzing and exploring this programme, I discovered that masses including students, startups, developers are not completely aware, very few users actually being aware about Rust. Even after spending a quality time on this programming language, I still feel I have a whole new world to be discovered up in front of me. Simultaneously I thought it would be wise to educate users regarding Rust language. I seeked help from my mentors,friends and staff from Mozilla in setting up a campaign to spread awareness about Rust. This is how we came up with Rain Of Rust campaigns.</p>
<p><strong>About Rain Of Rust :</strong></p>
<p>Rain of Rust Campaign, a month-long global campaign in which would be specifically focused on the Rust language. It has taken place in June 2017 in collaboration with the Rust community.</p>
<p><strong>Key stats of RainOfRust campaign June 2017:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>19 offline events across 10 regions globally. Ref</li>
<li>4 online meeting which is recorded in Air Mozilla. Ref</li>
<li>As part of the campaign the RainOfRust has Rust teaching kits which currently has 3 application-oriented activities</li>
<li>The Github repo has received more than 500+ views in the within 1 month, <a href="https://discourse.mozilla-community.org/t/rain-of-rust-campaign-live/16020">Read more</a></li>
</ul>
<p><span id="more-1343"></span></p>
<p>I contributed in Rust community by travelling across 8 cities in India through spreading awareness, educating and promoting Rust  amongst students, developers, entrepreneurs &amp; young aspirants.</p>
<p><em>Here are few glimpses of Rain Of Rust,</em></p>
<div class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 1035px;"><img class="size-medium" height="537" src="http://blog.mozillagujarat.org/wp-content/uploads/2017/06/index.jpe" width="1025" /><p class="wp-caption-text"><em><strong>                Rain Of Rust at Vadodara</strong></em></p></div>
<div class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 1290px;"><img class="size-medium" src="https://i0.wp.com/2.bp.blogspot.com/-hb4sYBZamW0/WWUhL3Df0MI/AAAAAAAADQI/OXx4C5RSW2QQEtZdxbtT8NnLT-QGag7fwCLcBGAs/s1600/IMG_20170629_235101.jpg?resize=720%2C540&amp;ssl=1" /><p class="wp-caption-text"><em><strong>         Rain Of Rust at Patan</strong></em></p></div>
<p><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/BVeVzTGgb06/?taken-by=mozillagram" target="_blank" title="View on Instagram"><img alt="Instagram Photo" src="http://instagr.am/p/BVeVzTGgb06/media/?size=l" /></a></p>
<p> </p>
<div class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 544px;"><img class="size-medium" src="https://i1.wp.com/blog.mozillagujarat.org/wp-content/uploads/2017/07/moz6.jpg?resize=544%2C835" /><p class="wp-caption-text"><em><strong>I was interviewed by the reporters who were dedicated to the newspaper called “<a href="http://epaper.divyabhaskar.co.in/detail/-680365/61505323854/0/map/tabs-1/2017-06-15/64/2/image/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Divya Bhaskar</a>“.</strong></em></p></div>
<h5><em><strong>Meet our <span>sensational</span> trio </strong></em></h5>
<p><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/BVe9RYfgNgB/?taken-by=mozillagram" target="_blank" title="View on Instagram"><img alt="Instagram Photo" src="http://instagr.am/p/BVe9RYfgNgB/media/?size=l" /></a></p>
<p>Here are detailed results of campaign statistics : <a href="https://goo.gl/V4mdgk">https://goo.gl/V4mdgk</a></p>
<blockquote>
<h4><em>Still confused about switching to rust? Check this out… <a href="http://www.rowdymehul.com/why-should-i-use-rust/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Why should I use Rust?</a></em></h4>
</blockquote>
<h3 class="gh-header-title"><em><strong>What next?</strong> </em><span class="js-issue-title"><br />
</span></h3>
<ol>
<li>More collaboration with the Rust team to build better nodes</li>
<li>Mentor-ship sessions to support mobilizers across different countries or regions.</li>
<li>Create better communication channel so we don’t miss the numbers</li>
<li>Needs to share and create more teaching kits, video tutorials</li>
<li>Designing Rust curriculum activities for university students, Like C,C++,Python, etc</li>
<li>Encouraging more womoz participation</li>
<li>Target startups to adopt Rust in production; how? That’s where we need to work on!</li>
<li>Bring more awesome people to be part of the Rust mobilizers to team</li>
<li>Setting up Rust Regional Communities across global</li>
</ol>
<p>I would like to applaud the hardwork and determination put in by Rain Of Rust team (<strong><a href="https://reps.mozilla.org/u/couci/">Konstantina</a>, <a href="https://reps.mozilla.org/u/kelimuttu/">Kelimutu</a>, <a href="https://reps.mozilla.org/u/umesh/">Umesh Agrawal</a>, <a href="https://reps.mozilla.org/u/prathamesh/">Prathamesh Chavan</a> &amp; <a href="https://reps.mozilla.org/u/dvigneshwer/">Vigneshwar</a></strong>).</p>
<h4>Hope you enjoyed my blog. <b><em>Don’t Forget To Share It With Your All Tech Friends..!! <img alt="🙂" class="wp-smiley" src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/2.3/72x72/1f642.png" style="height: 1em;" /></em></b></h4>
<p> </p>]]>
  </description>
  <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jul 2017 10:35:00 +0000</pubDate>
  
</item>

<item>
  <title>Mehul Patel - Why should I use Rust?</title>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.rowdymehul.com/?p=1334</guid>
  <link>http://www.rowdymehul.com/why-should-i-use-rust/</link>
  <description>
    <![CDATA[<p>With respect to subject of my blog, this might be the questions of all who heard about this programming language or who have attended any rust session/workshops very first time. Recently when I was traveling to some cities in India for Rust campaign called <a href="https://blog.mozillaindia.org/1932" rel="noopener" target="_blank">RainOfRust</a>, that time one 2nd year engineering student who attended one of my session asked me this question, “<strong><em>Why should I use Rust?</em></strong>” when my session got over.</p>
<p>Well, this was the best questions so far anyone asked me during this campaign and I loved to shared how I answered that.</p>
<p>You might thought that I have started my conversation with this general definition that,</p>
<p><a href="https://www.rust-lang.org/en-US/" rel="noopener" target="_blank"><b>Rust</b> </a>is a systems programming language that runs blazingly fast, prevents segfaults, and guarantees thread safety.</p>
<p>This the common definition which everybody knows. I always believe that you should share your things the way you understand or the you adopt it. This way your thoughts spread better among all who listened to you.</p>
<blockquote><p>Rust is a good choice when you’d choose C++. You can also say, “Rust is a systems programming language that pursuing the trifecta: safe, concurrent, and fast.” I would say, Rust is an ownership-oriented programming language.</p></blockquote>
<p>Here is my definition and from here I started to explained him, after sometime some more students joined the conversation and it became more interesting.</p>
<p>Firstly, the reason that I’ve looked into Rust at first.</p>
<ul>
<li>Rust is new enough that you can write useful stuff that would have already existed in other languages</li>
<li>It gives a relatively familiar tool to the modern C++ developers, but in the much more consistent and reliable ways.</li>
<li>It is low-level enough that you take account of most resources.</li>
<li>Its more like C++ and Go, less like Node and Ruby</li>
<li>cargo is awesome. Managing crates just works as intended, which makes a whole lot of troubles you may have in other languages just vanish with a satisfying <em>poof</em>.</li>
</ul>
<p><span id="more-1334"></span></p>
<p>Second, According to recent The Stack Overflow survey Rust is the most beloved among developers of all programming languages and frameworks.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><a class="https://insights.stackoverflow.com/survey/2016#technology-most-loved-dreaded-and-wanted" href="https://i2.wp.com/www.rowdymehul.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/07/Rust-Popularity.jpg" rel="https://insights.stackoverflow.com/survey/2016#technology-most-loved-dreaded-and-wanted noopener" target="_blank"><img alt="" class="alignnone wp-image-1336 size-full" src="https://i2.wp.com/www.rowdymehul.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/07/Rust-Popularity.jpg?resize=720%2C516" /></a>Credits : <a href="https://insights.stackoverflow.com/survey/2016#technology-most-loved-dreaded-and-wanted" rel="noopener" target="_blank"><em>https://insights.stackoverflow.com</em></a></p>
<p>Last, explained them that how we working in community and get a chance to learn and work with some expert community leaders. <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=duv0tuPAnO0" rel="noopener" target="_blank"><em><strong>Growing the Rust Community</strong></em></a> is one of the focused goal of Rust team and this is the reason we have taken the initiative to run <a href="https://discourse.mozilla-community.org/t/rain-of-rust-campaign-live/16020" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Rust campaign</a> and Thanks <a href="https://twitter.com/Carols10cents" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Carol Nichols</a> from Rust team who helped all her best during this campaign. Here, I would like all of you to see her recent interview at <a href="https://channel9.msdn.com/Events/Seth-on-the-Road/Codemash-2017" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Codemash 2017</a> where she shared some of the awesome things about Rust.</p>
<p></p>
<p style="text-align: center;">Video Credits : <em><a href="https://channel9.msdn.com/Events/Seth-on-the-Road/Codemash-2017/Why-Rust-is-Awesome-with-Carol-Nichols" rel="noopener" target="_blank">https://channel9.msdn.com</a></em></p>
<p>Rust will be the language of the future. I bet on it. And I hope now you may convinced that why you should use <a href="https://www.rust-lang.org/en-US/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">Rust</a>! If so, then what you are you waiting for, Its time to get Rusty!</p>
<h4>Hope you enjoyed my blog. <b><em>Don’t Forget To Share It With Your All Tech Friends..!! <img alt="🙂" class="wp-smiley" src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/2.3/72x72/1f642.png" style="height: 1em;" /></em></b></h4>]]>
  </description>
  <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jul 2017 21:03:12 +0000</pubDate>
  
</item>

<item>
  <title>Official Reps Blog - Reps Mobilizer Experiment</title>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.mozilla.org/mozillareps/?p=503</guid>
  <link>https://blog.mozilla.org/mozillareps/2017/07/10/reps-mobilizer-experiment/</link>
  <description>
    <![CDATA[<p>During the second quarter of 2017, and in order to understand how to better identify, recruit and support <a href="http://blog.mozilla.org/mozillareps/2017/02/13/reps-as-mobilizers-in-the-mozilla-community/">mobilizers</a>, we decided to run a small experiment with a reduced set of existing “best in class” mobilizers and walk with them during their work supporting technical communities.</p>
<h3>Why</h3>
<p>Reps program is a program for core mobilizers, who create, grow, sustain and engage communities around Mozilla projects. There are still improvement areas in order to become  a state of the art mobilizer program, so we wanted to identify which are these areas and which are the changes we can implement.</p>
<h2>Participants</h2>
<p><img alt="" class="alignleft" height="158" src="https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/tbrBE3v7f3pwAd9A6TUzAKycbO7rPhrDZtNMxY9WEkrC8ad0j5CJADd28kvQBNz0C03CseQ7q39BiicRUBBTBHeipuKmcAF951iyWFX-Ps3Do5G6zCRYAQoVpTYyZjgq6-f9s_D6" title="" width="132" /></p>
<p><a href="https://mozillians.org/u/bobchao/"><b>Bob Chao</b></a><b> (Taiwan) – WebVR</b></p>
<p>Long time contributors, Bob has been empowering and growing different Mozilla related communities in Taiwan, more recently Rust and WebVR.</p>
<p><a href="https://discourse.mozilla-community.org/t/results-of-the-mobilizer-experiment-for-webvr-taiwan/16643">Full Report</a></p>
<p> </p>
<p><img alt="" class="alignleft" height="163" src="https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/tHoZUQNLn65YDWMpHIOokieA-l7DPmKQ9qsRb6Q3kYoo8YWtNFq8PMOWaVXXshi_9WKkll64Ed5SCY-44-JeiRqX78H40CXqi5O-EEGMqP9QrUjs4JVtx61aqlk3YNYJRQYHDDsS" title="" width="132" /></p>
<p><a href="https://mozillians.org/u/n.srushtika/"><b>Srushtika Neelakantam</b></a><b> (India) – WebVR</b></p>
<p>Deeply involved with the WebVR community since its formation, Srushtika has been empowering the local community in India for a few years now. She has even wrote a book about WebVR.</p>
<p><a href="https://discourse.mozilla-community.org/t/results-of-the-mobilizer-experiment-for-webvr-india/16491/">Full Report</a></p>
<p> </p>
<p><img alt="" class="alignleft" height="131" src="https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/6wuF66Hs-Jg1x2kP9esgH4zg-5PuqwbO6dFFYG7p6dhIW60OZtFgZusX1pXAiwL8PO82r2vNuNYZcyAwtYgsTS6oJImwwTSifKtwpPlTJWo0tdPPY-_Gvn04Afa_gKt1ISuSvX3r" title="" width="132" /></p>
<p><a href="https://mozillians.org/u/mte90/"><b>Daniele Scasciafratte</b></a><b> (Italy) – WebExtensions</b></p>
<p>Extremely involved contributors, Daniele has been supporting the community in Italy for many years. He has been key to develop the first Addons activity for the MozActivate campaign.</p>
<p><a href="https://discourse.mozilla-community.org/t/results-of-the-mobilizer-experiment-for-webextension-italy/16494/">Full Report</a></p>
<p><img alt="" class="alignleft" height="123" src="https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/nn7GQ_fpDBaTv7K734IdD44YDovRHQ_RA9fH73vomsokGeG5EcksT-QB0PoyGpiYs6AkSkYLcarYJqpPtxPQp8isVAx60hjSopcnmqac4-XwuttdOzNJLnAtAZqj5MCRmoTeoUUD" title="" width="135" /></p>
<p><a href="https://mozillians.org/u/dvigneshwer/"><b>Vigneshwer Dhinakaran</b></a><b> (India) – Rust</b></p>
<p>He has been key for the formation and growth of the Rust community in India, he is author of a book about the technology.</p>
<p><a href="https://discourse.mozilla-community.org/t/results-of-the-mobilizer-experiment-for-rust-india/16558/">Full Report</a></p>
<p> </p>
<h2>Process Overview</h2>
<p>We decided to use a human centered design approach to test this hypothesis. Each project started with a research phase followed by multiple iterations of potential solutions. Each iteration involved testing, reflecting on the learnings and iterating on the approach.</p>
<h3><a href="http://blog.mozilla.org/mozillareps/files/2017/07/Mobilizer-experiment-Workflow.png"><img alt="" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-504" height="450" src="http://blog.mozilla.org/mozillareps/files/2017/07/Mobilizer-experiment-Workflow-600x450.png" width="600" /></a>Overall main learnings</h3>
<ol>
<li>A certain degree of understanding of the technology is needed for the mobilizer to be truly effective and understand the communities.</li>
<li>It’s key to devote enough time to do research and understand the local environment and the potential contributors needs
<ol>
<li>After a solid research, we can start thinking on which are and implement the best channels for communications between the community (sync and async) as well as information distribution (announces, materials…)</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>There are two important areas when working with technical communities:
<ol>
<li>Getting people excited about the tech and the community</li>
<li>Keeping people engaged after the main activities take place. The top priority should be designing for the follow-up instead of the activity.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>Establishing a direct conversation between mobilizers and the functional area staff is key for having a correct direction and impactful outputs.
<ol>
<li>Teams that work with more closed tools (slack) presented a bigger challenge</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ol>
<p>As a result of these learnings we will evaluate a set of recommendations to improve the Reps program and we will share with some early ideas soon on the <a href="https://discourse.mozilla-community.org/c/reps">Reps discourse</a>.</p>
<p><strong>Thank you Vigneshwer, Daniele, Srushtika and Bob</strong>, your work is an inspiration to all Reps and to the rest of Mozilla, you have demostrated strong leadership and an impact-oriented strategy thinking that will help others to follow your steps.</p>]]>
  </description>
  <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2017 13:25:18 +0000</pubDate>
  
</item>

<item>
  <title>Viswaprasath KS - Weeks of Contribution-WebExtension</title>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://iamVP7.in//WebExtension-IRC-Learning/</guid>
  <link>http://iamVP7.in//WebExtension-IRC-Learning/</link>
  <description>
    <![CDATA[<p><a href="https://viswaprasathks.wordpress.com/2015/06/24/weeks-of-contribution/"><strong>Weeks of Contribution</strong></a> is one of the amazing series of online event where first time contributors get started  contributing to Mozilla Community. It was started in 2015 by set of contributors aiming to bring contributors around Tamilnadu in various areas of Mozilla contribution like Localization, Doocmentation, Firefox OS app development, Add-ons development for Firefox and so on.</p>]]>
  </description>
  <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jul 2017 23:34:00 +0000</pubDate>
  
</item>

<item>
  <title>Viswaprasath KS - Weeks of Contribution-WebExtension</title>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://iamVP7.in//PreSession-WOC-Extension-IRC-Learning/</guid>
  <link>http://iamVP7.in//PreSession-WOC-Extension-IRC-Learning/</link>
  <description>
    <![CDATA[<p><a href="https://viswaprasathks.wordpress.com/2015/06/24/weeks-of-contribution/"><strong>Weeks of Contribution</strong></a> is one of the amazing series of online event where first time contributors get started  contributing to Mozilla Community. It was started in 2015 by set of contributors aiming to bring contributors around Tamilnadu in various areas of Mozilla contribution like Localization, Doocmentation, Firefox OS app development, Add-ons development for Firefox and so on.</p>]]>
  </description>
  <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jul 2017 23:34:00 +0000</pubDate>
  
</item>

<item>
  <title>Md Shahbaz Alam - Let’s increase Firefox Market share</title>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alamshahbaz.wordpress.com/?p=852</guid>
  <link>https://alamshahbaz.wordpress.com/2017/07/02/lets-increase-firefox-market-share/</link>
  <description>
    <![CDATA[<div class="cooked">
<p>With the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Andreas_Gal" rel="nofollow noopener">Andreas Gal’s</a> latest <a href="https://andreasgal.com/2017/05/25/chrome-won/" rel="nofollow noopener">post</a> it is quite clear that we are losing our market share and same can be seen on Wikipedia’s <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Usage_share_of_web_browsers" rel="nofollow noopener">Usage Share Page</a>.</p>
<p>I am a Mozilla Rep. When I joined Mozilla 4 years back, I was literally knowing only three browsers <strong>Internet Explorer</strong>(thanks to Microsoft), <strong>Google Chrome</strong>(here due to Android) and <strong>Opera Mini</strong>(Only browser which uses less data then).<br />
But thanks to the community in Rajasthan which was so much active then, promoting Mozilla and it’s Mission. That was the first time when I get to know about Mozilla Firefox. Firefox is a product which is the core of Mozilla, this is what I believe and assume other volunteers,mozillians and Reps Share the same.</p>
<p>Today, Firefox is mainly used by Mozilla volunteers and few engineers that to are losing faith in it due to compatibility issue and other problems.To name a few, Hangout call is not supported by Firefox, which we use more often for our monthly meeting in India. So what we could do is, create a campaign just like Firefox Nightly and Rain of Rust to promote the use of Firefox, where we will introduce this browser to the students which are still unaware of the browser, which you may agree too.</p>
<p>We are a country with a population of over 1.311 billion where <a href="http://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/At-315-million-India-has-the-most-students-in-world/articleshow/37669667.cms" rel="nofollow noopener">315 million</a> are students, if we could target those and industry people. This will definitely increase our market share.</p>
<p>I agree that Firefox sometimes doesn’t behave well and we lack other support too which is available in other browsers. I also see a great opportunity for us to make this browser more advanced and easy to use.We want a browser which we love. During this campaign, we will be collecting lots of feedback and suggestions and how you want this browser for yourself. Then we will share these reports with Mozilla staff and help them to create a browser which people love.</p>
<p>I would love to know your feedback and suggestion regarding this campaign as well as any correction will be appreciatable.</p>
<p>Please follow this <a href="https://discourse.mozilla-community.org/t/lets-increase-firefox-market-share/16793" rel="noopener" target="_blank">topic</a> on discourse for more updates</p>
<p>Cheers,<br />
Shahbaz<br />
Mozilla Rep<br />
Mozilla Firefox User</p>
</div><br />  <a href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/alamshahbaz.wordpress.com/852/" rel="nofollow"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/alamshahbaz.wordpress.com/852/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" height="1" src="https://pixel.wp.com/b.gif?host=alamshahbaz.wordpress.com&amp;blog=73514675&amp;post=852&amp;subd=alamshahbaz&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" />]]>
  </description>
  <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jul 2017 06:40:47 +0000</pubDate>
  
</item>

<item>
  <title>Official Reps Blog - Rep of the Month – June 2017</title>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.mozilla.org/mozillareps/?p=501</guid>
  <link>https://blog.mozilla.org/mozillareps/2017/06/30/rep-of-the-month-june-2017/</link>
  <description>
    <![CDATA[<p>Please join us in congratulating <a href="https://reps.mozilla.org/u/rowdymehul/">Mehul Patel</a>, our Rep of the Month for June 2017!</p>
<p>Mehul is an highly motivated Rep from India supporting and enabling many Mozillians in the region of Pune, Nashik and Gujrat.</p>
<p><img height="500" src="https://discourse-paas-production-content.s3.amazonaws.com/original/2X/9/984b072dd022e5aa6c759b5dfcf12f49b48ccb0e.jpg" width="498" /></p>
<div class="im_message_outer_wrap hasselect">
<div class="im_message_wrap clearfix">
<div class="im_content_message_wrap im_message_in">
<div class="im_message_body">
<div>
<div class="im_message_text" dir="auto">He is also a campus club advisory board member helping shaping the new activities for students. His recent activities include conducting the first phase of the <a href="https://blog.mozillaindia.org/1932">Rain of Rust campaign</a> which mobilized Mozillians around Rust across various parts of India.</div>
<div class="im_message_text" dir="auto"></div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<p>Mehul, keep rocking the open web!</p>
<div class="" id="magicdomid21"><a href="https://discourse.mozilla-community.org/t/rep-of-the-month-june-2017/16773"><span class="author-a-ez76zz82zy82z68zfz86zcxz122zmwz76zz66z">Join</span><span class="author-a-tz66zfeb4z79zz66zqz122zz71zpz75zz73zz65zz66z"> us in congratulating him on Discourse.</span></a></div>]]>
  </description>
  <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jun 2017 21:45:12 +0000</pubDate>
  
</item>

<item>
  <title>Geraldo Barros - WebVR with A-Frame @Circuito SENAI</title>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">https://geraldobarros.me/?p=824</guid>
  <link>https://geraldobarros.me/webvr-with-frame-circuito-senai/</link>
  <description>
    <![CDATA[<p>The <a href="https://www.sympla.com.br/projetos-de-software---1-temporada-2017---dia-2306-e-2406__155283">Circuito SENAI</a> is a technology event of the <a href="https://informatica.sp.senai.br/">National Industrial Learning Service</a> in São Paulo that spreaded modern technologies, we worked in this event to ensure that more web developers are introduced on <a href="https://webvr.rocks/">WebVR</a>, 3D and <a href="https://aframe.io/">A-Frame</a> to begin creating virtual reality experiences in the Web.<span id="more-824"></span></p>
<p>I’ve been at the event to talk about WebVR and A-Frame, encourage more people to join in developing new virtual reality experiences on the Web and invite everyone to attend our hands on A-Frame Workshop that will happen next month.</p>
<p>It was so important to talk about VR, WebVR and 3D and tell the history of the development of these technologies and show what they have in common, and most importantly, show how Mozilla is working to ensure that this technology reaches more people and is accessible to everyone on the Web, our talk included topics such as:</p>
<ul>
<li>VR/3D</li>
<li>Headsets</li>
<li>Friction of VR Ecosystems</li>
<li>WebVR</li>
<li>WebGL</li>
<li>Supported browsers</li>
<li>Metaverse</li>
<li>A-Frame (how setup, how start coding, docs, examples…)</li>
</ul>
<p>Many developers believe that virtual reality is just a dream or utopia, or something extremely difficult to develop, this talk is important to show otherwise, that virtual reality is on the web and that we can all begin to create with open and modern technologies that Mozilla and other organizations around the world are developing.</p>
<p>After our talk many people joined us to talk, test and meet A-Frame demonstration, and everyone was invited to join us next month at our <a href="https://reps.mozilla.org/e/webvr-camp-senai-santa-cecilia/">WebVR Camp</a> to learn and develop practical things with A-Frame along with our awesome Mozilla volunteers team, this invitation was so important and necessary that in just a <span style="color: #ff0000;"><strong>few hours the tickets sold out</strong></span>!</p>
<p><em>Get your tickets to our WebVR Camp at <a href="https://www.eventbrite.com.br/e/a-frame-webvr-com-html-e-entity-component-registration-35103567716">Eventbrite</a></em><br />
<em>See my slides for this talk at<a href="https://github.com/barrosgeraldo/aframe-presentation"> A-Frame presentation slide decks</a></em></p>
<blockquote class="instagram-media">
<div style="padding: 8px;">
<div style="line-height: 0; margin-top: 40px; text-align: center; width: 100%;">
<div></div>
</div>
<p style="margin: 8px 0 0 0; padding: 0 4px;"> <a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/BVvQg5xhY6d/" style="color: #000; font-family: Arial,sans-serif; font-size: 14px; font-style: normal; font-weight: normal; line-height: 17px; text-decoration: none;" target="_blank">Simplesmente muito obrigada todos os palestrantes por terem ajudado a fazer esse evento lindo #circuitosenai Até os próximos <img alt="🙂" class="wp-smiley" src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/2.3/72x72/1f642.png" style="height: 1em;" /></a></p>
<p style="color: #c9c8cd; font-family: Arial,sans-serif; font-size: 14px; line-height: 17px; margin-bottom: 0; margin-top: 8px; overflow: hidden; padding: 8px 0 7px; text-align: center; white-space: nowrap;">Uma publicação compartilhada por Alda Rocha (@mjcoffeeholick) em <time datetime="2017-06-24T22:04:08+00:00" style="font-family: Arial,sans-serif; font-size: 14px; line-height: 17px;">Jun 24, 2017 às 3:04 PDT</time></p>
</div>
</blockquote>
<p></p>
<blockquote class="instagram-media">
<div style="padding: 8px;">
<div style="line-height: 0; margin-top: 40px; padding: 50.0% 0; text-align: center; width: 100%;">
<div></div>
</div>
<p style="margin: 8px 0 0 0; padding: 0 4px;"> <a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/BVsFa45B19V/" style="color: #000; font-family: Arial,sans-serif; font-size: 14px; font-style: normal; font-weight: normal; line-height: 17px; text-decoration: none;" target="_blank">Retomando o evento #circuitosenai agora com @geraldo_barros falando sobre VR e criando cenas e ambientes em@realidades virtual</a></p>
<p style="color: #c9c8cd; font-family: Arial,sans-serif; font-size: 14px; line-height: 17px; margin-bottom: 0; margin-top: 8px; overflow: hidden; padding: 8px 0 7px; text-align: center; white-space: nowrap;">Uma publicação compartilhada por Alda Rocha (@mjcoffeeholick) em <time datetime="2017-06-23T16:29:28+00:00" style="font-family: Arial,sans-serif; font-size: 14px; line-height: 17px;">Jun 23, 2017 às 9:29 PDT</time></p>
</div>
</blockquote>
<p></p>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="und"><a href="https://twitter.com/geraldobarros_">@geraldobarros_</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/mozillavr">@mozillavr</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/mozillabrasil">@mozillabrasil</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/circuitosenai?src=hash">#circuitosenai</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/aframe?src=hash">#aframe</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/WebVR?src=hash">#WebVR</a> <a href="https://t.co/EYl7KCheJy">pic.twitter.com/EYl7KCheJy</a></p>
<p>— cy63113 (@cyb3113) <a href="https://twitter.com/cyb3113/status/878285057932357632">June 23, 2017</a></p></blockquote>
<p></p>
<p><em>Hooooray!!! See you at our WebVR Camp in July!</em></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://geraldobarros.me/webvr-with-frame-circuito-senai/" rel="nofollow">WebVR with A-Frame @Circuito SENAI</a> appeared first on <a href="https://geraldobarros.me" rel="nofollow">Geraldo Barros</a>.</p>]]>
  </description>
  <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jun 2017 23:17:35 +0000</pubDate>
  
</item>

<item>
  <title>Sanyam Khurana - Why you should contribute to Open Source</title>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">tag:SanyamKhurana.com,2017-06-26:blog/why-contribute-to-foss.html</guid>
  <link>http://SanyamKhurana.com/blog/why-contribute-to-foss.html</link>
  <description>
    <![CDATA[<p>My first step with FOSS was <a class="reference external" href="http://www.sanyamkhurana.com/blog/how-dgplug-training-is-proving-beneficial-to-me.html">during the summer of 2014</a>, where I got introduced to <a class="reference external" href="http://dgplug.org">DGPLUG</a> (Durgapur Linux Users Group). Every year, they conduct a training over IRC covering a wide range of topics. Since then, I've been contributing to different projects, primarily to <a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/mozilla/gecko-dev">Mozilla's Gecko Engine</a>. Recently I also started <a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/python/cpython/pulls?utf8=%E2%9C%93&amp;q=is%3Apr%20author%3ACuriousLearner">contributing to CPython</a>.</p>
<p>Over <a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/CuriousLearner/">this journey as CuriousLearner over the past few years</a>, I've been fortunate enough to collaborate with some of the best engineers, learnt a lot of skills &amp; gained some nice perspective on different technologies by just contributing to Open Source. I owe my learning to them.</p>
<p>I've been always asked this question by my friends, colleagues, and strangers whom I often run into in local meet-ups and conferences.</p>
<blockquote>
<ul class="simple">
<li>Why should I contribute to Open Source</li>
<li>What's in it for me</li>
</ul>
</blockquote>
<p>So, I thought I would cover this topic from the perspective of a student as well as the perspective of a working professional.</p>
<div class="section" id="learn-new-skills">
<h2>Learn new skills</h2>
<p>When I say skills, I'm not referring to just coding skills or learning yet another framework. There are tons of skills to be learnt. These include coding, debugging, testing, writing docs, collaboration, participating in meetings etc. In FOSS, you won't just learn technical skills, but soft skills as well. That means you'll learn how to communicate effectively over different mediums and making sense to other people who might be from different backgrounds.</p>
<p>I've seen many engineers are hesitant when it comes to communication. They can think and write really nice code, but when it comes to explaining themselves, they lack the communication skills, which is vital to be a better professional.</p>
</div>
<div class="section" id="improve-existing-skills">
<h2>Improve existing skills</h2>
<p>It's not always about learning a new tech that you heard about. It's important to improve on things you think <em>you might already know</em>. Contributing to a FOSS project would make you learn intricate details that your mentors have gained working as a software craftsmen for several years.</p>
</div>
<div class="section" id="meet-like-minded-people">
<h2>Meet like-minded people</h2>
<p>Many organizations do stand-up / all-hands meetings where everyone comes together and explains what are they're working on, what they plan to do next and if they face any blocker. So, students, there is a high possibility that when you graduate, you'll do this in your organization :) You'll meet a lot of people having similar interests and you'll learn a lot of things just by hanging out with them (most of the time on IRC).</p>
</div>
<div class="section" id="learn-people-skills">
<h2>Learn people skills</h2>
<p>Learn team management, resolving internal conflicts, brainstorming on a new feature, public-speaking, time-management, conducting meet-ups &amp; learn to prioritize your work. You will just expand your horizons.</p>
</div>
<div class="section" id="learn-to-read">
<h2>Learn to READ</h2>
<p>One of the best things I've been ever taught is to "READ". (And those who've met me personally knows how many times I've been repeating this thing :)).</p>
<p>When I say read, I mean you'll read the documentation, development guide and most importantly the source code.</p>
<p>Always remember that code is meant to be read more times than it is written. When you contribute to any FOSS project, one of the important skill you add to your skill-set is to make your brain make sense out of the code that may look gibberish to many people.</p>
<p>This is a very important skill. Once you're in a company, you'll be given the responsibility of maintaining huge code base and constantly adding features to it. There won't be someone who would spoon-feed you by explaining what every line of code means.</p>
<p>I've seen many people struggling hard in their jobs to figure out what a particular piece of code does. But if you've already worked with humongous code bases, this shall be a cake-walk for you. You would already know how to scrutinize bugs, debug errors and most importantly, would have already taught your brain to think and <cite>READ</cite>.</p>
</div>
<div class="section" id="find-mentors">
<h2>Find mentors</h2>
<p>FOSS is all about mentors &amp; mentees. There are people just like me and you who volunteer their time and skill to do good for the community. You'll find a lot of mentors who would be willing to teach you different skills. Remember, that you've got this opportunity to learn from domain experts :)</p>
<p>And no matter what, always respect everyone's time.</p>
</div>
<div class="section" id="teach-others">
<h2>Teach others</h2>
<p>While it is important to get your code reviewed, it is much more important to review other's code. This would help you in learning different coding style and also about how someone approached a particular problem. This would help in expanding your logical skills &amp; as always you'll be learning a lot yourself along the way with having healthy discussions in code reviews.</p>
</div>
<div class="section" id="it-feels-great-to-make-small-changes">
<h2>It feels great to make (small) changes</h2>
<p>You don't necessarily need to work on big features in a project or become a life-long contributor. Contribute to a project that you use on daily basis (like <a class="reference external" href="https://whatcanidoformozilla.org/">Mozilla Firefox</a>) and I promise you that it would be gratifying when you see the whole world rely on the small code changes you did.</p>
<p>A small change in the documentation means you might save someone countless hours of debugging and scratching their head on how to use a particular piece of code. Always remember, documentation bugs are not something inferior; you'll learn a lot in writing documentation, right from the tools such as Sphinx and rST to expanding your domain knowledge about the project.</p>
</div>
<div class="section" id="building-your-reputation-career-along-the-way">
<h2>Building your reputation (&amp; career) along the way</h2>
<p>All the code you'll write in Open Source projects would be public and can be taken as a demonstration of how you write code &amp; what you can do. It depicts how you work with others and most importantly give you an enormous amount of experience in working with people having diversified skill-set.</p>
<p>Once you get acquainted with the code base, you'll be invited to develop stand-alone features and who knows you might get that commit bit turned on when you've developed enough reputation in the community ;)</p>
<p>Apart from all the things mentioned above, I think Mozilla's mission says a lot about why I contribute to FOSS</p>
<blockquote>
Doing good is part of our code</blockquote>
<p>Alright, I didn't realize, I'll be able to write this much. Hopefully, this would help &amp; motivate people to get involved in contributing to Open Source. As always, if you have any queries, or want help in contributing to any project, feel free to mail me on <strong>Sanyam [at] SanyamKhurana [dot] com</strong>.</p>
</div>]]>
  </description>
  <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jun 2017 11:41:00 +0000</pubDate>
  
</item>

<item>
  <title>Official Reps Blog - New Council Members – Spring 2017</title>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.mozilla.org/mozillareps/?p=497</guid>
  <link>https://blog.mozilla.org/mozillareps/2017/06/23/new-council-members-spring-2017/</link>
  <description>
    <![CDATA[<p>We are very happy to announce that our new council members are already onboarded and working on their focus areas.</p>
<p>We are also extremely happy with the participation we had for these elections as for the first time we had the record number of 12 nominees and 215 (75% of the body)  have voted.</p>
<p><a href="http://blog.mozilla.org/mozillareps/files/2017/06/collage.jpg"><img alt="" class="aligncenter  wp-image-498" height="226" src="http://blog.mozilla.org/mozillareps/files/2017/06/collage-252x189.jpg" width="301" /></a></p>
<p> </p>
<p>Welcome <a href="https://reps.mozilla.org/u/ankitgadgil/">Ankit</a>, <a href="https://reps.mozilla.org/u/Mte90/">Daniele</a>, <a href="https://reps.mozilla.org/u/elio/">Elio</a>, <a href="https://reps.mozilla.org/u/fayetandog/">Faye</a>, and <a href="https://reps.mozilla.org/u/Flore/">Flore</a>, we are very excited to have you onboard.</p>
<p>Here are the areas that each of the new council members will work on:</p>
<ul>
<li>Flore – Resources</li>
<li>Faye – Coaching</li>
<li>Ankit  -Activate</li>
<li>Elio – Communications</li>
<li>Daniele – onboarding</li>
</ul>
<p>Of course they will also all co-work with the old council members on the program’s strategy and implementation bringing the Reps Program forward.</p>
<p>Also I would like to thank and send #mozlove to <a href="https://reps.mozilla.org/u/dricupello/">Adriano</a>, <a href="https://reps.mozilla.org/u/ioana_chiorean/">Ioana</a>, <a href="https://reps.mozilla.org/u/Rara/">Rara</a> and <a href="https://reps.mozilla.org/u/FaisalAziz/">Faisal</a> for all their hard work during their term as Reps Councils Members. Your work has been impactful and appreciated and we can’t thank you enough.</p>
<p>The Mozilla Reps Council is the governing body of the Mozilla Reps Program. It provides the general vision of the program and oversees day-to-day operations globally. Currently, 7 volunteers and 2 paid staff sit on the council.<a href="https://wiki.mozilla.org/ReMo/Council"> Find out more on the Reps wiki</a>.</p>
<p>Don’t forget to congratulate the new Council members on the<a href="https://discourse.mozilla-community.org/t/important-council-elections-results-and-next-steps/16012"> Discourse topic</a>!</p>
<p> </p>]]>
  </description>
  <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jun 2017 09:39:39 +0000</pubDate>
  
</item>

<item>
  <title>Official Reps Blog - RepsNext – Status Update June 2017</title>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.mozilla.org/mozillareps/?p=496</guid>
  <link>https://blog.mozilla.org/mozillareps/2017/06/22/repsnext-status-update-june-2017/</link>
  <description>
    <![CDATA[<p>In the past few months we have kept working on the implementation of our RepsNext initiative. The RepsNext initiative has started more than a year ago with the goal to bring the Mozilla Reps program to the next level. <a href="https://blog.mozilla.org/mozillareps/2017/01/30/repsnext-status-update-january-2017/">Back in January we wrote a status update</a>. Almost half a year later, we want to provide a further update. We have also <a href="https://blog.mozilla.org/mozillareps/2017/04/20/reps-program-objectives-q2-2017/">published our OKRs for the current quarter</a> with goals to further the implementation of RepsNext.</p>
<p><a href="https://discourse-paas-production-content.s3.amazonaws.com/original/2X/9/9c3909b947de58cfa42fa46560f7fb110fedb20d.png"><img alt="RepsNext overview explaining what is done and what not, explained further down in text in this article." src="https://discourse-paas-production-content.s3.amazonaws.com/original/2X/9/9c3909b947de58cfa42fa46560f7fb110fedb20d.png" /></a></p>
<h2>Resources</h2>
<p>The Resources training is finalized. It’s still a little bit text-heavy, but we want to move forward with the training and iterate based on feedback. For this, we have reached out to a few selected Reps based on the past 6 months to ask them to test the training and give initial feedback about the process and content. Once we have this feedback, we will adjust the training if needed and then open up the Resources track for applications. Applications will most probably be done in a Google Form and will include general info about the Rep as well as a free-text input field where the Rep can explain why they are fitted for the track as well as provide some links to previous, good budget requests they filed. You can learn more about the Resources Track on the <a href="https://wiki.mozilla.org/ReMo/Resources">Resources Wiki page</a>.</p>
<h2>Onboarding Process</h2>
<p>We have simplified and streamlined the on-boarding process for new Reps. Until April we had a lot of applications that were open for more than 6 months. We are happy to report that we have started to on-board 20 new Reps between April and now. Further 10 Reps are in the administrative process of signing the agreement and creating profiles on the Portal. All of this is thanks to a new <a href="https://wiki.mozilla.org/ReMo/Webinar">Webinar</a>. The Webinar allows us to give Reps the very needed first information about Reps and what to expect being a Rep.</p>
<h2>Participation Alignment</h2>
<p>The Council is working with the Participation team in order to co-create the quarterly and yearly goals and OKRs for 2017. This happened twice already this year and we will continue to give our valuable input and feedback for the quarters to come. The <a href="http://mozilla.github.io/Reps/okr-dashboard/">program’s goals</a> are also being created based the team’s goals and priorities. We are also attending the monthly Open Innovation Team calls. Of course this is an ongoing work that will continue. The Reps Council is also involved in strategic and operational discussions as representatives for the broader community, giving feedback on the currently ongoing strategic projects. All of this work will continue at the All Hands in San Francisco later this month.</p>
<h2>Leadership</h2>
<p>At the beginning of our work on RepsNext, we wanted to do a specific Leadership Track Reps can apply for as a specialization. Throughout the past months it became clear that we want all Reps to improve their leadership skills to help out other Reps as well as their communities. Therefore <a href="http://wiki.mozilla.org/ReMo/Leadership">we created an initial list of good leadership resources</a> for everyone to access and learn. At first this is a basic list of resources which will be improved on in the future. We want all Reps to be able to improve their leadership skills as soon as possible and later build on top of this knowledge with further resources. Please provide <a href="https://discourse.mozilla-community.org/t/leadership-resources/16551">your feedback in the Discourse topic</a>!</p>
<h2>Coaching</h2>
<p>Previously known as Regional Coaches, <a href="https://discourse.mozilla-community.org/t/next-steps-for-regional-community-coaches/16094?u=mkohler">Community Coaches</a> will continue to support local communities. Additionally to that we are currently creating a <a href="https://github.com/mozilla/Reps/issues/137">Coaches Training</a> to train new Reps on coaching skills as well as existing mentors to improve their skills. These coaches will be able to coach Reps in regards to personal development. The idea is to have the Coaches Training on a self-serve basis, so everyone can take the training and complete a narrative which will be evaluated at the end to graduate from the training. This will help us to increase the quality of coaching/mentoring in the Reps program as well as in local communities. Additionally it will decrease the current bottleneck we have onboarding new Reps and we will be able to assign a coach to every Rep on a one year commitment basis with the option to switch the coach after this period. We are currently reviewing the implementation proposal so we can add the training to Teachable and publish it for all Reps.</p>
<h2>Functional areas</h2>
<p>We recently asked all Reps <a href="https://discourse.mozilla-community.org/t/action-needed-reps-path/15539">to choose their path for the future</a>. This gives us a valuable basis to argue around functional doers in the Reps program. We will further build out the exact details about functional doers and their interest. The ongoing strategy projects will additionally give us valuable guidance in coming up with the perfect opportunities for functional doers. If you are interested in statistics about this survey, <a href="https://discourse.mozilla-community.org/t/statistics-about-reps-path-responses/16206">join our discussion on Discourse</a>.</p>
<h2>Upcoming work</h2>
<p>We are in the last steps to finish our work on the Resources track and the Coaching training. This allows us to start talks on further improvements in the third quarter of this year. We are also going to the <a href="https://wiki.mozilla.org/All_Hands/SanFrancisco">All Hands</a> to discuss Reps, Strategy, Mobilizers and more with the Open Innovation team. We will update you about the outcomes of that after the All Hands.</p>
<p>You can follow all the Reps program’s goals and progress in the<a href="https://github.com/mozilla/Reps/issues"> Reps Issue Tracker</a>.</p>
<p>Which thoughts cross your mind upon reading this? Where would you like to help out? Let’s keep the conversation going! <a href="https://discourse.mozilla-community.org/t/repsnext-update-june-2017/16585">Join the discussion on Discourse.</a></p>]]>
  </description>
  <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jun 2017 10:19:11 +0000</pubDate>
  
</item>

<item>
  <title>Md Shahbaz Alam - A-frame Bug Fixing Contest</title>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alamshahbaz.wordpress.com/?p=848</guid>
  <link>https://alamshahbaz.wordpress.com/2017/06/10/a-frame-bug-fixing-contest/</link>
  <description>
    <![CDATA[<div class="ace-line" id="magicdomid32"><span class="">Hello Mozilla India!</span></div>
<div></div>
<div class="ace-line" id="magicdomid33"><span class="">We are inviting all the new developers as well as everyone else interested in contributing,  to take part in the A-Frame bug fixing contest. A quick description for those who don’t know, A-Frame is an open-source web framework for building virtual reality experiences for the web[1]. Your tasks will involve checking the open good-first-bugs in the A-Frame framework[2] as well as the A-Frame official website[3]. Bonus points for fixing advanced bugs! [4] <img alt="😉" class="wp-smiley" src="https://s0.wp.com/wp-content/mu-plugins/wpcom-smileys/twemoji/2/72x72/1f609.png" style="height: 1em;" /></span></div>
<div class="" id="magicdomid4"></div>
<div class="ace-line" id="magicdomid34"><span class="">Steps to get started:</span></div>
<div class="ace-line" id="magicdomid35">
<ul class="list-bullet1">
<li><span class="">Visit the links [2] and [3] and comment </span><span class="b"><b> “I want to work on this”</b></span><span class="">  on the issue you decide to work upon.</span></li>
</ul>
</div>
<div class="ace-line" id="magicdomid36">
<ul class="list-bullet1">
<li><span class="">Ask for help if you need. You will get enough help from the A-Frame team as well as the WebVR-India team.</span></li>
</ul>
</div>
<div class="ace-line" id="magicdomid37">
<ul class="list-bullet2">
<li><span class="">Fork the repository on GitHub.</span></li>
</ul>
</div>
<div class="ace-line" id="magicdomid38">
<ul class="list-bullet2">
<li><span class="">Run npm install and npm run dev to serve the test examples.</span></li>
</ul>
</div>
<div class="ace-line" id="magicdomid39">
<ul class="list-bullet2">
<li><span class="">Make changes to your fork of the repository.</span></li>
</ul>
</div>
<div class="ace-line" id="magicdomid40">
<ul class="list-bullet2">
<li><span class="">If necessary, write unit tests and run with npm test.</span></li>
</ul>
</div>
<div class="ace-line" id="magicdomid41">
<ul class="list-bullet2">
<li><span class="">Submit a pull request to the master branch.</span></li>
</ul>
</div>
<div class="ace-line" id="magicdomid42">
<ul class="list-bullet2">
<li><span class="">Address review comments if any.</span></li>
</ul>
</div>
<div class="ace-line" id="magicdomid43">
<ul class="list-bullet1">
<li><span class="">Once you have fixed the issue, report it to the community as well, using the issue 33 under volunteer-contributions[5].</span></li>
</ul>
</div>
<div class="ace-line" id="magicdomid44"><span class=""> </span></div>
<div class="ace-line" id="magicdomid45"><span class="">What’s in it for you?</span></div>
<div class="ace-line" id="magicdomid46">
<ul class="list-bullet1">
<li><span class="">Contributors who resolve the maximum number of bugs (Top 5), will get a Sony Xperia Z3C to hack and explore!</span></li>
</ul>
</div>
<div class="ace-line" id="magicdomid47">
<ul class="list-bullet1">
<li><span class="">Amongst the remaining ones, the contributors who have fixed a minimum of three bugs will get a special T-shirt from WebVR India! </span></li>
</ul>
</div>
<div class="" id="magicdomid19"></div>
<div class="ace-line" id="magicdomid48"><span class="">And this doesn’t just end here! While fixing these bugs you will get more familiar with the codebase of A-frame, which will enhance your skills as well as be a great help for the exciting open-source project. As you continue, you will be able to fix a lot more bugs for A-Frame as well as develop for awesome features for the framework. And eventually you become a ‘</span><span class="b"><b>WebVR Hack Star</b></span><span class="">‘, who can guide others to become like them!</span></div>
<div class="ace-line" id="magicdomid49"><span class="">So what are you waiting for, jump on the links right away and get started! </span></div>
<div class="" id="magicdomid22"></div>
<div class="ace-line" id="magicdomid50"><span class="">[1] </span><span class=" url"><a href="https://aframe.io">https://aframe.io</a></span></div>
<div class="ace-line" id="magicdomid51"><span class="">[2] </span><span class=" url"><a href="https://github.com/aframevr/aframe/labels/help%20wanted%20%28easy%29">https://github.com/aframevr/aframe/labels/help%20wanted%20%28easy%29</a></span></div>
<div class="ace-line" id="magicdomid52"><span class="">[3] </span><span class=" url"><a href="https://github.com/aframevr/aframe-site/labels/help%20wanted%20%28easy%29">https://github.com/aframevr/aframe-site/labels/help%20wanted%20%28easy%29</a></span></div>
<div class="ace-line" id="magicdomid53"><span class="">[4] </span><span class=" url"><a href="https://github.com/aframevr/aframe/labels/help%20wanted%20%28hard%29">https://github.com/aframevr/aframe/labels/help%20wanted%20%28hard%29</a></span></div>
<div class="ace-line" id="magicdomid54"><span class="">[5] </span><span class=" url"><a href="https://github.com/webvr-india/volunteer-contributions/issues/33">https://github.com/webvr-india/volunteer-contributions/issues/33</a></span></div>
<div></div>
<div>For any queries whatsoever, contact @shaguftamethwani or @mdsbzalam on Telegram</div>
<div class="" id="magicdomid28"></div>
<div class="" id="magicdomid29"></div>
<div class="" id="magicdomid30"></div>
<div class="" id="magicdomid31"></div><br />  <a href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/alamshahbaz.wordpress.com/848/" rel="nofollow"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/alamshahbaz.wordpress.com/848/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" height="1" src="https://pixel.wp.com/b.gif?host=alamshahbaz.wordpress.com&amp;blog=73514675&amp;post=848&amp;subd=alamshahbaz&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" />]]>
  </description>
  <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jun 2017 06:43:29 +0000</pubDate>
  
</item>

<item>
  <title>Official Reps Blog - Rep of the Month – May 2017</title>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.mozilla.org/mozillareps/?p=494</guid>
  <link>https://blog.mozilla.org/mozillareps/2017/05/29/rep-of-the-month-may-2017/</link>
  <description>
    <![CDATA[<div class="cooked">
<p>Please join us in congratulating <a href="https://reps.mozilla.org/u/vabajaj/" rel="nofollow">Vaibhav Bajaj</a>, our Rep of the Month for May 2017!</p>
<p>Vaibhav is a Reps Mentor from Bhopal, India. He has been contributing as a Mozilla Rep since October 2014.</p>
<div class="lightbox-wrapper"><a class="lightbox" href="https://discourse-paas-production-content.s3.amazonaws.com/original/2X/3/3d041e89ec5c7520386142992a60bf066a04b0ee.jpg" rel="nofollow" title="3567cb5bef4d24f03d871f4ed1a81e8a.jpg"><img class="aligncenter" height="500" src="https://discourse-paas-production-content.s3.amazonaws.com/optimized/2X/3/3d041e89ec5c7520386142992a60bf066a04b0ee_1_500x500.jpg" width="500" /></a></div>
<p>During the past few months, Vaibhav has organized a <a href="https://reps.mozilla.org/u/vabajaj/r/2017/January/2/41916/" rel="nofollow">WebVR Camp</a> in Bhopal, and attended the WebVR Camp in Indore. Additionally he took part in the <a href="https://reps.mozilla.org/e/mozilla-hindi-marathi-community-meet-up-2016-1/" rel="nofollow">Hindi &amp; Marathi localization community meetup</a> and participated in the <a href="https://reps.mozilla.org/e/a-frame-hack-night-india/" rel="nofollow">A-Frame Hack Night India</a> which had the goal to create training material about WebVR. To help increase the Nightly usage in India, he is also part of the <a href="https://reps.mozilla.org/e/india-uses-firefox-nightly/" rel="nofollow">India uses Firefox Nightly</a> initiative.</p>
<p>Vaibhav, Keep rocking the open web!</p>
<div class="" id="magicdomid21"><a href="https://discourse.mozilla-community.org/t/rep-of-the-month-may-2017/15950"><span class="author-a-ez76zz82zy82z68zfz86zcxz122zmwz76zz66z">Join</span><span class="author-a-tz66zfeb4z79zz66zqz122zz71zpz75zz73zz65zz66z"> us in congratulating him on Discourse.</span></a></div>
</div>]]>
  </description>
  <pubDate>Mon, 29 May 2017 15:46:00 +0000</pubDate>
  
</item>

<item>
  <title>Viswaprasath KS - Creating Simple Easy Searcher Using ContextMenu</title>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://iamVP7.in//Creating-Simple-Easy-Searcher-Using-ContextMenu/</guid>
  <link>http://iamVP7.in//Creating-Simple-Easy-Searcher-Using-ContextMenu/</link>
  <description>
    <![CDATA[<p>Before reading this post setup your Firefox so you can run WebExtensions in your browser.</p>]]>
  </description>
  <pubDate>Sat, 27 May 2017 23:34:00 +0000</pubDate>
  
</item>

<item>
  <title>Viswaprasath KS - Creating ShortenURL Maker Addon</title>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://iamVP7.in//Creating-ShortenURL-Maker/</guid>
  <link>http://iamVP7.in//Creating-ShortenURL-Maker/</link>
  <description>
    <![CDATA[<p>Before reading this post setup your Firefox so you can run WebExtensions in your browser.</p>]]>
  </description>
  <pubDate>Sat, 27 May 2017 23:34:00 +0000</pubDate>
  
</item>

<item>
  <title>Viswaprasath KS - Simple Alarm with Notification</title>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://iamVP7.in//Create-Alarm-And-Notification/</guid>
  <link>http://iamVP7.in//Create-Alarm-And-Notification/</link>
  <description>
    <![CDATA[<p>Before reading this post setup your Firefox so you can run WebExtensions in your browser.</p>]]>
  </description>
  <pubDate>Thu, 25 May 2017 23:34:00 +0000</pubDate>
  
</item>

<item>
  <title>Geraldo Barros - 2017 Mozilla Global Sprint – São Paulo – BRA</title>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">https://geraldobarros.me/?p=790</guid>
  <link>https://geraldobarros.me/2017-mozilla-global-sprint-sao-paulo-bra/</link>
  <description>
    <![CDATA[<p>We’re hosting a site here at São Paulo for the <a href="https://mozilla.github.io/global-sprint/">Mozilla Global Sprint</a> on June 1-2, 2017. The Global Sprint is a fun, two-day community event bringing people from around the world together to collaborate on open projects, such as developing open source software, building open tools, writing curriculum, planning events, and more.<span id="more-790"></span></p>
<p>We’d like to invite you to join us on the 1st and 2nd at Campus São Paulo, from 9AM.You can join in and participate, no matter your skill set or level. We’re looking for coders, designers, artists, writers, educators, students— anyone who’s passionate about the open web. We’ve got a terrific list of projects that need help— all that’s missing is you!</p>
<p>For more on how you’d participate at the event, see our info page for <a href="https://mozilla.github.io/global-sprint/participants/">Participants</a>. To browse all the amazing projects you can work on during the Sprint, see our <a href="https://mozilla.github.io/global-sprint/projects">Featured Projects</a>, and our full list of all <a href="https://github.com/mozilla/global-sprint/issues">Sprint Projects</a>.</p>
<p>If you’re interested in attending, please <a href="https://ti.to/Mozilla/global-sprint-sao-paulo">register</a>. If you have any questions about our local event, feel free to get in touch!</p>
<p>I hope you’ll join us for the Sprint!</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://geraldobarros.me/2017-mozilla-global-sprint-sao-paulo-bra/" rel="nofollow">2017 Mozilla Global Sprint – São Paulo – BRA</a> appeared first on <a href="https://geraldobarros.me" rel="nofollow">Geraldo Barros</a>.</p>]]>
  </description>
  <pubDate>Thu, 25 May 2017 23:16:29 +0000</pubDate>
  
</item>

<item>
  <title>Tanzeel Khan - Kashmir Uses Firefox Nightly</title>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://khantanzeel.wordpress.com/?p=350</guid>
  <link>https://khantanzeel.wordpress.com/2017/05/25/kashmir-uses-firefox-nightly/</link>
  <description>
    <![CDATA[<p><img alt="nightly event.png" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-351" height="280" src="https://khantanzeel.files.wordpress.com/2017/06/nightly-event.png?w=560" width="560" /></p>
<p>The event was a part of PAN India pilot campaign for Firefox Nightly aimed to create a strong technical community who will be using and testing Nightly on a regular basis. Besides, it was a meetup for community members in the region. The event <a href="https://reps.mozilla.org/e/kashmir-uses-firefox-nightly/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Kashmir Uses Firefox Nightly</a> was organised at Bangs, Srinagar on 25th May, 2017.</p>
<p><img alt="fxnightly1.PNG" class=" size-full wp-image-371 alignnone" height="231" src="https://khantanzeel.files.wordpress.com/2017/06/fxnightly11.png?w=316" width="316" /> <img alt="fxnightly2.PNG" class="alignnone  wp-image-372" height="231" src="https://khantanzeel.files.wordpress.com/2017/06/fxnightly22.png?w=305&amp;h=231" width="305" /></p>
<p>We started with the brief Introduction about Mozilla, its projects and programs and its local community in the state of Jammu and Kashmir. We then introduced the attendees to Firefox Nightly, why do we have this version of firefox, why should we use it and what are the benefits. Then the steps to download, install and the filing of bug was shown. Few attendees installed the browser and also signed up for an account on Bugzilla.</p>
<p><img alt="fxnightly3.PNG" class=" size-full wp-image-374 alignnone" height="231" src="https://khantanzeel.files.wordpress.com/2017/06/fxnightly3.png?w=308" width="308" />  <img alt="fxnightly4.PNG" class=" size-full wp-image-377 alignnone" height="232" src="https://khantanzeel.files.wordpress.com/2017/06/fxnightly41.png?w=311" width="311" /></p>
<p>We also discussed WebCompat and how to contribute to it.</p>
<p>Besides, the attendees were introduced to the projects and programs of Mozilla that are currently in focus. WebVR, Rust, WebCompat to name a few. We also devised a plan for the local community as to what activities to take out in the coming months.</p>
<p><img alt="fxnightly5.PNG" class="  wp-image-379 alignnone" height="235" src="https://khantanzeel.files.wordpress.com/2017/06/fxnightly5.png?w=314&amp;h=235" width="314" />    <img alt="fxnightly6.PNG" class=" size-full wp-image-380 alignnone" height="237" src="https://khantanzeel.files.wordpress.com/2017/06/fxnightly6.png?w=271" width="271" /></p>
<p>The attendees shared content about the event and the Firefox Nightly Browser online with the hashtag #INUsesFxNightly.</p>
<p>For more event pictures, visit our <a href="https://www.facebook.com/mozillajandk/posts/1964781080423388" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Facebook Page</a></p>
<p><a href="https://www.facebook.com/plugins/post.php?href=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.facebook.com%2Fmozillajandk%2Fposts%2F1964781080423388&amp;width=500">https://www.facebook.com/plugins/post.php?href=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.facebook.com%2Fmozillajandk%2Fposts%2F1964781080423388&amp;width=500</a></p>
<p>For more information, mail us at mozillajk@gmail.com</p><br />  <a href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/khantanzeel.wordpress.com/350/" rel="nofollow"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/khantanzeel.wordpress.com/350/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" height="1" src="https://pixel.wp.com/b.gif?host=khantanzeel.wordpress.com&amp;blog=64114717&amp;post=350&amp;subd=khantanzeel&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" />]]>
  </description>
  <pubDate>Thu, 25 May 2017 15:55:59 +0000</pubDate>
  
</item>

<item>
  <title>Geraldo Barros - My first WebVR Camp roadshow with local projects based in São Paulo and Campinas</title>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">https://geraldobarros.me/?p=742</guid>
  <link>https://geraldobarros.me/my-first-webvr-camp-roadshow-with-local-projects-based-in-sao-paulo-and-campinas/</link>
  <description>
    <![CDATA[<p>In recent weeks I’ve taken my time to dive into <a href="https://webvr.rocks/">WebVR</a> with <a href="https://aframe.io/">A-Frame</a> and teach people from technology projects to create new things using A-Frame, the result is that I teach WebVR/A-Frame to developers, creators, educators, clubbers, <a href="http://www.mozilla.org/pt-BR/contribute">Mozilla volunteers</a> and people working or not with technology, the workshops were part of the <a href="https://activate.mozilla.community/">Mozilla Activate campaign</a>.<span id="more-742"></span></p>
<p>And to start the journey, we have partnered with 3 local projects based in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Campinas">Campinas</a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/S%C3%A3o_Paulo">São Paulo</a>, which are:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="http://reprograma.com.br">Reprograma</a>, a project based in São Paulo focused on the professional development of women in technology that work with <a href="http://www.portaldaindustria.com.br/senai/">National Service of Industrial Learning </a>in São Paulo at Santa Cecília.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.campinas.sp.gov.br/governo/assistencia-social-seguranca-alimentar/juventude-conectada.php">Programa Juventude Conectada</a>, a Campinas municipal government initiative to promote digital and social inclusion, through free access to information technology in community telecentres implemented in the different territories of the city.</li>
<li><a href="https://leaomozillaclubs.com">Leão Mozilla Clubs</a>, a Mozilla Club based on Campinas focused on digital inclusion, web literacy and 21 century skills, that I lead as captain.</li>
</ul>
<p><em>In this report I will quickly tell you the steps for you to prepare this workshop, our experiences, <strong>tips and tricks</strong>.</em></p>
<h3>#1 Roadshow’s Organizing</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Event team:</strong> I invited 2 local Mozilla volunteers, club facilitators and colleagues involved within the projects to facilitate partnerships, logistics and organization.</li>
<li><strong>Date and venue:</strong> along with the project facilitators we schedule the dates and space.</li>
<li><strong>Promoting:</strong> within the projects we send emails and talked about the workshop weeks before.</li>
<li><strong>Material:</strong> We customized the official <a href="https://github.com/aframevr/aframe-presentation-kit">A-Frame presentation</a> and <a href="https://github.com/barrosgeraldo/aframe-school-br-activities">created our own teaching activities for workshops that include comments in the HTML code</a> – and for physical materials we buy <a href="https://vr.google.com/cardboard/">cardboads</a> and print beautiful <a href="https://github.com/aframevr/aframe-presentation-kit/blob/master/materials/sticker-aframe2.png">A-Frame buttons</a>.</li>
<li><strong>Learning:</strong> We also studied A-Frame using <a href="https://aframe.io/school/">A-Frame School</a> and <a href="https://aframe.io/docs/0.5.0/introduction/">official documentation</a>.</li>
</ul>
<h3>#2 Event’s Flow</h3>
<p>This is our event flow, it is based on the <a href="https://activate.mozilla.community/webvr-camp/">Mozilla Activate template</a>, with only a few modifications and more details.</p>
<p><strong>Getting Started<br />
</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Introduction of speakers and attendees with an ice breaker session</li>
<li>About <a href="https://www.mozilla.org/mission/">Mozilla’s mission</a> as a non-profit and community-focused organization.</li>
<li>About <a href="https://gurumukhi.wordpress.com/2016/09/21/a-frame-for-vr-development-on-web/">VR, WebVR &amp; A-Frame</a></li>
</ul>
<p><strong>A-Frame <a href="https://aframe.io/docs/0.3.0/introduction/">Concepts</a><br />
</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><a href="http://aframe.io/examples">Demo</a> of basic A-Frame scenes &amp; apps</li>
<li>Creating account and overview in GitHub and Glitch</li>
<li>Introduce A-Frame HTML tags</li>
<li>Building scenes with exercises using:
<ul>
<li>Primitives</li>
<li>Inspector</li>
<li>Position</li>
<li>Rotation</li>
<li>Radius</li>
<li>Others primitives</li>
<li>Loading resources (images using A-Frame CDN)</li>
<li>Entity-component</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Hacking</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Time to create/remix a scene</li>
<li>Push the projects to GitHub account</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Review &amp; Plan<br />
</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Review the whole event</li>
<li>Talk about <a href="http://aframe.io/community/">A-Frame community</a></li>
<li><a href="http://mzl.la/howwasit">How Was It</a> – Form</li>
<li>Swags</li>
</ul>
<h3>#3 The experience</h3>
<h4><a href="http://reprograma.com.br/">Reprograma</a></h4>
<div class="wp-caption aligncenter" id="attachment_734" style="width: 1290px;"><img alt="WebVR Reprograma Learning Team" class="size-full wp-image-734" height="727" src="https://geraldobarros.me/wp-content/uploads/2017/05/webvr_reprograma.png" width="1280" /><p class="wp-caption-text">WebVR Reprograma Learning Team</p></div>
<p>It was my first experience teaching A-Frame and happened to students of the web development course of <strong>Reprograma</strong> and other guests who participated in our workshop, this was certainly one of the best workshops because I and Mozilla volunteers learned a lot about methodology to teach A-Frame and the organization of this type of workshop. Participants are developers in the process of learning and professional development, already familiar with HTML, CSS, Javascript and GitHub, not yet very familiar with <a href="https://glitch.com/">Glitch</a>.</p>
<p><em><strong>Our learning this first workshop were:</strong></em></p>
<ul>
<li>It is necessary to think of a new teaching methodology, including finding other platforms that can help facilitators such as <a href="http://www.dontpad.com/">Dontpad</a>, <a href="https://glitch.com/">Glitch</a> is a good tool, but maybe not the best for learning.</li>
<li>WebVR and related workshops need much longer than expected, including for organization.</li>
<li>Coffee, break and time for networking is important to keep participants active and unwind.</li>
<li>Tag name are important to identify everyone who is attending the event, to know their names at all times and to improve empathy – in this case, two events were happening in the same place.</li>
<li>Swag is very cool, fun and allows participants to take the Mozilla brand, A-Frame and WebVR to every corner of the city, marketing allied to things people like = <strong>match</strong>.</li>
<li>Invite Mozilla volunteers around to learn and develop the upcoming workshops.</li>
<li>Invite volunteers to join local Mozilla community groups, they may be interested in other areas and ways of contributing.</li>
</ul>
<p>Participants were very excited for more workshops that teach more about A-Frame, others have started creating their own projects using A-Frame!</p>
<h4><a href="https://leaomozillaclubs.com">Leão Mozilla Clubs</a></h4>
<div class="wp-caption aligncenter" id="attachment_773" style="width: 3850px;"><img alt="WebVR Workshop on Leão Mozilla Clubs" class="size-full wp-image-773" height="2160" src="https://geraldobarros.me/wp-content/uploads/2017/05/DSC_0075.jpg" width="3840" /><p class="wp-caption-text">WebVR Workshop on Leão Mozilla Clubs</p></div>
<div class="wp-caption aligncenter" id="attachment_771" style="width: 3850px;"><img alt="WebVR Workshop on Leão Mozilla Clubs" class="size-full wp-image-771" height="2160" src="https://geraldobarros.me/wp-content/uploads/2017/05/DSC_0073.jpg" width="3840" /><p class="wp-caption-text">WebVR Workshop on Leão Mozilla Clubs</p></div>
<div class="wp-caption aligncenter" id="attachment_776" style="width: 3850px;"><img alt="WebVR Workshop on Leão Mozilla Clubs" class="size-full wp-image-776" height="2160" src="https://geraldobarros.me/wp-content/uploads/2017/05/DSC_0078.jpg" width="3840" /><p class="wp-caption-text">WebVR Workshop on Leão Mozilla Clubs</p></div>
<p>This was my second experience teaching A-Frame, the participants are teenagers and some adults including seniors who are developing essential 21st century skills weekly at the club, most of them future technology professionals and content creators such as musicians, artists and youtubers.</p>
<p>Teaching WebVR/A-Frame has taken 2 sessions to learn basics of WebVR and A-Frame, here you also need something fun to motivate this specific audience, we teach basic concepts of VR, we try the examples and we begin to make a remix of examples of the A-Frame directly in the <a href="https://github.com/aframevr/aframe-inspector">Inspector</a> to learn notions of trigonometry such as position, rotation and radius, in addition to familiarizing with the primitives and entities, after the playful experiment with cardboards and A-Frame Inspector we started development activities using only the HTML tags of the A-Frame using <a href="https://atom.io/">Atom</a> that is already installed on telecentre computers.</p>
<p><em><strong>Our learning this second workshop were:</strong></em></p>
<ul>
<li>Activities in Mozilla Clubs need 2-3 facilitators to help with the activity, it’s something very new to them.</li>
</ul>
<p>We already have scheduled activities to continue teaching and developing cool things with A-Frame.</p>
<h4><a href="http://www.campinas.sp.gov.br/governo/assistencia-social-seguranca-alimentar/juventude-conectada.php">Programa Juventude Conectada</a></h4>
<div class="wp-caption aligncenter" id="attachment_786" style="width: 5258px;"><img alt="WebVR Workshops on Programa Juventude Conectada" class="size-full wp-image-786" height="3936" src="https://geraldobarros.me/wp-content/uploads/2017/05/DSC_0107-1.jpg" width="5248" /><p class="wp-caption-text">WebVR Workshops on Programa Juventude Conectada</p></div>
<div class="wp-caption aligncenter" id="attachment_784" style="width: 5258px;"><img alt="WebVR Workshops on Programa Juventude Conectada" class="size-full wp-image-784" height="3936" src="https://geraldobarros.me/wp-content/uploads/2017/05/DSC_0141.jpg" width="5248" /><p class="wp-caption-text">WebVR Workshops on Programa Juventude Conectada</p></div>
<div class="wp-caption aligncenter" id="attachment_783" style="width: 5258px;"><img alt="WebVR Workshops on Programa Juventude Conectada" class="size-full wp-image-783" height="3936" src="https://geraldobarros.me/wp-content/uploads/2017/05/DSC_0138.jpg" width="5248" /><p class="wp-caption-text">WebVR Workshops on Programa Juventude Conectada</p></div>
<div class="wp-caption aligncenter" id="attachment_787" style="width: 5258px;"><img alt="WebVR Workshops on Programa Juventude Conectada" class="size-full wp-image-787" height="3936" src="https://geraldobarros.me/wp-content/uploads/2017/05/DSC_0134-1.jpg" width="5248" /><p class="wp-caption-text">WebVR Workshops on Programa Juventude Conectada</p></div>
<p>We have already worked with other workshops of Mozilla together with the Programa Juventude Conectada, is a digital culture program of the city of Campinas, here we developed 4 workshops for 68 educators of digital culture, we divided them into 4 different groups in 2 full days of workshops . The educators of digital culture work promoting digital culture that include digital inclusion, web development, photography and video in all the telecenters of the city of Campinas.</p>
<p>The teams of educators have multiple skills, including web development, so it was easy to develop the activity for all of them, the prediction is that this group can take A-Frame/WebVR to activities in telecenters of the city and many projects begin to be developed with the framework.</p>
<p><em><strong>Our learnings in this third workshop were:</strong></em></p>
<ul>
<li>Get WiFi passwords and administrator users of the operating systems of lab computers.</li>
<li>Take HDMI/VGA cables/adapters to connect your laptop to the projector.</li>
<li>Many people do not use GitHub!</li>
</ul>
<h3>#4 …and then?</h3>
<p><strong>Work continues! Here are some ideas we’ll be working on in the coming months:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>More and more workshops on web development projects, hackerspaces and FLOSS events.</li>
<li>Start an A-Frame meetup in São Paulo to focus on new continuous sessions, hackathons and build a local community of contributors.</li>
<li>Start a local group on Facebook.</li>
<li>Create a video course on YouTube or Teachable for more people learning A-Frame in every corner of our country.</li>
<li>Create a teaching activity focused on <a href="https://learning.mozilla.org/clubs">Mozilla Clubs</a> or start an experiment and issue a badge through the <a href="https://www.openbadgeacademy.com/">OBA</a> for this WebVR activity.</li>
</ul>
<p><em>Do you want to help us develop some of these challenges? <a href="https://discourse.mozilla-community.org/c/mozilla-brasil">Start a topic in our forum</a>!</em></p>
<h3>#5 Thankfulness</h3>
<p><a href="https://aframe.io/examples/showcase/hello-metaverse/"><img class="aligncenter size-full" height="714" src="https://pageshot.net/images/ac727536-e91a-413e-bf4a-dfcb0f9d5f60.png" width="1642" /></a></p>
<p>Thanks to everyone who participated in our workshops, it was a privilege to teach A-Frame! More news is coming, <strong>I’ll see you soon</strong>! Thanks to all local projects and partners who have made room for activities, including facilitators of local projects! And a <strong>super, mega and big thank</strong> you to <a href="https://twitter.com/cynthiapereira_">Cynthia Pereira</a>, <a href="https://twitter.com/airtonzanon">Airton Zanon</a>, <a href="https://twitter.com/francjp">Francisco Picolini</a> and <a href="https://twitter.com/kelimuttu">Rizki Kelimutu</a> from Mozilla for the resources, time and support!!!</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://geraldobarros.me/my-first-webvr-camp-roadshow-with-local-projects-based-in-sao-paulo-and-campinas/" rel="nofollow">My first WebVR Camp roadshow with local projects based in São Paulo and Campinas</a> appeared first on <a href="https://geraldobarros.me" rel="nofollow">Geraldo Barros</a>.</p>]]>
  </description>
  <pubDate>Thu, 25 May 2017 00:52:24 +0000</pubDate>
  
</item>

<item>
  <title>Md Shahbaz Alam - Jaipur Uses Firefox Nightly</title>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alamshahbaz.wordpress.com/?p=779</guid>
  <link>https://alamshahbaz.wordpress.com/2017/05/16/jaipur-uses-firefox-nightly/</link>
  <description>
    <![CDATA[<p><span class="">It was an initiative to run a pilot campaign for <a href="https://reps.mozilla.org/e/jaipur-uses-firefox-nightly/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Firefox Nightly in Jaipur</a> as it is happening throughout India. Through this event we wanted be building strong technical community in Jaipur which will be using and testing Nightly on a regular basic which is a great way to get involved to a Mozilla project.<br />
</span></p>
<p>Event started with a brief introduction of Mozilla and What is <a href="https://wiki.mozilla.org/Nightly#What_is_Firefox_Nightly.3F" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Firefox Nightly</a>? And then we have shared the nightly file so that everyone has nightly browser to explore and use on a daily basis. As they were installing on their computer I talked about importance of nightly user and what great impact it gives back to community when we use this browser and file a bug if any in nightly browser.</p>

<a href="https://alamshahbaz.wordpress.com/2017/05/16/jaipur-uses-firefox-nightly/18486436_1699395803409501_859767328494890206_n/"><img alt="" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail" height="113" src="https://alamshahbaz.files.wordpress.com/2017/05/18486436_1699395803409501_859767328494890206_n.jpg?w=150&amp;h=113" width="150" /></a>
<a href="https://alamshahbaz.wordpress.com/2017/05/16/jaipur-uses-firefox-nightly/18424083_1699395463409535_979582241966293095_n/"><img alt="" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail" height="113" src="https://alamshahbaz.files.wordpress.com/2017/05/18424083_1699395463409535_979582241966293095_n.jpg?w=150&amp;h=113" width="150" /></a>
<a href="https://alamshahbaz.wordpress.com/2017/05/16/jaipur-uses-firefox-nightly/18519492_1699395663409515_5940272611773158119_n/"><img alt="" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail" height="84" src="https://alamshahbaz.files.wordpress.com/2017/05/18519492_1699395663409515_5940272611773158119_n.jpg?w=150&amp;h=84" width="150" /></a>

<p>After the installation we have discussed about two methods of filing bug. One for the browser specific , use <a href="http://bugzilla.mozilla.org/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">bugzilla</a> and for website which are not compatible in nightly, use <a href="http://webcompat.com/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">webcompat</a> . Also gave a demo of <span class="mw-headline" id="What_is_the_Nightly_Tester_Tools_extension.3F"><a href="https://addons.mozilla.org/firefox/addon/nightly-tester-tools/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Nightly Tester Tools extension</a> and how they an use it in the browser.<br />
</span></p>
<p>During the event we shared <a href="https://www.facebook.com/mdsbzalam/posts/1699396156742799?pnref=story" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">pictures</a> on social media and used profile changer and shared the details of campaign and nightly on twitter. Also one of the participant filed two bugs,<a href="https://bugzilla.mozilla.org/show_bug.cgi?id=1364735" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"> one on bugzilla</a> and <a href="https://webcompat.com/issues/6694" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">one on webcompat</a> . Everyone will be using this browser on a daily basis and we are looking forward for more bugs to be filed .</p>

<a href="https://alamshahbaz.wordpress.com/2017/05/16/jaipur-uses-firefox-nightly/18424069_1699395300076218_8572378443863762929_n/"><img alt="" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail" height="84" src="https://alamshahbaz.files.wordpress.com/2017/05/18424069_1699395300076218_8572378443863762929_n.jpg?w=150&amp;h=84" width="150" /></a>
<a href="https://alamshahbaz.wordpress.com/2017/05/16/jaipur-uses-firefox-nightly/18485310_1699396106742804_4277924514248193578_n/"><img alt="" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail" height="113" src="https://alamshahbaz.files.wordpress.com/2017/05/18485310_1699396106742804_4277924514248193578_n.jpg?w=150&amp;h=113" width="150" /></a><br />  <a href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/alamshahbaz.wordpress.com/779/" rel="nofollow"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/alamshahbaz.wordpress.com/779/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" height="1" src="https://pixel.wp.com/b.gif?host=alamshahbaz.wordpress.com&amp;blog=73514675&amp;post=779&amp;subd=alamshahbaz&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" />]]>
  </description>
  <pubDate>Tue, 16 May 2017 04:31:14 +0000</pubDate>
  
</item>

<item>
  <title>Nino Vranesic - Let’s focus on privacy and get rid of the clutter</title>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.elnino.si/post/160523882052</guid>
  <link>http://blog.elnino.si/post/160523882052</link>
  <description>
    <![CDATA[We live in Information Society in which the creation and distribution of 
information has become the...]]>
  </description>
  <pubDate>Wed, 10 May 2017 19:49:39 +0000</pubDate>
  
</item>

<item>
  <title>Geraldo Barros - [Mozilla at] CryptoRave 2017 — 24 hours for privacy and freedom in the network</title>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">https://geraldobarros.me/?p=681</guid>
  <link>https://geraldobarros.me/mozilla-cryptorave-2017-24-hours-privacy-freedom-network/</link>
  <description>
    <![CDATA[<p>The <a href="https://cryptorave.org/">CryptoRave</a> is the biggest open and free event of its kind in the world. The last edition attracted more than 3000 people (!!!): hackers, activists and cypherpunks from different parts of the world and people interested in learning more about safety practices and personal data protection. We were at <a href="https://twitter.com/cryptoravebr">CryptoRave 2017</a> yesterday representing Mozilla and talking about the <a href="https://internethealthreport.org/v01/">Internet health</a>.<span id="more-681"></span></p>
<h4>The Internet Health Report</h4>
<p>I and <a href="https://reps.mozilla.org/u/cynthiapereira/">Cynthia Pereira</a> talked about <a href="https://internethealthreport.org/v01/">Internet Health Report</a> and especially on the topic of <a href="https://internethealthreport.org/v01/privacy-and-security/">privacy and security</a>, the focus of the talk was to present Internet Health Report, a Mozilla’s new open source initiative to document and explain what’s happening to the health of the Internet combining research from multiple sources, and of course get feedback, inform people about the status of privacy and security health and discuss the <strong>Internet health in Brazil</strong>.</p>
<p>We started talking about <a href="https://www.mozilla.org/pt-BR/">Mozilla</a>, a healthy ecosystem, healthy Internet, the attacks that are decreasing the health of the Internet in Brazil and then we introduced the Internet Health Report and then we start by talking about all the key topics in the report, <strong>including healthy and unhealthy points for each topic</strong>.</p>
<p>After the presentation we started a discussion with the participants about what they think about healthy and unhealthy points of the report, what they think most expressive and any other comment for discussion. Based on open discussion, some comments were important and the keys to a discussion:</p>
<ul>
<li>The<strong> web literacy</strong> it is one of the most important topics, the Internet is in the hands of many, but people are not know to understand, explore, build and participate, web literacy should include etiquette on the Internet, few tools let you express what people are feeling and the tone of conversation in the social networks.</li>
<li>The <strong>policy of conduct</strong> in social networks does not respect all cultures.</li>
<li>Brazilian legislation is a <strong>gatekeeper</strong> for product innovation across all industry sectors.</li>
<li>The Internet is being <strong>monopolized</strong> by large Internet companies.</li>
</ul>
<p>Another plus point is that people wanted to get help in something to improve the Internet health, as in the case of two participants who wants to start a Mozilla Club now in their region, I’ll reach him to help on Mozilla Clubs leader training.</p>
<p>Finally, we encourage you to participate in giving feedback through the <a href="https://internethealthreport.org/v01/your-feedback/">Internet Health Report feedback session</a>. You can also see our slides deck bellow (thanks Solana for the slides!).</p>
<p>Overall, It was awesome to have the opportunity to talk about the Internet health and have a relevant and open conversation with all. <em>I wanted more 50 minutes to discuss in depth all the topics. <img alt="😂" class="wp-smiley" src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/2.3/72x72/1f602.png" style="height: 1em;" /></em></p>
<p></p>
<h4>Install Fest</h4>
<p>The Install Fest was the perfect space to connect with the people of the event! It was awesome!</p>
<p>We Mozillians (Me, <a href="https://twitter.com/cynthiapereira_">Cynthia</a> and <a href="https://twitter.com/airtonzanon">Airton</a>) get together at a single table, we distribute our famous Firefox swags and expect people to reach us, the result was awesome, many people came to us because they recognize Mozilla and its products as a open web advocate and a technology leader, we talk about web compatibility, emerging technologies, Rust, WebVR, Let’s Encrypt, Internet Health Report, Firefox, Mozilla Support and Pocket.</p>
<div class="wp-caption aligncenter" id="attachment_713" style="width: 2160px;"><img alt="Firefox swag, get yours before you go home, it's free!" class="wp-image-713 size-full" height="1958" src="https://geraldobarros.me/wp-content/uploads/2017/05/DSC_0027-e1494201239871.jpg" width="2150" /><p class="wp-caption-text">Firefox swag, get yours before you go home, it’s free!</p></div>
<div class="wp-caption aligncenter" id="attachment_710" style="width: 3850px;"><img alt="Mozilla at Install Fest (CryptoRave Sao Paulo)" class="size-full wp-image-710" height="2160" src="https://geraldobarros.me/wp-content/uploads/2017/05/DSC_0026.jpg" width="3840" /><p class="wp-caption-text">Mozilla at Install Fest (CryptoRave Sao Paulo)</p></div>
<p>The producer of the event came to meet us and receive feedback, I said that I loved the event because it is an <strong>open, accessible, relevant and contagious content</strong>, in Brazil it is very <strong>rare to have events focused on privacy and security</strong>. Another important point that we understand the quality of the event is that sponsorships are not accepted in exchange for favors, sales, slots for talks and anything else, this really has guaranteed the great quality of the event.</p>
<p>The event is open and free to allow all people to participate, and the content is divided by levels of knowledge, so everyone can participate, food is vegetarian and vegan so everyone can eat, transportation is easy and fast by tube/bus. This cryptoparty is sponsored by people who donate by <a href="https://www.catarse.me/cryptorave2017">crowdfunding</a>.</p>
<pre>Text credit: <a href="https://cryptorave.org/">CryptoRave 2017</a> 
Slide decks: <a href="https://twitter.com/solanasaurus">Solana Larsen</a> (Mozilla)
Image head:  <a href="https://twitter.com/_DouglasEsteves">Douglas Esteves</a>
</pre>
<p>The post <a href="https://geraldobarros.me/mozilla-cryptorave-2017-24-hours-privacy-freedom-network/" rel="nofollow">[Mozilla at] CryptoRave 2017 — 24 hours for privacy and freedom in the network</a> appeared first on <a href="https://geraldobarros.me" rel="nofollow">Geraldo Barros</a>.</p>]]>
  </description>
  <pubDate>Mon, 08 May 2017 03:31:51 +0000</pubDate>
  
</item>

<item>
  <title>Viswaprasath KS - Simple Tab Closing Addon using WebExtension API</title>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://iamVP7.in//Simple-Tab-Closing-Extension/</guid>
  <link>http://iamVP7.in//Simple-Tab-Closing-Extension/</link>
  <description>
    <![CDATA[<p>Before reading this post setup your Firefox so you can run WebExtensions in your browser.</p>]]>
  </description>
  <pubDate>Fri, 05 May 2017 23:34:00 +0000</pubDate>
  
</item>

<item>
  <title>Geraldo Barros - The Internet Health Report at CryptoRave 2017</title>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">https://geraldobarros.me/?p=670</guid>
  <link>https://geraldobarros.me/internet-health-report-cryptorave-2017/</link>
  <description>
    <![CDATA[<p>The Internet is an ecosystem. A living entity that billions of people depend on for knowledge, livelihood, self-expression, love…. The health of this system relies on – and influences – everyone it touches. Signs of poor health in any part impacts the whole. We’re all connected.<span id="more-670"></span></p>
<p>How healthy is our Internet? How might we understand and diagnose it? We believe this is a timely and necessary conversation.</p>
<p>Our individual actions shape the health of the Internet ecosystem. Only by recognizing where the system is healthy can we take positive steps to make it stronger. Only by understanding where it’s at risk can we avoid actions that weaken it.</p>
<p>I’ll be at CryptoRave 2017 tomorrow to talk about <a href="https://internethealthreport.org/v01/about/">Internet Health Report</a>, and especially about the health of Internet security and privacy. <strong>Let’s discuss! I hope you’ll join in!</strong></p>
<p><strong>Come to us in our talk</strong><br />
<em>5 topics on Internet Health in the World</em><br />
Day: 05/06/2017<br />
Start time: 09:00<br />
Duration: 00:50<br />
Room: Chelsea Manning<br />
Track: Politics<br />
Language: Portuguese<br />
More info: <a href="https://cpa.cryptorave.org/pt-BR/CR2017/public/events/46">talk link</a>.</p>
<p><strong>CryptoRave</strong><br />
<a href="https://cryptorave.org">CryptoRave</a> is the biggest open and free event of its kind in the world. The last edition attracted more than 3000 people (!!!): hackers, activists and cypherpunks from different parts of the world and people interested in learning more about safety practices and personal data protection.</p>
<pre><strong>Text credit</strong>: <a href="https://internethealthreport.org/v01/about/">Internet Health Report website</a>, <a href="https://cryptorave.org/">CryptoRave 2017</a> 
<strong>Image</strong>:  <a href="https://blog.mozilla.org/internetcitizen/2017/05/02/mozilla-internet-health-clinic-republica-17/">Step into the “Internet Health Clinic” @ re:publica 17</a></pre>
<p>The post <a href="https://geraldobarros.me/internet-health-report-cryptorave-2017/" rel="nofollow">The Internet Health Report at CryptoRave 2017</a> appeared first on <a href="https://geraldobarros.me" rel="nofollow">Geraldo Barros</a>.</p>]]>
  </description>
  <pubDate>Fri, 05 May 2017 14:45:23 +0000</pubDate>
  
</item>

</channel>
</rss>
