<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

<channel>
	<title>Mozilla Reps Planet</title>
	<link>http://planet.mozillareps.org</link>
	<language>en</language>
	<description>Mozilla Reps Planet - http://planet.mozillareps.org</description>
	<atom:link rel="self" href="http://planet.mozillareps.org/rss20.xml" type="application/rss+xml"/>


<item>
	<title>Official Reps Blog - Rep of the Month – August 2019</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.mozilla.org/mozillareps/?p=605</guid>
	<link>https://blog.mozilla.org/mozillareps/2019/09/30/rep-of-the-month-august-2019/</link>
	<description>Please join us in congratulating Yamama Shakaa, our Rep of the Month for August 2019! Yamama is from Nablus, Palestine. She is a teacher and has become a very active Mozillian, she joined the Reps program in November 2018 and ...</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2019 10:10:55 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

<item>
	<title>Bhuvana Meenakshi Koteeswaran - Speaker experience at DevFest’19</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://kbmtechie.wordpress.com/?p=342</guid>
	<link>https://kbmtechie.wordpress.com/2019/09/22/speaker-experience-at-devfest19/</link>
	<description>This was my first to DevFest as a speaker although I was an attendee for the same last year. This time Google Developers Group organised DevFest at Coimbatore and it was the first time the city was experiencing such a ...</description>
	<pubDate>Sun, 22 Sep 2019 16:11:00 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

<item>
	<title>Official Reps Blog - Rep of the Month – July 2019</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.mozilla.org/mozillareps/?p=601</guid>
	<link>https://blog.mozilla.org/mozillareps/2019/09/11/rep-of-the-month-july-2019/</link>
	<description>Please join us in congratulating Bhuvana Meenakshi Koteeswaran, Rep of the Month for July 2019! Bhuvana is from Salem, India. She joined the Reps program at the end of 2017 and since then she has been involved with Virtual and ...</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2019 11:34:26 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

<item>
	<title>Md Shahbaz Alam - Common Voice Ranchi Sprint</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://alamshahbaz.wordpress.com/?p=1144</guid>
	<link>https://alamshahbaz.wordpress.com/2019/09/11/common-voice-ranchi-sprint/</link>
	<description>Common Voice is a project to help make voice recognition open to everyone. To create voice systems, developers need an extremely large amount of voice data. Most of the data used by large companies aren’t available to the majority of ...</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2019 08:27:45 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

<item>
	<title>Official Reps Blog - Reps OKRs for second half of 2019</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.mozilla.org/mozillareps/?p=599</guid>
	<link>https://blog.mozilla.org/mozillareps/2019/08/12/reps-okrs-for-second-half-of-2019/</link>
	<description>Here is the list of the OKRs (objective and Key Results) that the Reps Council has set for the second half of 2019 Objective 1: By the end of 2019, Reps are feeling informed and are more confident to contribute ...</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2019 16:29:54 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

<item>
	<title>Md Shahbaz Alam - Beta Testing BugHunting</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://alamshahbaz.wordpress.com/?p=1123</guid>
	<link>https://alamshahbaz.wordpress.com/2019/07/16/beta-testing-bughunting/</link>
	<description>Hello Everyone, It’s been almost 9 months since I wrote a blog. There are pending blogs coming soon from Oct 2018, which includes my journey experience and speaking experience from southeast Asia. After a series of WebExtension events in Ranchi, ...</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2019 09:15:53 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

<item>
	<title>Official Reps Blog - Rep of the Month – June 2019</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.mozilla.org/mozillareps/?p=596</guid>
	<link>https://blog.mozilla.org/mozillareps/2019/07/05/rep-of-the-month-june-2019/</link>
	<description>Please join us in congratulating Pranshu Khanna, Rep of the Month for June 2019! Pranshu is from Surat, Gujarat, India. His journey started with a Connected Devices workshop in 2016, since then he’s been a super active contributor and a ...</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2019 11:37:15 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

<item>
	<title>Official Reps Blog - 8 Years of Reps Program, Celebrating Community Successes!</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.mozilla.org/mozillareps/?p=595</guid>
	<link>https://blog.mozilla.org/mozillareps/2019/07/03/8-years-of-reps-program-celebrating-community-successes/</link>
	<description>The Reps program idea was started in 2010 by William Quiviger and Pierros Papadeas, until officially launched and welcoming volunteers onboard as Mozilla Reps in 2011. The Mozilla Reps program aims to empower and support volunteer Mozillians who want to ...</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2019 12:23:21 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

<item>
	<title>Robert Reyes - DevCon Summit 2019</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.bobreyes.com/myblog/?p=5675</guid>
	<link>https://www.bobreyes.com/myblog/devcon-summit-2019/</link>
	<description>“The Future of Jobs, Embracing Industry 4.0” was this year’s DevCon (Developers Connect) Summit 2019 was all about. Held at the SMX Convention Center of SM Aura in Bonifacio Global City, Taguig City earlier today, I was invited to represent ...</description>
	<pubDate>Sat, 22 Jun 2019 14:11:26 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

<item>
	<title>Official Reps Blog - New Council members – 2019 Spring elections</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.mozilla.org/mozillareps/?p=590</guid>
	<link>https://blog.mozilla.org/mozillareps/2019/06/04/new-council-members-2019-spring-elections/</link>
	<description>We are very happy to announce that our 5 new Council members are are fully on-boarded and already working moving the Mozilla Reps program forward. In more detail here are the subjects that they will work on: Mayur Patil: Campaigns ...</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2019 16:02:00 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

<item>
	<title>Official Reps Blog - Rep of the Month – April 2019</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.mozilla.org/mozillareps/?p=587</guid>
	<link>https://blog.mozilla.org/mozillareps/2019/05/13/rep-of-the-month-april-2019/</link>
	<description>Please join us in congratulating Lidya Christina, Rep of the Month for April 2019! Lidya Christina is from Jakarta, Indonesia. Her contribution in SUMO event in 2016 lead her into a proud Mozillian, an active contributor of Mozilla Indonesia and ...</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2019 17:07:21 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

<item>
	<title>Viswaprasath KS - WebXR talk at VIT DevSpace</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://vp7techie.wordpress.com/?p=901</guid>
	<link>https://vp7techie.wordpress.com/2019/05/12/webxr-talk-at-vit-devspace/</link>
	<description>VIT, Vellore is one of the most reputed college in Tamilnadu. At the end of this March they organized DevSpace, Computer science department and Computer Society Students branch of college teamed up and organized this event. It is one of ...</description>
	<pubDate>Sun, 12 May 2019 17:52:40 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

<item>
	<title>Bhuvana Meenakshi Koteeswaran - Discovery of another passion!</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://kbmtechie.wordpress.com/?p=331</guid>
	<link>https://kbmtechie.wordpress.com/2019/04/07/discovery-of-another-passion/</link>
	<description>During this year’s traditional festival of Tamil Nadu, I not only celebrated it in a holy way but also I learnt, shared and discovered. Yes, this was the exact time that the Firefox Fights For You video challenge was open ...</description>
	<pubDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2019 18:37:47 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

<item>
	<title>Viswaprasath KS - Add-ons session at LPU</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://vp7techie.wordpress.com/?p=889</guid>
	<link>https://vp7techie.wordpress.com/2019/03/31/lpu2019/</link>
	<description>LPU generally called as Lovely Professional University is well known university in India. Recently the students club organized one of the amazing event #DiveIntoOpenSource It was not a very easy travel to LPU. I to some extent I love travel ...</description>
	<pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2019 15:50:07 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

<item>
	<title>Official Reps Blog - Rep of the Month – February 2019</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.mozilla.org/mozillareps/?p=581</guid>
	<link>https://blog.mozilla.org/mozillareps/2019/03/14/rep-of-the-month-february-2019/</link>
	<description>Please join us in congratulating Edoardo Viola, our Rep of the Month for February 2019! Edoardo is a long-time Mozillian from Italy and has been a Rep for almost two years. He’s a Resource Rep and has been on the ...</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2019 12:32:46 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

<item>
	<title>Official Reps Blog - Rep of the Month – November 2018</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.mozilla.org/mozillareps/?p=578</guid>
	<link>https://blog.mozilla.org/mozillareps/2019/03/06/rep-of-the-month-november-2018/</link>
	<description>Please join us in congratulating Viswaprasath KS, our Rep of the Month for November 2018! Viswaprasath KS, also know as iamvp7, is a long time Mozillian from India who joined the Mozilla Rep program in June 2013. By profession he ...</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2019 11:06:34 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

<item>
	<title>Shivam Singhal - 2018 Year in Review with AMO</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://championshuttler.wordpress.com/?p=417</guid>
	<link>https://championshuttler.wordpress.com/2019/02/14/2018-year-in-review-with-amo/</link>
	<description>Sibelius Monument, Finland Each one of us have some goals to complete, things to learn, and places to visit. With the year getting ended, it is time to lock back and see what all did we do for the last ...</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 13 Feb 2019 17:27:14 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

<item>
	<title>Official Reps Blog - Reps OKRs – First half of the year 2019</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.mozilla.org/mozillareps/?p=576</guid>
	<link>https://blog.mozilla.org/mozillareps/2019/01/29/reps-okrs-first-half-of-the-year-2019/</link>
	<description>Here are the OKRs for the first half of the year: Objective 1: Reps are the bridge between their local communities (Mozilla or other local open source communities) and the Mozilla contribution opportunities Key Result 1.1: 60% of Reps have ...</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2019 18:24:44 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

<item>
	<title>Bhuvana Meenakshi Koteeswaran - 2018 – Red letter days, Mozilla and Me :)</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://kbmtechie.wordpress.com/?p=327</guid>
	<link>https://kbmtechie.wordpress.com/2018/12/31/2018-red-letter-days-mozilla-and-me/</link>
	<description>Date: 31.12.2018 With the New Year fast approaching I just recollected the sweet memories that the past year 2018 has given me. Of course a lot of ups and downs, without which life can’t be interesting. Firstly I express my ...</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2018 18:30:12 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

<item>
	<title>Robert Reyes - ASEAN Mozillian Localizers Meet at Hanoi, Vietnam</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.bobreyes.com/myblog/?p=5591</guid>
	<link>https://www.bobreyes.com/myblog/asean-mozillian-localizers-meet-at-hanoi-vietnam/</link>
	<description>All roads (flights, actually) lead to Hanoi, Vietnam as the Mozilla Localization Team hosted a Meetup/Workshop for Mozillian Localizers from Southeast Asia on the weekend of 17 to 18 November. The delegation from Mozilla Philippines (MozillaPH) is composed of Kemuel ...</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 19 Nov 2018 15:21:49 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

<item>
	<title>Bhuvana Meenakshi Koteeswaran - An escape to The Square Mile #Mozfest2018</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://kbmtechie.wordpress.com/?p=297</guid>
	<link>https://kbmtechie.wordpress.com/2018/11/03/an-escape-to-the-square-mile-mozfest2018/</link>
	<description>Dates of the event: 26,27 and 28, Oct 2018. Venue: Ravensbourne University, London My first trip overseas came true just because of Mozilla and Mozfest2018. In first place my sincere thanks to Mozilla Foundations and Sarah Allen for helping me ...</description>
	<pubDate>Sat, 03 Nov 2018 08:31:45 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

<item>
	<title>Md Shahbaz Alam - VR and AR on the Web @ Cognizance 2018</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://alamshahbaz.wordpress.com/?p=1102</guid>
	<link>https://alamshahbaz.wordpress.com/2018/10/04/vr-and-ar-on-the-web-cognizance-2018/</link>
	<description>Mozilla India’s first collaboration with Cognizance 2k18. Spreading the Mozilla mission in Changa. Also spreading awareness for online privacy, MozActivate campaign. Amongst students from all over Gujarat, in the technical fest hosted by CHARUSAT, Changa. This will be the 1st ...</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 04 Oct 2018 17:14:23 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

<item>
	<title>Mehul Patel - DevConfIN 2018</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.rowdymehul.com/?p=1634</guid>
	<link>http://www.rowdymehul.com/events/devconfin-2018/</link>
	<description>DevConf.in 2018 is the second annual Developers’ Conference to be organized by Red Hat in Bengaluru, India. It is meant to provide a platform to the local FOSS community participants to come together and engage in the knowledge sharing through ...</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 14 Sep 2018 22:27:02 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

<item>
	<title>Bhuvana Meenakshi Koteeswaran - A day admist techie geeks #Devconf2018</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://kbmtechie.wordpress.com/?p=173</guid>
	<link>https://kbmtechie.wordpress.com/2018/09/09/a-day-admist-techie-geeks-devconf2018/</link>
	<description>Dates of the event: 04 &amp;amp; 05, August, 2018 Venue : Christ University, Bangalore, India. This is the first conference as a speaker I attended and it turned out to be a great event with huge bunch of people interested ...</description>
	<pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 08:19:07 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

<item>
	<title>Viswaprasath KS - Devconf India 2018</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://vp7techie.wordpress.com/?p=872</guid>
	<link>https://vp7techie.wordpress.com/2018/08/11/devconf-india-2018/</link>
	<description>DevConf Contributor Conferences are technology conference events for Linux and JBoss Developers, Admins, Linux and other open source project contributors, organized by Red Hat. This is the 2nd time happening at India, it was one of the amazing open source ...</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 10 Aug 2018 20:08:04 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

<item>
	<title>Viswaprasath KS - Mozofest 2018</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://vp7techie.wordpress.com/?p=863</guid>
	<link>https://vp7techie.wordpress.com/2018/07/08/mozofest-2018/</link>
	<description>Mozofest is an event organized by SRMKzilla club each and every year. This year they had big plans for this event. Usually they used limited number of events this year they had Speaker series, Hackathon and other events which educate ...</description>
	<pubDate>Sun, 08 Jul 2018 12:30:28 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

<item>
	<title>Md Shahbaz Alam - LinuxCon China</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://alamshahbaz.wordpress.com/?p=1081</guid>
	<link>https://alamshahbaz.wordpress.com/2018/07/05/linuxcon-china/</link>
	<description>LinuxCon China was a technical conference for developers, operations experts (architects, sys admins, devops), business, compliance and legal leadership and other professionals to come together in an informal setting to learn from open source experts, have fascinating discussions, collaborate with ...</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 05 Jul 2018 04:43:27 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

<item>
	<title>Bhuvana Meenakshi Koteeswaran - Taking WebXR to the most energetic gen</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://kbmtechie.wordpress.com/?p=159</guid>
	<link>https://kbmtechie.wordpress.com/2018/05/29/taking-webxr-to-the-most-energetic-gen/</link>
	<description>Venue: Academic heights public school, Hyderabad Date: 20.05.2018 I in the first place wondered whether a topic like WebXR going to complicate the audience I targeted for the day. My audience included 50+ kids, their parents and their guardians of ...</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 29 May 2018 10:20:01 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

<item>
	<title>Bhuvana Meenakshi Koteeswaran - Organise things right!</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://kbmtechie.wordpress.com/?p=145</guid>
	<link>https://kbmtechie.wordpress.com/2018/05/15/organise-things-right/</link>
	<description>The Global Sprint which was going throughout the world on various projects made Fahima and me to think about the event in our home town too. So I took the initiative to organise all things required for this event. I ...</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 15 May 2018 05:31:24 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

<item>
	<title>Viswaprasath KS - COEP FOSS Meetup 2018</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://vp7techie.wordpress.com/2018/04/27/coep-foss-meetup-2018/</guid>
	<link>https://vp7techie.wordpress.com/2018/04/27/coep-foss-meetup-2018/</link>
	<description>This is my second visit to Pune, after my recent GNUify event. GNUNify was mainly focused for Student developers, the target audience were getting started with Open source community. COeP Foss Meetup had well experienced developers and students who are ...</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 27 Apr 2018 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

<item>
	<title>Md Shahbaz Alam - WebVR @ LPU</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://alamshahbaz.wordpress.com/?p=1056</guid>
	<link>https://alamshahbaz.wordpress.com/2018/04/27/webvr-lpu/</link>
	<description>Lovely Professional University is a private university situated in Jalandhar, Punjab, India. It is a well know educational institutions in the country with around 34000 students and over 130 programs. Mrinal and I were invited to LPU for a workshop ...</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 27 Apr 2018 05:59:03 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

<item>
	<title>Michael Kohler - 10 Years as a Mozilla Volunteer</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">https://michaelkohler.info/2018/04/09/mozilla-10-years-mozillian/</guid>
	<link>https://michaelkohler.info/2018/04/09/mozilla-10-years-mozillian/</link>
	<description>March 10th, 2018 marked my 10 year anniversary as a Mozilla volunteer. I wanted to write this blog post for quite some time now, but as y</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 09 Apr 2018 19:29:11 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

<item>
	<title>Md Shahbaz Alam - Virtual Reality @ Indian Institute of Technology (BHU)</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://alamshahbaz.wordpress.com/?p=1023</guid>
	<link>https://alamshahbaz.wordpress.com/2018/04/09/virtual-reality-indian-institute-of-technology-bhu/</link>
	<description>Again trio has come together for a wonderful event. This time it was IIT-BHU. The event started with the introduction of the speakers, Shahbaz, Umesh and Prathamesh ( trio aka SUP ). Prathamesh started the session explaining the difference between ...</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 09 Apr 2018 18:25:31 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

<item>
	<title>Bhuvana Meenakshi Koteeswaran - A day as a speaker @ SRMkzilla</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://kbmtechie.wordpress.com/?p=132</guid>
	<link>https://kbmtechie.wordpress.com/2018/04/01/a-day-as-a-speaker-srmkzilla/</link>
	<description>Date: 24th March,2018 Venue: SRM University, Chennai The day started with the inauguration by the chief guest, Mr. Raaman. It was an interesting talk on Linux forum and how open source plays the real trend in today’s world. I was ...</description>
	<pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2018 13:04:04 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

<item>
	<title>Md Shahbaz Alam - Virtual Reality @ Hackfest, IIT (ISM) Dhanbad</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://alamshahbaz.wordpress.com/?p=1010</guid>
	<link>https://alamshahbaz.wordpress.com/2018/03/28/virtual-reality-hackfest-iit-ism-dhanbad/</link>
	<description>HackFest is IIT(ISM) Dhanbad’s 36-hour annual hackathon organized by the Computer Science and Engineering Society (CSES) and ACM Student Chapter, IIT(ISM) Dhanbad. The event started with an introduction of speakers. Prathamesh, Umesh, and Shahbaz ( yep it’s me ), since ...</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 28 Mar 2018 15:15:53 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

<item>
	<title>Md Shahbaz Alam - Footprints 2018</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://alamshahbaz.wordpress.com/?p=998</guid>
	<link>https://alamshahbaz.wordpress.com/2018/03/26/footprints-2018/</link>
	<description>WebMR is a new technology which is in its initial stages. WebMR was the thing which has brought a huge participation at Baroda. Everyone was eagerly waiting for us. Event started with a brief introduction of the speakers. Prathamesh Chavan ...</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 26 Mar 2018 17:23:45 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

<item>
	<title>Bhuvana Meenakshi Koteeswaran - My first talk on WebXR</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://kbmtechie.wordpress.com/?p=128</guid>
	<link>https://kbmtechie.wordpress.com/2018/03/18/my-first-talk-on-webxr/</link>
	<description>Date: 17.03.2018 Venue : PES University, Bangalore, India. This was my first presentation on WebXR as my previous talks were mostly focused on WebVR and projects related to it. There were around 150+ enthusiastic participants who actively participated in this ...</description>
	<pubDate>Sun, 18 Mar 2018 17:12:22 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

<item>
	<title>Sanyam Khurana - International Women's Day with WoMoz in Delhi</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">tag:www.sanyamkhurana.com,2018-03-15:blog/womoz-international-womens-day-delhi.html</guid>
	<link>https://www.sanyamkhurana.com/blog/womoz-international-womens-day-delhi.html</link>
	<description>We all know that every year, 8th March is celebrated as International Women&#39;s Day. It is a focal point in the movement for women&#39;s rights. On this occasion, all the Open Source communities in and around Delhi came forward to ...</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 14 Mar 2018 21:21:00 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

<item>
	<title>Tanzeel Khan - Discussion: Aadhaar and Right to Privacy in India @ Delhi NCR</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://khantanzeel.wordpress.com/?p=592</guid>
	<link>https://khantanzeel.wordpress.com/2018/03/09/discussion-aadhaar-and-right-to-privacy-in-india-delhi-ncr/</link>
	<description>To assess the status of Aadhaar Campaign in India and plan future initiatives to safeguard the right to privacy in India, a Talk Session was held at SpringHouse Gurugram on March 9 2018. Senior Global Policy Manager of Mozilla Jochai ...</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 09 Mar 2018 05:23:30 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

<item>
	<title>Robert Reyes - Three (03) Mozilla Talks in a Week!</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.bobreyes.com/myblog/?p=5481</guid>
	<link>https://www.bobreyes.com/myblog/three-03-mozilla-talks-in-a-week/</link>
	<description>I was able to squeeze delivery of three (03) Mozilla talks during the week of 05 to 11 February 2018. To chronicle what has transpired during these three (03) events, I have this blog post… Prof. Belay Montes’ Class at ...</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 07 Mar 2018 07:08:04 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

<item>
	<title>Viswaprasath KS - Prayatna 2018</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://vp7techie.wordpress.com/2018/03/05/prayatna-2018/</guid>
	<link>https://vp7techie.wordpress.com/2018/03/05/prayatna-2018/</link>
	<description>Prayatna is one of the prime Technical fest organised by MIT, Anna University Chennai. It is an yearly where the number of students participating will be very high. This year our community organized One day workshop of WebExtension. This time ...</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 05 Mar 2018 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

<item>
	<title>Viswaprasath KS - KGiSL Mozactivate 2018</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://vp7techie.wordpress.com/2018/03/02/kgisl-mozactivate-2018/</guid>
	<link>https://vp7techie.wordpress.com/2018/03/02/kgisl-mozactivate-2018/</link>
	<description>KGiSL community space is very close to every Mozillian around Tamilnadu, we had our first meetup there. There are lot of events related to Mozilla and open source communities happen at this space. After so long time I got opportunity ...</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 02 Mar 2018 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

<item>
	<title>Sanyam Khurana - MozAMU: Mozilla Addons Development at AMU</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">tag:www.sanyamkhurana.com,2018-03-01:blog/mozilla-addons-dev-amu.html</guid>
	<link>https://www.sanyamkhurana.com/blog/mozilla-addons-dev-amu.html</link>
	<description>It all started with PyCon India. I met a few students of Aligarh Muslim University who were trying to teach about FOSS in their college. A few them were already contributing to Coala. We talked a bit and they were ...</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 11:41:00 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

<item>
	<title>Viswaprasath KS - GNUnify 2018</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://vp7techie.wordpress.com/2018/02/19/gnunify-2018/</guid>
	<link>https://vp7techie.wordpress.com/2018/02/19/gnunify-2018/</link>
	<description>GNUnify is one of the amazing event where each and every year Mozilla India community make sure to participate. GNUnify is an annual gathering consisting of Free and Open Source software workshops, talks, seminars and BOFs (Birds of a feather), ...</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2018 07:39:00 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

<item>
	<title>Sanyam Khurana - Web Extensions, Womoz &amp; Privacy</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">tag:www.sanyamkhurana.com,2018-01-23:blog/web-extensions-womoz-privacy.html</guid>
	<link>https://www.sanyamkhurana.com/blog/web-extensions-womoz-privacy.html</link>
	<description>A Saturday well spent teaching students about Open Source, Add-ons and Privacy. We had an activity at Indira Gandhi Delhi Technical University for Women (IGDTUW) for Addons, WoMoz and Privacy. The session started with Trishul giving a talk on getting ...</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 23 Jan 2018 14:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

<item>
	<title>Sanyam Khurana - Moz-Fedora Day</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">tag:www.sanyamkhurana.com,2018-01-14:blog/moz-fedora-day.html</guid>
	<link>https://www.sanyamkhurana.com/blog/moz-fedora-day.html</link>
	<description>We recently organized Moz-Fedora Day, a one day event on promoting FOSS through Mozilla &amp;amp; Fedora at Investopad, Hauz Khas, Delhi on Jan 13, 2018. The aim was to depict the usage of packaging &amp;amp; building one of the Mozilla&#39;s ...</description>
	<pubDate>Sun, 14 Jan 2018 14:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

<item>
	<title>Sanyam Khurana - Ending the year with MozCoffee</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">tag:www.sanyamkhurana.com,2017-12-24:blog/mozcoffee-2017-end.html</guid>
	<link>https://www.sanyamkhurana.com/blog/mozcoffee-2017-end.html</link>
	<description>We had MozCoffee Delhi on last Saturday, Dec 23, 2017. We had a lot of Rep Attendees this time with other Mozillians. What would have been a better way to end an year than the MozCoffee. From past various months, ...</description>
	<pubDate>Sun, 24 Dec 2017 15:04:00 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

<item>
	<title>Viswaprasath KS - Year in review 2017</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://vp7techie.wordpress.com/2017/12/10/year-in-review-2017/</guid>
	<link>https://vp7techie.wordpress.com/2017/12/10/year-in-review-2017/</link>
	<description>2017 is one of the amazing year I had. I have dedicated it fully to learn and share my knowledge about WebExtension and develop some WebExtension during my free time. January This is one of the best month and very ...</description>
	<pubDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2017 01:34:00 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

<item>
	<title>Xavier Martorell - My Experience - Mozfest17</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">https://yunit0.tumblr.com/post/167299502492</guid>
	<link>https://yunit0.tumblr.com/post/167299502492</link>
	<description>Right now, I’m on my flight back from London where I had the pleasure to assist to the Mozilla Festival 2017. I’ll try to use this 2 hours of my flight time to relate to you how my experience was ...</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 09 Nov 2017 09:52:28 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

<item>
	<title>Xavier Martorell - My Story with Mozilla</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">https://yunit0.tumblr.com/post/166545352987</guid>
	<link>https://yunit0.tumblr.com/post/166545352987</link>
	<description>I was in high school, sitting in the Computers room, taking part of a boring and monotonous class about Office IT. Because of that, I decided to open Firefox and start surfing the web for some entertainment to make the ...</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2017 20:11:36 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

<item>
	<title>Viswaprasath KS - Weeks of Contribution- WebExtension Session7</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://vp7techie.wordpress.com/2017/10/02/weeks-of-contribution-webextension-session7/</guid>
	<link>https://vp7techie.wordpress.com/2017/10/02/weeks-of-contribution-webextension-session7/</link>
	<description>Date : 29th August 2017 Time: 8:30 – 9:30 IRC channel: #MozillaTN This is our first series of the WebExtension webseries. The main agenda of the program is to get started with Mozilla community and discuss the syllabus we will ...</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 02 Oct 2017 00:54:00 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

<item>
	<title>Ajay Kumar Jogawath - Mozilla Campus Club Inauguration @ BITS,Warangal</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://ajaykumarjogawath.wordpress.com/?p=499</guid>
	<link>https://ajaykumarjogawath.wordpress.com/2017/09/11/mozilla-campus-club-inauguration-bitswarangal/</link>
	<description>Hello everyone, It has been a long time, I have been writing here. This blog post will be about sharing my personal experience during the Mozilla Campus Club Inauguration at Balaji Institute of Technology and Science, Warangal, Telangana, India. I ...</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2017 06:07:02 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

<item>
	<title>Ram Dayal Vaishnav - Highlights from Netherlands HackerCamp – SHA2017!</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://gurumukhi.wordpress.com/?p=882</guid>
	<link>https://gurumukhi.wordpress.com/2017/09/05/highlights-from-netherlands-hackercamp-sha/</link>
	<description>SHA, aka Still Hacking Anyways, is part of international non profit outdoor hacker camp series organized once in 4 years in The Netherlands. This year it was organized in Zeewolde on August 4th to 8th and I was honored to ...</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 04 Sep 2017 20:32:51 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

<item>
	<title>Abhiram Ravikumar - It’s raining Rust at Red Hat</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://abhiramrk.com/?p=322</guid>
	<link>http://abhiramrk.com/its-raining-rust-at-red-hat/</link>
	<description>I know it’s been a while since I’ve put out a post and mostly because I’m trying to learn amazing things and get my hands dirty, trying to build solutions that actually make sense. One such pet-project has been Rust, ...</description>
	<pubDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2017 14:21:43 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

<item>
	<title>Robert Reyes - First Time at COSCUP Taiwan</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.bobreyes.com/myblog/?p=5421</guid>
	<link>https://www.bobreyes.com/myblog/first-time-coscup-taiwan/</link>
	<description>I had the opportunity to represent Mozilla (and my country) in COSCUP 2017 over the weekend. COSCUP is an annual conference held by Taiwanese Open source community participants since 2006. It’s a major force of Free software movement advocacy in ...</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 07 Aug 2017 02:35:27 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

<item>
	<title>Michael Kohler - WebVR/A-Frame Hackathon in Lausanne</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">https://michaelkohler.info/2017/07/24/webvr-aframe-hackathon-in-lausanne/</guid>
	<link>https://michaelkohler.info/2017/07/24/webvr-aframe-hackathon-in-lausanne/</link>
	<description>Last Saturday the Mozilla Switzerland community, together with</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 24 Jul 2017 22:49:55 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

<item>
	<title>Sanyam Khurana - Why you should contribute to Open Source</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">tag:www.sanyamkhurana.com,2017-06-26:blog/why-contribute-to-foss.html</guid>
	<link>https://www.sanyamkhurana.com/blog/why-contribute-to-foss.html</link>
	<description>My first step with FOSS was during the summer of 2014, where I got introduced to DGPLUG (Durgapur Linux Users Group). Every year, they conduct a training over IRC covering a wide range of topics. Since then, I&#39;ve been contributing ...</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 26 Jun 2017 11:41:00 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

<item>
	<title>Tanzeel Khan - Kashmir Uses Firefox Nightly</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://khantanzeel.wordpress.com/?p=350</guid>
	<link>https://khantanzeel.wordpress.com/2017/05/25/kashmir-uses-firefox-nightly/</link>
	<description>The event was a part of PAN India pilot campaign for Firefox Nightly aimed to create a strong technical community who will be using and testing Nightly on a regular basis. Besides, it was a meetup for community members in ...</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 25 May 2017 15:55:59 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

<item>
	<title>Biraj Karmakar - India uses Firefox Nightly: Kick off on May 1, 2017</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://birajkarmakar.wordpress.com/?p=1367</guid>
	<link>https://birajkarmakar.wordpress.com/2017/04/25/india-uses-firefox-nightly-kick-off-on-may-1-2017/</link>
	<description>In my last blog, I have announced that Mozilla India is going to organize a special campaign on Firefox Nightly Usage in India. RSVP here. Everything is set. Gearing up for the campaign. BTW Recently we have organized one community ...</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 25 Apr 2017 13:02:38 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

<item>
	<title>Robert Reyes - Pinoy Mozillians at the 2017 Asian L10n Workshop in Taipei</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.bobreyes.com/myblog/?p=5149</guid>
	<link>https://www.bobreyes.com/myblog/pinoy-mozillians-2017-asian-l10n-workshop-taipei/</link>
	<description>A delegation of four (04) Pinoy Mozillians participated in the weekend-long workshop for Mozilla Localization (L10n) at Mozilla Taiwan office. Heading the delegation was your’s truly, with fellow Mozilla Rep Frederick Villaluna, and Localizers Richmond Lacanlalay and Michelle Manlogon. Bye, ...</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 24 Apr 2017 14:55:59 +0000</pubDate>
	
</item>

</channel>
</rss>
